<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Turns out, it wasn’t the fault of either driver when two trucks plunged from I-285 to Ga. 400, causing a crash that stopped traffic at the busy interchange for five hours, police said Thursday. Instead, it was the driver of a 2014 Kia Sorento who allegedly sparked the wreck when he left his lane, driving into the path of a tractor-trailer, according to Sandy Springs police. Howard Silverstein, 64, was <head>charged</head> with failure to maintain lane in the Friday crash. “Silverstein entered into the path and lane on 285 eastbound already occupied by the Publix tractor-trailer,” Sandy Springs police said in an emailed statement. “The right front tire of the Kia Sorento struck the left front tire and rim of the tractor-trailer causing the Kia’s tire to go flat.”
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Sandy Springs police said Thursday that Howard Silverstein, 64, of Duluth, was driving a Kia Sorento on Sept. 28 and veered into the right lane, where he hit a Publix tractor-trailer. The Publix tractor-trailer veered to the right after being hit, and hit another tractor-trailer. Both tractor-trailers went over a concrete barrier onto Ga. 400. Silverstein was <head>charged</head> with failure to maintain a lane, Sandy Springs police said. The fuel tanker in the far right lane was carrying 8,000 gallons of gasoline, but Sandy Springs Fire Rescue said the fuel was contained inside the vehicle and there was no leak. Both truck drivers were briefly trapped in their trucks but were pulled out. They both suffered non-life threatening injuries.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Prosecutors added a new perjury count and other criminal charges Thursday against Pennsylvania's attorney general, saying they found a signed document that contradicts her claims she never agreed to maintain secrecy of a grand jury investigation in 2009, before she took office. The Montgomery County district attorney <head>charged</head> Kathleen Kane with felony perjury and two misdemeanors — false swearing and obstruction — based on a signed secrecy oath she signed shortly after taking office in early 2013. Kane, the first woman and first Democrat elected attorney general in Pennsylvania,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="4"/>
<context>
In declining to file charges against the reality television star and former Olympian, the DA's office stated in a charge evaluation sheet that prosecutors simply could not prove Jenner's conduct was unreasonable "beyond a reasonable doubt." The Los Angeles County Sheriff's Department had previously recommended that Jenner be <head>charged</head> with manslaughter. Jenner was driving and towing a buggy on the PCH in Malibu on Feb. 7 when her vehicle rear ended Kimberly Howe's white Lexus, forcing it to veer into oncoming traffic on the other side of the roadway, the DA's office said. The 69-year-old victim died when her car collided with a black Hummer. Jenner's vehicle was traveling slightly below the posted speed limit on the highway, and minimally slower than the victim's car, the DA's office said.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Virto allegedly drove for 200 hundred yards with Luna on the hood of his car. Police said the cyclist was traveling in a crosswalk with a green light when he was struck by the speeding car. Luna died of multiple traumatic injuries, according to the county coroner’s office. Virto faces up to six years in state prison if convicted as <head>charged</head>. He had initially been booked on suspicion of second-degree murder and felony driving under the influence with great bodily injury, police said Friday. Prosecutors planned to ask that bail be set at $130,000. The case has inflamed passions in the cycling community, which includes many members angry with City Councilman Gil Cedillo for shooting down city-planned bike lanes along North Figueroa Street in Highland Park.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Flores was arrested on June 30, according to the Los Angeles Times. He was later “relieved of duty” and placed on administrative leave, Sheriff’s Department spokeswoman Amber Smith told the Times. Flores had worked with the department for more than seven years in the court services and transit bureau, Smith added. The DA <head>charged</head> Flores with three felony counts of domestic battery with corporal injury and two felony counts of assault with force likely to produce great bodily injury. He also faced one felony count each of aggravated assault, dissuading a witness by force or threat, and false imprisonment by menace or violence with sentencing enhancement allegations for great bodily injury inflicted during domestic violence.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Defense attorney Gary Pohlson said Abraham's father picked him up after the crash. "What happened is my client saw the family. … The grandmother appeared to be dead, and he just panicked, and he went away and he called his parents," Pohlson said. Robert Hampton said Abraham's father should be "hung out to dry along with his son." Abraham was arrested at a park in Costa Mesa about 1 p.m. Thursday. Abraham was <head>charged</head> Monday with two felony counts of gross vehicular manslaughter with gross negligence, one felony count of hit-and-run with permanent injury or death, one felony count of reckless driving with bodily injury, and one misdemeanor count of petty theft by taking and carrying away, and sentencing enhancements for fleeing the scene of a vehicular manslaughter and inflicting great bodily injury.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="4"/>
<context>
A 26-year-old man appeared in court Thursday to face charges in the hit-and-run death of a teen skateboarder who was struck while crossing the street last month in Echo Park. Sang Won Jung has been <head>charged</head> with one count each of felony hit-and-run resulting in death or injury and misdemeanor vehicular manslaughter, the Los Angeles County District Attorney’s Office announced. He entered a not guilty plea during an appearance at the Foltz Criminal Justice Center in downtown L.A.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Tuesday with murder for allegedly stabbing her brother’s girlfriend to death with a pair of scissors during an argument in Rowland Heights over the weekend. Lisette Kimberly Moreno was <head>charged</head> with one count of murder and a special allegation that she personally used a deadly and dangerous weapon during the commission of the crime, the Los Angeles County District Attorney’s Office stated in a news release. Moreno allegedly got into an argument with 21-year-old Annette Martinez on Aug. 6 at an apartment in the 1900 block of Baston Avenue, the release stated.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Brandon Wynn, 33, aka “Smooth,” appeared in the Antelope Valley Branch of the Los Angeles County Superior Court. His arraignment was postponed till Aug. 4, and his bail was set at $3.46 million. Wynn, suspected of being a pimp to the unidentified adult victim, was <head>charged</head> with 13 felony counts, according to the District Attorney’s Office: two counts each of human trafficking to commit another crime, pimping and kidnapping; one count each of first-degree residential burglary, forcible oral copulation, assault to commit a felony during the commission of a first-degree burglary, assault by means likely to produce great bodily injury, assault with a deadly weapon — bleach, child abuse, and attempted murder.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="4"/>
<context>
A 19-year-old man who allegedly sexually assaulted a woman in her 70s at a senior living apartment complex in Huntington Beach over the weekend was scheduled to make his first court appearance on Tuesday, according to the Orange County District Attorney’s Office. Ahkail Demyers has been <head>charged</head> with one felony count each of forcible rape, sexual penetration by force, elder abuse and assault with the intent to commit a sexual offense during the commission of a first-degree burglary in connection with the Aug. 9 incident, a news release from the DA’s office stated. He also faced sentencing enhancement allegations of aggravated kidnapping and commission of forcible rape and sexual penetration by force during the commission of a burglary, officials said in the release.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="4"/>
<context>
as an adult Monday with special circumstance murder in the death of an 86-year-old Lancaster woman who was found stabbed to death in her bed, the Los Angeles County District Attorney’s Office announced Tuesday. Tony Donnell Brown was <head>charged</head> with one count of murder and two counts of first-degree burglary in the death of Annie Margaret Bell, according to a news release from the DA’s office. The charges filed against Brown included a special circumstance allegation that the murder was committed during a first-degree burglary and a special allegation that the defendant used a knife, the release stated.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Friday with several misdemeanor counts of child abuse stemming from a boot camp run by the Huntington Park and South Gate police departments, authorities said. Two officers from the South Gate force, Edgar Yovany Gomez and Carlos Manuel Gomez-Marquez, and one officer from Huntington Park, Marissa Larios, were <head>charged</head> with battery and cruelty to a child by inflicting injury, according to the complaint filed by the San Luis Obispo County district attorney’s office. Prosecutors allege the trio victimized 10 children between the ages of 12 and 16. The alleged abuse occurred during a boot camp program run by the Huntington Park and South Gate police departments from May 17 to May 24 at Camp San Luis Obispo, prosecutors said.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="4"/>
<context>
He was also accused of borrowing and then stealing a bystanders cellphone as he was running away. Defense attorney Gary Pohlson said Abraham’s father picked him up after the crash. Abraham was arrested at a park in Costa Mesa on June 11. Abraham has been <head>charged</head> with two counts of murder and was being held on $1 million bail, according to the news release. If convicted, Abraham faces a maximum sentence of 30 years to life in state prison. He was scheduled to appear in court for arraignment on July 8.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="3"/>
<context>
The man arrested after a chase and manhunt that required police to set up a high-profile perimeter in the busy Roowood area of Norwood on Wednesday afternoon is facing robbery charges a day after his arrest. Jeffery McDaniel, 26, of Amelia, has been was <head>charged</head> with two counts of robbery -- one from Sept. 24 and one from Wednesday -- after his arrest in the 2700 block of Arbor Avenue. Police say McDaniel led police on an hour-long pursuit after he attempted to take money out of a cash register at a Speedway gas station in the 2700 block of Williams Avenue.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="4"/>
<context>
The former basketball star claimed he fired the shot in self-defense after being "jumped" by the group, but evidence indicates his life was not in danger when he pulled the trigger, McSorley said. Beechum could face at least 25 years in prison if convicted. "He really placed everyone in harm there," the prosecutor said. Hutchinson, who is black, was also involved in the dispute but has not been criminally <head>charged</head>. Beechum returned to his home in Arizona after the shooting but is expected to return to Iowa and turn himself in this week, McSorley said. DeShawne Bird-Sell, a Glenwood attorney representing Beechum, said she had no comment Wednesday. McDaniel, the 21-year-old shooting victim, and another man from the group, Denver Cook, 18, are both facing assault and other charges for their roles in the altercation.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Fernstrom, a 6-foot-5 sophomore center, played in all 31 games for the Cyclones last season, averaging 9 points, 3.2 rebounds and 1.2 blocks. “We are aware of the situation,” Iowa State officials said in a statement, “and we will handle it according to team and university rules.” A spokesperson for the Ames Police Department confirmed Monday that Fernstrom, 20, had been <head>charged</head>.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="3"/>
<context>
We’re being told there may have been some type of verbal argument that escalated to the gunfire.” The man identified Thursday afternoon as Nwankwo appeared to have been shot multiple times and died at the scene, where police recovered a handgun, Hampton said. Harper was taken to police headquarters for questioning before police <head>charged</head> him in Nwankwo’s death. Police cordoned off the entrance to the building, which was closed to tenants for hours. The crime scene tape was taken down about 9:30 a.m. The building, formerly known as Tower Place 200 and now called 3348 Peachtree, is “back open for business,” said John Barton, a spokesman for building manager Parkway Properties.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Scott Shellenberger, Baltimore County's top prosecutor, said the case involved two officers seeking overtime pay for appearing in court, despite the officers not being present. Officers must get such overtime approved by prosecutors, and the charges allege Webb knowingly signed off on the extra pay. The second officer, identified in court records as Officer Vincent Fox, was not <head>charged</head> due to a lack of "sufficient evidence," Shellenberger said, though he is cited as one of Webb's co-conspirators in court records outlining her charges. Webb could not be reached for comment, and the Baltimore State's Attorney's Office declined to comment. The office had also declined to comment on Webb's departure when contacted in July, calling it a personnel matter.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Webb could not be reached for comment, and the Baltimore State's Attorney's Office declined to comment. The office had also declined to comment on Webb's departure when contacted in July, calling it a personnel matter. Baltimore Police said Stach was suspended without pay, which is department policy when someone is <head>charged</head> with a felony. Fox is facing internal disciplinary charges, police said. "I and other police officers have no tolerance for theft within our profession," Baltimore Police Department Interim Commissioner Kevin Davis said in a statement. Webb, 33, faces charges of theft scheme less than $1,000, three counts of theft less than $1,000, three counts of conspiracy to commit theft under $1,000, and three counts of misconduct in office.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="3"/>
<context>
A Missouri woman and her boyfriend are facing felony charges in the case of a 16-year-old boy who told police he was held down and raped as part of a foursome, according to the Carrollton Police Department. Authorities say 26-year-old Laura Ann Bentley is being <head>charged</head> with statutory rape and statutory sodomy. Her boyfriend, 34-year-old Jason Ashley Schlueter, faces a single count of statutory sodomy. The Carroll County Prosecutor's Office has yet to decide if charges will be filed against another woman allegedly involved in the incident, who is under the age of 21.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="4"/>
<context>
LGBT activist by strangling her, before gouging out his cell mate’s eyeballs in a violent attack in a Georgia jail. Donte Lamar Wyatt, 33, has been accused of waging the gruesome violence on two separate occasions in April and July this year. In two separate indictments, Wyatt was <head>charged</head> with 14 felonies, including two counts of malice murder, two counts of felony murder and four counts of aggravated assault. Wyatt’s attorney entered a not guilty plea on his behalf in DeKalb County courtroom, reported AJC.com. “The allegations really are gruesome in this case,” said DeKalb County District Attorney Robert James.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Two Pawling men, one of them a police officer, face charges of larceny after investigation of vehicle break-ins, the Dutchess County Sheriff's Office reports. The notice from the sheriff's office said the two were <head>charged</head> in connection with a series of vehicle break-ins in the Town of LaGrange area. They were identified as Anthony Ramos, 28, and William Tyson, 26, of Pawling. Ramos is also a police officer with the City of Danbury Police Department in Connecticut, according to the statement from Capt. John Watterson.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="3"/>
<context>
alongside her parents in a case involving sex, a threesome and a computer mogul allegedly extorted out of $3 million has died unexpectedly while awaiting trial in federal court. Romulus resident Jessica Tackett, 25, who prosecutors say was a prostitute and stripper, died Monday, six months after being <head>charged</head> in federal court. Tackett and her parents allegedly were involved in a scheme to extort almost $3 million from a retired software mogul by threatening to tell police about a threesome involving her, her teenage cousin and the businessman, prosecutors said. Tackett, the mother of a toddler son, had a long history of drug addiction but the cause and manner of death is unclear, as is the potential impact on a salacious criminal case in U.S. District Court.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="0"/>
<context>
According to the suit, patients in D.C. are entitled to a copy of their medical records within 30 days for a reasonable fee. Federal law allows a provider to charge for the cost of labor for copying and preparing a summary, the cost of the paper and electronic media and postage. No other fee may be <head>charged</head>. The couple, according to the lawsuit, requested an electronic copy of their child's birth record from MedStar Georgetown. The other patient requested an electronic health record for treatment he received.  The lawsuit alleges that the couple and the individual patient were
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="0"/>
<context>
a total of $1,167.88 and $1,559.26, respectively. HealthPort, MedStar Georgetown's third-party vendor, allegedly informed the couple that records were available only on paper. In both cases, HealthPort <head>charged</head> a copying fee of 76 cents per page, a basic fee of $22.88 and a shipping and handling fee of $16.38. HealthPort did not respond to an interview request. After challenging the legality of the per-page fee, MedStar Georgetown's legal counsel responded, saying the hospital had offered an alternative for getting EHRs, “which was not acceptable to (the patients)," according to the suit.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="4"/>
<context>
In the first case, witnesses told OHS agents they saw a woman slapping her cowering Jack Russell at a dog park on Aug. 5. According to the witnesses, the terrier was whimpering on the ground when it was repeatedly hit two different times that day, the society said. A woman has been <head>charged</head> with two counts of causing unnecessary suffering to a dog. In the second case, charges were laid after a man reportedly choked, kicked and punched a dog on July 17 and again on July 18. After a picture of the suspect was posted on Crime Stoppers and the OHS Facebook account, witnesses came forward to identify the man, the society said.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="3"/>
<context>
According to police, the suspect – who teaches at TL Kennedy Secondary School near Hurontario and Dundas streets – was arrested Tuesday, and appeared in a Brampton court Wednesday. Details surrounding what led police to arrest the suspect were not immediately provided in a release issued Thursday afternoon. Sixty-five-year-old Martin Danio is <head>charged</head> with possessing child pornography. “Investigators are concerned that there could be more victims and are appealing to witnesses to come forward with any information, regardless of how dated or insignificant it may seem,” police said.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Aaron Swartz, 30, of the 200 block of White Street was arrested about 8 a.m. at William Henry Harrison Park. Mr. Swartz attempted to meet a 15-year-old girl, said Capt. Scott Frank of the Wood County Sheriff's Office. An undercover deputy had conversed online with Mr. Swartz since June. The two arranged a meeting at the park, Captain Frank said. Mr. Swartz was <head>charged</head> with three fifth-degree felony counts of importuning and is held at the Wood County jail. He is scheduled for arraignment Thursday in Bowling Green Municipal Court.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="3"/>
<context>
An officer saw the stolen 2004 Audi at a home on the 85-8400 block of Mamalahoa Highway in Captain Cook on Monday. Police recovered the car and arrested Kolton Bannister, 21, police said. On Wednesday, he was <head>charged</head> with unauthorized control of a propelled vehicle, burglary, unauthorized possession of personal confidential information and two counts of theft. His bail was set at $6,750. He remains at the cellblock until his initial court appearance scheduled for Thursday.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="5"/>
<context>
The investigation, dubbed Operation Kids Count, began a year-and-a-half ago when the Minnesota Department of Human Services' Office of Inspector General noticed unusually high billings from Minnesota Child Care Services, 2500 Minnehaha Ave., Minneapolis, to the Child Care Assistance Program. "Each of the child care facilities <head>charged</head> have been involved in a common theme of billing the government for child care services and then not providing them. These centers do provide legitimate support and services, but they also bill the government anywhere from 15-30 percent for kids who weren't there," said Hennepin County Attorney Mike Freeman. "If there were 200 kids in the center, they would bill the government for 300."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Baltimore County Police say the 14-year-old girl told the officer the boy grabbed her by her shirt near her stomach, pulled her toward him and kissed her against her will. Police say the boy said someone dared him to do it. The boy was <head>charged</head> as a juvenile with second-degree assault and released to his mother. Police say he was not taken to the precinct and processed. County schools spokesman Mychael Dickerson says the boy faces school disciplinary action for violating the code of conduct.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Police from three agencies swarmed a house on West 10th Street in Hazleton for most of the day; neighbors say they had been there since the night before. After executing a search warrant, state police took the man who lives here, Eleazar Yisrael, into custody. He has now been <head>charged</head> with possession of a controlled substance for having marijuana and possession of a weapon for having a large knife with a metal knuckles handle, according to charging documents. Hazleton police and state police came to Yisrael's house after Butler Township police discovered a car belonging to a missing man in Hazleton on Tuesday.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Deputies found the woman locked in the shed on Sept. 22 after getting reports of someone screaming. When they opened the shed, deputies described the woman as frail, malnourished and covered with wounds, prosecutors said. The woman's brother, 61-year-old Elias Abdurahman, and his girlfriend, 50-year-old Sara Kebede Tadesse, were arrested and <head>charged</head> with false imprisonment by violence, torture, assault with a deadly weapon, and abuse of a dependent adult causing great bodily injury. The deadly weapon that investigators allege was used is a cane. Abdurahman had not yet been assigned an attorney, and it was unclear whether Tadesse's case had been assigned.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Court documents say the torture charge stemmed from the intention "to cause cruel and extreme pain and suffering for the purpose of revenge, extortion, persuasion and for a sadistic purpose." The false imprisonment charge was "effected by violence, menace, fraud and deceit." The torture and abuse charges covered a yearlong time period, while the false imprisonment <head>charged</head> stemmed from a single day, the day the woman was found locked in the shed. Abdurahman and Tadesse were being held on $1.1 million bail. Their arraignments have been set for Oct. 20. Messages left at a listing in Lancaster for Abdurahman were not returned.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="0"/>
<context>
At that time the church was Dominion Christian Centre on Park Street North, near Cannon Street West, in Hamilton. In 2014, it moved to Burlington on Plains Road West near the Royal Botanical Gardens and now uses the name One Community Church. "The accused is the pastor and leader of this religious organization," Hennick said. On Sept. 4, 50-year-old Peter Rigo of Hamilton was <head>charged</head> with sexual assault and an indecent act. He was released on a promise to appear in court at a later date. The charges relate to a single incident. The church's board of directors released a statement Wednesday, saying it aware of the allegations and of its pastors. "We trust the judicial system and it's (sic) process to find this allegation false. We know our Pastor as a dedicated husband, father and friend and we steadfastly support him during this time."
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="4"/>
<context>
The owner of Caffe Tuscany and Fountain Park Family Restaurant is being asked by city officials to explain an incident that landed him a felony battery charge. Meanwhile, the owner has closed one of those businesses without notice or explanation. Jetmir Ameti was <head>charged</head> with felony substantial battery in early September after allegedly beating a man he had evicted from the Fountain Park Motel, which he also owns. City Attorney Chuck Adams said members of the city's Law and Licensing Committee want Ameti to explain what happened during the Aug. 28 incident so they can decide what action, if any, they should take with respect to his liquor license for Caffe Tuscany and Fountain Park Family Restaurant.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Jah’Corey D. Tyson, 23, was being held on family violence and rape charges when he was attacked, officials said. Indictments accuse Wyatt of strangling Tyson and “depriving [him] of his eye globes.” Tyson died after being transported to DeKalb Medical Center. In two separate indictments, Wyatt is <head>charged</head> with a total of 14 crimes — including two counts of malice murder, two counts of felony murder and four counts of aggravated assault. He is scheduled to be arraigned at 9 a.m. Wednesday in front of DeKalb County Judge Asha Jackson. During an arraignment, defendants are typically asked to enter a plea.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Deng was a student from New York trying to get into the Pi Delta Psi fraternity and authorities say he was badly beaten during a hazing ritual called the "glass ceiling." He died at the hospital shortly after. It happened at a home the frat was renting near Long Pond in 2013. This is the second wave of fraternity brothers to be <head>charged</head> in connection with Deng's death. They're facing charges for allegedly concealing evidence, giving cops false information, criminal conspiracy, and hazing. Police say these men were some of the least involved in Deng's death.  Those accused of the actual homicide will be
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Detectives had been investigating the activities at Orange Sun Therapy at 666 Plainsboro Road since July, when they received a quality-of-life complaint from a resident. On Tuesday, police searched the business and the Lawrenceville home of Yuzhu Zhou, 57, who was identified as the manager. Zhou was arrested at her home and <head>charged</head> with promoting prostitution. She was taken to the Middlesex County jail on $30,000 bail. When police searched Orange Sun Therapy, they found three female employees and two male customers, according to a news release.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="3"/>
<context>
with promoting prostitution. She was taken to the Middlesex County jail on $30,000 bail. When police searched Orange Sun Therapy, they found three female employees and two male customers, according to a news release. One of the employees had allegedly solicited an undercover officer earlier in the month, police said. She was arrested and <head>charged</head> with engaging in prostitution, police said. The employee did not have proper identification and was held in the Middlesex County jail as "Jane Doe," police said. A man inside the business, Milton Baker is accused of being a driver for the business, police said. Baker, 73, was
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="4"/>
<context>
People can face felony murder under a variety of circumstances. Texas prosecutors, for example, have used the statute against repeat drunk drivers to upgrade manslaughter charges to murder. The charge has also been given to individuals who are far more tangentially involved. In 2011, a Florida prosecutor <head>charged</head> shoplifter Mervin Bettis with felony murder after a Target security guard collapsed and later died after struggling to handcuff him. Bettis pleaded guilty to third-degree murder in 2013 in exchange for a five-year sentence.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Such cases, she says, require a different legal approach: Swain has to persuade jurors to not focus on whether her client is technically guilty of felony murder, but whether a life sentence is a fitting punishment for their indirect crime. “It’s up to you to convince jurors to act with their conscience and not their brain,” she said. “Attorneys don’t understand that jury nullification is about…[making] jurors see the unfairness of the situation.”One of her clients, Kyler Carriker, was <head>charged</head> with felony murder after he helped arrange a marijuana deal at a friend’s house. The buyer turned out to be a gang member intent on robbery, and he shot Carriker and killed the dealer. A jury ultimately agreed with Swain’s argument, and found Carriker not guilty of murder, though he still faces prison time for the drug conviction. “You have to have jurors that are going to be able to put themselves in that position and think, ‘Jesus, what if that was me? Would I want to be held accountable for a murder I didn’t have anything to do with?’” Swain said.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="0"/>
<context>
with murder after a decomposing body was discovered at a woodland beauty spot. The body of Hidir Aksakal, 53, who also goes by the names of Boxer Cetin and Musa Yakut, was found close to Hollow Ponds in Epping Forest, north-east London, on 9 September. Remzi Akguc, 40, has been <head>charged</head> with his murder and will appear at Redbridge magistrates’ court on Saturday. Aksakal, a Turkish national, lived in Margate, Kent, but had close links to the Green Lanes area of Haringey, north London, where he used to live. He was last seen in Green Lanes in the early hours of Monday 17 August. A postmortem examination revealed he was murdered, and detectives say his body could have been in Epping Forest for several weeks.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="0"/>
<context>
on 6 July 1539 at the Kreuzkirche, at the time the city's principal church. Its Kreuzschule performed the same function in Dresden as the more famous Thomasschule in Leipzig. The story of music in Dresden stretches back almost as far as the history of the city itself and can not detain us here other than pausing to note an earlier golden age that commenced when Heinrich Schtz was appointed to the court in 1615, nominally initially as subordinate to Michael Praetorius, the de facto Kapellmeister, but later in his own right as Kapellmeister. In fact Schtz was <head>charged</head> with wide ranging duties, including the rebuilding of the Kapelle for a new Elector, Johann Georg I. Schtz succeeded in this task with spectacular success, building the musical life of the court to a pinnacle of excellence that included the arrival of opera in Dresden in the shape of his Dafne of 1627, a lost work believed to be the first German opera. This illustrious era was brought to end when the devastating 30 Years War reached Saxony in 1631, necessitating a drastic reduction in musical activity.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="0"/>
<context>
innovation officers and starting innovation teams as a way to be more deliberate and disciplined in how they test new ideas and put them in place. Adding new positions in a tough economy may seem counterintuitive. But organizations point to the changing financial landscape, especially when it comes to government money, as one of the chief reasons for investing in innovation. At large nonprofits with lots of chapters, chief innovation officers look for new ideas that are making an impact at the local level and work to expand them across the organization. Some innovation officers are <head>charged</head> with figuring out how to use the latest research to improve services for clients, while others, together with their deputies, help organizations respond quickly to new opportunities. Not everyone, however, is convinced that hiring a chief innovation officer is the best way to drive organizational change in the nonprofit world.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Alex Ferguson last night insisted his men had been mugged in Moscow following Manchester United's disastrous UEFA Cup exit. The Old Trafford side lost out in a dramatic penalty shoot-out with Torpedo Moscow when Steve Bruce, Brian McClair and Gary Pallister all failed from the spot. But bitter Ferguson refused to blame individuals for United's continental calamity and said:' We let them in the back door and they stole the game. 'England defender Pallister was <head>charged</head> with keeping United alive, against a dour Moscow side, once the shoot-out went to sudden death. He found the nerve-racking task too much. Ferguson admitted, 'Even when Paul Ince and Denis Irwin had scored to put us 2-0 ahead, I still wasn't counting my chickens.' In fact, when the match moved into the shoot-out, I didn't really fancy our chances. 'The fact that striker Mark Hughes was dismissed in the 88th minute for a second bookable offence was almost forgotten as Ferguson
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="0"/>
<context>
That's probably helping Nora. It's not on the minutes, but just to remind you, the thirteenth and fourteenth of December, thanks Tony. Is it to be in the Town Hall? Is it in the Town Hall, Tony? Blessed if I can remember, chair, no. In St Catherine's, Vice Chair suggests. Page four? On page five, those of you who were at the last council meeting will know that the City Centre Management Working Party were <head>charged</head> with the responsibility of looking at the whole issue of street trading. They have now done that and they will be making a report, I hope, fairly shortly, either to us or (unclear) or both. On item four on page five, you'll see that we said' relevant papers to be sent to all members of council'. Pragmatically, I suggested to the officers that a summary of those papers be sent to all members of council in the interests of saving paper, and that
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="0"/>
<context>
output of private presses, which was growing much faster than that of the party and the state, had to be monitored, and surpassed in quality by party organs.' The rising gutter literature', as the private press was called, appealed especially to wayward youth. In this connection the whole of the local Komsomol press was ordered to put itself under the leadership of the party guberniia committees. In view of the unorthodox behaviour of the Komsomol that we have noted in the provinces, such a move was overdue. Finally, guberniia executive committees were <head>charged</head> with the resurrection of village reading-rooms, most of which had gone under in the changed economic conditions of NEP. Mere words could do little in the short term to reverse the chaotic situation. Saratov guberniia, admittedly a troubled area, reduced its press network from twenty-five organs in mid-1921 to two by the spring of 1922. Petrograd, still the cultural centre of the whole country, had been spared the cut-back of January 1922, but due to financial pressures four papers merged into two in order to save
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="0"/>
<context>
may be transferred, and binding promises may be made to an infant, but in general he is unable to make a binding disposition of his property or to make binding promises to others. As regards property, it should be noticed that law and practice, to a large extent, make it unlikely that property of any considerable value will come into the direct ownership of an infant. When property passes on death, it will go in the first instance to the executor appointed by will, or the administrator appointed by the court, who are <head>charged</head> with the duty of dealing with it and transferring it to the persons entitled (see p. 114). Similarly, under the settlements which people of property commonly make, the property will be in the hands of trustees. The infant can not give a receipt which executors, administrators or trustees can safely take. They must therefore retain the property to which an infant is entitled till he attains full age, and meanwhile deal with it under the directions of the will or settlement or under the orders
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="0"/>
<context>
For this reason an interval of six weeks elapses between the decree nisi, which is made upon the hearing of the case, and the decree absolute, which finally dissolves the marriage and enables the parties to marry again, though the court has power to expedite the decree absolute in a suitable case. During this interval any person may intervene to show cause, on the ground of, e.g., the suppression of material facts, why the decree should not be made absolute, and a public officer, the Queen's Proctor, is especially <head>charged</head> with the duty of intervening. The nature and degree of insanity which will afford a defence to a criminal charge has from time to time been a matter of considerable discussion. Where the defence arises our courts will act upon the so-called' M'Naghten' rules, propounded by the judges in response to questions addressed to them by the House of Lords. An accused person is presumed to be sane, until he can prove the contrary. He will be criminally liable unless he was so insane
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="0"/>
<context>
nevertheless be desirable for administration to be dispersed from the geographical centre and into the regions and localities where it takes actual effect' on the ground'. A third technique is devolution -- the separation, except for the ultimate and overriding authority of Parliament, of functions from central government entirely and their vesting in a subordinate authority. As has already been indicated, the modern vogue is for leviathan departments, headed by a Secretary of State and comprising a number of Ministries. Each of these Ministries will, in turn, have separate branches each <head>charged</head> with the administration of a particular facet of the Ministry's affairs. Thus, there may be within the Department of Health and Social Security, a Ministry of Social Security, containing a Pensions Branch. There is nothing constitutionally mandatory about any such particular structure but, both in existing legislation and particularly so far as internal civil service organisation is concerned, such a structure is assumed and there are heavy administrative costs involved in change. Notwithstanding that a particular central government department has total responsibility for
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Other European legislation, however, e.g. regulations of the Council of Ministers, guided by the Commission, is directly effective without further action by Parliament. In such cases, Parliament obviously has no legislative role once the law has been made. It is customary, however, for the Commission to publish drafts of legislation before submission to the Council of Ministers, and Parliament does, therefore, have the opportunity to comment on these drafts before they pass into law. To this end, a Select Committee on European Legislation, <head>charged</head> with examining such drafts, has been established. The Committee draws attention to any draft which it considers to raise a matter of political or legal importance. Much of the entire activity of Parliament is directed towards controlling or, possibly more accurately, embarrassing the Executive. This process takes place just as much in the context of legislating as in connection with other procedures which appear to lend themselves more obviously to this end.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="0"/>
<context>
to guide them, or a rational institutional structure to supervise them, tribunals can not develop a system of administrative law. Nevertheless, in the period after the Second World War, as the Labour government made significant advances in laying down its programme for a welfare state, there was a growing unease about the scale of administrative activity. These issues came to a head with the Crichel Down affair in the 1950s, which led to a general' moral panic' about administrative power. One of the reverberations was the establishment in 1955 of the Franks Committee, <head>charged</head> with the task of examining the working of the system of administrative tribunals and inquiries. At this stage, we should record, the ideological dimension of conservative normativism altered its tack. If the growth of administrative adjudication could not be prohibited, it was argued that it must be regularized by integrating it into the ordinary law of the land, thereby ensuring that it develops in harmony with traditional common law principles. The Report of the Franks Committee in 1957 was recognized by Robson as' an important landmark in
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The Commission was being asked to frame a philosophy for criminal justice and to measure the performance of penal proceedings against it. The remit extended to offenders of all ages. It called not only for an investigation of the sentencing powers and practice of the criminal courts, but of the sentencing process itself. The injunction to review the work of the services and institutions dealing with offenders included the prisons, young offender institutions, approved schools and the Probation Service. The whole endeavour was set in an international context, the Commission being <head>charged</head> with acquainting itself with modern penal practice abroad. The sixteen strong membership, headed by a former Minister, Viscount Amory, contained two judges, a Bishop, two Members of Parliament, a trade union leader, several magistrates, and two of the foremost criminologists of the day, Sir Leon Radzinowicz and Baroness Wootton of Abinger. From the start there were differences in approach and attitude. To Professor Radzinowicz and Barbara Wootton, both strong characters unaccustomed to taking no for an answer, any thorough re-examination of
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="3"/>
<context>
Thus, although examining magistrates may conduct a fresh investigation and take a detached look at the police evidence, it is difficult to establish whether this takes place to any serious extent. In Germany the responsibility for pretrial investigation is given to the public prosecutor in respect of both Verbrechen, offences punishable by imprisonment of one year or more, and Vergehen, punishable by lesser sentences. The police are under a duty to report all crimes to the prosecutor who is <head>charged</head> with the duty of conducting criminal investigations. Underlying the German criminal process is a principle of mutual trust between the police and the prosecutor. The result is that although prosecutors may direct investigations, they tend to leave matters to the police. At the start of the police interrogation the suspect is informed of his right of silence and of his right to consult a lawyer, but he has no right to have the lawyer present during the interrogation. A suspect may be accompanied by a lawyer when he is
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the light of the particular circumstances of the case. It was decided that, in the circumstances of that case, the discretion should be so exercised as not to require an undertaking in damages from the Crown. In that case, this House was concerned only with the position of the Crown in law enforcement actions. It was not concerned with the position of local authorities which have the function of enforcing the law in their districts in the public interest. Whether the same principle should be held to apply in the case of public authorities other than the Crown <head>charged</head> with the enforcement of the law falls to be decided in the present case. The majority of the Court of Appeal concluded that the same principle should not apply in the case of such public authorities. Dillon L.J. 19913 W.L.R. 985,994G concluded that the discretionary power not to require an undertaking in damages in a law enforcement action was' a privilege of the Crown alone.' In reaching that conclusion, he was much influenced by the fact that, in a relator action brought to enforce public rights or
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="2"/>
<context>
to be related not to the Crown as such but to the Crown when performing a particular function. It is true that, in all the speeches in that case, attention was focused upon the position of the Crown, for the obvious reason that it was the position of the Crown which was in issue in that case. But the considerations which persuaded this House to hold that there was a discretion whether or not to require an undertaking in damages from the Crown in a law enforcement action are equally applicable to cases in which some other public authority is <head>charged</head> with the enforcement of the law: see e.g. Lord Reid, at p. 341g, Lord Morris of Borth-y-Gest, at p. 352c, and Lord Cross of Chelsea, at p. 371b-g. In the circumstances, I find it difficult to understand why the same principle should not, in similar circumstances, apply to other public authorities when exercising the function of law enforcer in the public interest. It is instructive to turn to the position of the local authority in the present case. Plainly, the function of
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Nor do I feel compelled to depart from that conclusion by the fact that, under the present practice, a local authority which acts as a relator in a relator action is required to give an undertaking in damages even though it is so proceeding in order to enforce the law in the public interest. I observe that, in the Hoffmann-La Roche case, Lord Diplock distinguished the position of a relator on the ground that he owes no duty to the public to initiate any law enforcement action. In the present case, however, the Council is indeed <head>charged</head> with such a duty. That does not prevent the Crown from proceeding to enforce the law under its general powers; but it would be an extraordinary situation if a local authority, acting under a statutory duty, was required to give an undertaking in damages, whereas the Crown was not. To my mind, the position of the local authority as relator can not be decisive of the present case. The essential question is whether the court's discretion to require an undertaking in damages in law enforcement actions
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The procedural issue on which the appeal turns will naturally fall for decision in the light of the principles expounded in the speech of my noble and learned friend, Lord Diplock, in O'Reilly v. Mackman 19832 A.C. 237 in which judgment has just been delivered. But before attempting to apply those principles, it is necessary to analyse the functions of housing authorities under the Housing (Homeless Persons) Act 1977. These functions fall into two wholly distinct categories. On the one hand, the housing authority are <head>charged</head> with decision-making functions. It is for the housing authority to decide whether they have reason to believe the matters which will give rise to the duty to inquire or to the temporary housing duty. It is for the housing authority, once the duty to inquire has arisen, to make the appropriate inquiries and to decide whether they are satisfied, or not satisfied as the case may be, of the matters which will give rise to the limited housing duty or the full housing duty. These are essentially public
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="1"/>
<context>
as they have exercised a discretion (as they may require to do in considering questions of reasonableness under section 17(1) (2) and (4)), the exercise can be impugned on the principles set out in the judgment of Lord Greene M.R. in Associated Provincial Picture Houses Ltd. v. Wednesbury Corporation 19481 K.B. 223. All this is trite law and the contrary has, so far as I know, never been argued in any case which has come before the courts under the Act of 1977.' On the other hand, the housing authority are <head>charged</head> with executive functions. Once a decision has been reached by the housing authority which gives rise to the temporary, the limited or the full housing duty, rights and obligations are immediately created in the field of private law. Each of the duties referred to, once established, is capable of being enforced by injunction and the breach of it will give rise to a liability in damages. But it is inherent in the scheme of the Act that an appropriate public law decision of the housing authority is a
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Scotland, which is being published tomorrow. Sport 2000 seeks to create a situation where all sportsmen and women will have the opportunity to take part in sport at whatever level their ability or interest allows. It sets out, for the first time, a framework for achieving that situation and outlines the resources, both human and financial, which will be needed. But above all, it calls for a co-ordinated approach from the private, voluntary and public sectors to the development of sport in Scotland and suggests how that might be achieved. As the national agency <head>charged</head> with the promotion and development of sport, the Scottish Sports Council will take the lead and shortly we will be launching new initiatives to implement our role as identified in the strategy. However, it is important to stress that Sport 2000 should not be regarded as a Council strategy, rather it belongs to all who are committed to the future of sport in Scotland. The year-long consultative process which, as you may know, preceded the publication of Sport 2000, clarified the key and complementary roles to be
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="0"/>
<context>
ownership, management control and tangible net worth. Both LIFFE and its members are regulated under the provisions of the Financial Services Act, 1986. LIFFE is authorised as a Recognised Investment Exchange by the Securities and Investments Board (SIB), the chief regulator of the UK financial services industry. To satisfy the requirements for authorisation, LIFFE must ensure that its rules and market practices are such that business is conducted in an orderly manner and affords proper protection to investors. Daily supervision is the responsibility of LIFFE's Board of Management. Its Market Supervision Department is <head>charged</head> with ensuring an orderly market for contracts at all times. This department monitors the financial position of Exchange members and requires them to report daily on their aggregate open positions in each contract. In addition, it is authorised to inspect members' accounting records. The LIFFE Board has the authority to raise margin requirements and to close out positions on all or specific contracts in the event of a market emergency. The Securities and Futures Authority (SFA) which is the Self Regulating Organisation (SRO) for the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="0"/>
<context>
However, there is always a danger that in taking such measures a State may, intentionally or unintentionally, give undue assistance, and so promote its own industry at the expense of that of its trading partners. This will have the effect of distorting trade and militating against attaining the objectives of the SEM. Therefore, no outright exemptions are given under Article 92(2), and it is left to the Commission to determine the types of aid which are compatible. The procedure for control of State aids is set out in Article 93. In this the Commission is <head>charged</head> with keeping all State aids under continuous review, and member states are required to provide prior notification of any plans to grant or to alter aid. If the Commission then finds a proposal to be incompatible with the common market it is empowered to require its abolition or alteration, subject to the right of appeal to the European Court of Justice. Thus, there is a clear need for policy to regulate the granting of State aids, which after 1992 and the creation of the SEM will assume more importance
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="0"/>
<context>
This of course is a value judgement which a government is entitled to make, but it is one which some economists would argue is not fully justified by the evidence, on the basis of which there have been calls for much more stringent control. The main arguments for a tightening up of merger policy, along with suggestions as to how this could be achieved, are considered by George (1989). One suggestion that is favoured by a number of commentators would be to alter the onus of proof. At present the Monopolies and Mergers Commission is <head>charged</head> with determining whether a proposed merger is contrary to the public interest. This means that many mergers for which there have been no demonstrable advantages, but which have not been found to be overtly anti-competitive, have been allowed through, and thus contributed to the general increase in industrial concentration. This consequence of existing policy is particularly important in periods of high merger activity when there is a bandwagon effect with more and more firms seeking to engage in takeover activity.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="0"/>
<context>
resource misallocation which have been instrumental in influencing national policies have also been important in determining the shape of EC policy. Therefore, the EC has sought to develop a policy designed to secure the benefits that arise from a competitive market, since as national barriers to inter-state competition are removed there is a danger that these can be replaced by privately erected barriers. The competition policy of the EC stems from the Treaty of Rome and is mainly embodied in Articles 85 and 86. These were designed to ensure free competition within the EC, with the European Commission being <head>charged</head> with the responsibility for applying the legislation. In the process of this the Commission has to work closely with national governments, and so it is clearly desirable that domestic and EC law should be mutually consistent. Individual states still retain the right to develop their own distinct policies on competition where trade is contained within their national boundaries. Therefore, even after the completion of the SEM, the provisions of UK competition policy remain unaffected, inasmuch as they concern internal UK trade. However, in terms of trade
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="0"/>
<context>
These consist of the treatment of dominant firm monopolies, restrictive practices and mergers. In 1973 the Fair Trading Act brought these together within the purview of a single body, the newly created Office of Fair Trading, to be overseen by a civil servant, the Director General of Fair Trading. Where a firm or a group of firms acting collectively, accounts for 25 per cent of the market or more, the Director General of Fair Trading can refer the industry to the Monopolies and Mergers Commission for investigation. This body is then <head>charged</head> with providing a general report upon the operation of the industry, and making recommendations for change where the public interest is seen to be compromised. The Secretary of State at the Department of Trade and Industry then has complete liberty to accept or reject these recommendations, and to decide whether, and how, they should be acted upon. It is interesting to contrast this statutory definition of monopoly of " one quarter " with that of economic theory where monopoly refers to the existence of a single firm.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="0"/>
<context>
in respect of both types of system. Culyer et al. (1988) stress that' care will have to be exercised to ensure that very sick and elderly patients are not treated or cared for long distances away from their homes and families'. Possibly one of the most dramatic implications is the effect of the two different systems on health (care) planning. Type I systems, because they allocate funds to a health authority, which is <head>charged</head> with responsibility for the health (care) of its (geographically defined) population, will not only ensure, but will require, an important planning role for the health authority, to ensure that local needs and priorities are pursued. However, the Type I system is not without problems. As discussed below, the problems of letting contracts, controlling payments and maintaining quality would be immense in the more radical proposals. In addition, individual health authorities would enter the' Internal Markets' with different historical
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="0"/>
<context>
criticized behaviour will be discontinued. In fact, it is only a slight exaggeration to say that the main deterrent effect of monopoly policy has been not the threat of what changes might be required as a result of the MMC investigation, but the threat of having to tie up a large quantity of senior executives' time to argue the firm's case in the event that its activities attract a reference to the MMC. The Commission has investigated a wide range of cases, from beer to breakfast cereals and from contraceptives to cross-Channel ferries. Because the MMC is <head>charged</head> to investigate each case with an open mind, its judgements have tended to stress different aspects of behaviour in different cases. Certainly a high market share has not been sufficient to attract an unfavourable judgement. For example, Pilkington's Glass (making car windscreens) and Rank Xerox (making copiers) were honourably acquitted in spite of huge market shares and healthy profits. In both cases the MMC held that these companies were efficiently run and had contributed to substantial cost savings, the Schumpeterian view of monopoly to
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="0"/>
<context>
of competition and consumer law including the regulation of quality and standards discussed in Chapter 15. The Director-General is responsible for a monitoring company behaviour and, subject to a ministerial veto, can refer individual cases to the Monopolies and Mergers Commission (MMC) for a thorough investigation. A company can be referred if it supplies more than 25 per cent of the total market. The Commission can also be given cases where two or more distinct firms by implicit collusion operate to restrict competition. There is no presumption that monopoly is necessarily bad, and the Commission is <head>charged</head> to investigate whether or not the monopoly acts against the public interest, a brief that may be widely interpreted though in recent years there has been increasing emphasis on the' maintenance and promotion of effective competition'. The Restrictive Practices Court examines agreements between firms supplying goods and services in the UK, for example agreements on collusive pricing behaviour. All agreements must be notified to the Director-General of Fair Trading, who will refer them to the Court unless they are voluntarily abandoned or judged of trivial significance. The
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="0"/>
<context>
but just as important adjustments, have been made to the structure of the IBOA. Biennial district Meetings took place in every District in April. The future policy of the Association was discussed at these meetings. Amongst many other items, policy on terms and conditions was decided, policy on equality was discussed and policy on industrial relations matters was also reviewed. These policy decisions now fall upon the new Executive Committee to pursue with enthusiasm, vigour and zeal. The new Executive Committee is now poised to take the membership of the IBOA into the future and is <head>charged</head> with the task of navigating the difficult course that lies ahead. Traditional working conditions and fundamentals are being eroded by the Banks in the relentless pursuit of increased profitability with scant regard for their other responsibilities. They include a responsibility to staff who depend on their employers for a decent standard of living and a responsibility to the customer who expects a decent service. The customer pays all salaries, from the Chief Executive to the newest recruit. Where are the staff that were to be recruited to service the customers
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="0"/>
<context>
adjusted at local levels to reflect national possibilities. For governments, logic would suggest a simple sequence of thought and action. Starting from a recognition of the constraints and opportunities set by human and natural resource endowments, one might assume that they then define a broad set of goals for the future. These set the sights of ambition, often embodied in a series of national plans, what we called national intent in chapter 1. These goals form the basis of both macro-level policies for industry. National institutions and agencies, each responsible for one agenda, are <head>charged</head> with administering specific policies for each sector and each group of multi-nationals. Trouble arises at this point, for no country can ensure that all its ministries and agencies manage everything in a wholly co-ordinated way. There are dilemmas at every level of concern; different interest groups hold different priorities. Thus it is common for policies to be announced but not implemented fully or consistently. Where a country espouses outward-looking policies, it may continue to behave in many important respects as though it were still domestically focused. Dilemma
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="0"/>
<context>
avoided, at least in principle. But then it is hard to see how that arrangement could be described as, or even contribute to, industrial democracy. The reality that there are rights of ownership and that they are liable to, and do, conflict with those of labour can not be exorcised by pretending that they are not there; and it is the exclusion of the public sector from the Committee's purview which admits that reality. A nationalised industry is owned by the State. The public corporation in which its assets are vested and which is <head>charged</head> with the conduct of the business, is accountable to Parliament. The Secretary of State at the head of its sponsoring Department of State must lay its annual report and accounts before Parliament which may debate them and which may, if it thinks fit, call the Chairman and others before a select committee, examine them and report on their performance. Thus, Members of Parliament may be said to occupy much the same position with respect to the nationalised industries as do shareholders with respect to a joint stock company
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="0"/>
<context>
direct test of the economic theory, and the results of these few tests are not clear cut. Thus there seems nothing inevitable about the process. What is more, such actions as imposing regulation, though they may tend to acquire a momentum of their own, are nevertheless hardly irreversible. Preferences can change, and if different political parties have differing views, a private rather than social interest can not be expected to persist for ever. There is another strand to the Economic theory of regulation, which is that once the agency has an objective, those <head>charged</head> with carrying out the policies do so to the best of their ability. This is not because they wish to act in the public interest as exemplified in the values of their political masters, but rather because they wish to succeed in their careers and the way to do so is to appear efficient. This is a rather strict version of the managerial labour market theory (Fama, 1980) which will be discussed in chapter 3. Yet, again, it is surely difficult to test.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Other issues raised in this report included the pooling of the internal audit service of some authorities and the establishment of audit committees. Lapsley and Prowle (1978) carried out comprehensive surveys that lent considerable weight to the reforms suggested in the working group's report. However, progress was slow, hence the recent changes embodied in the 1990 Act, which clearly recognizes the success of the Audit Commission in local government. Time alone will tell if the Commission is to be equally successful in the field of health care. A Health Studies Directorate, <head>charged</head> with developing health VFM topics, has been established. The first three-year programme of health studies was as follows: The Directorate includes medical staff and is liaising closely with appropriate professional bodies, including Royal Colleges. The Director of Management Practice is developing health profiles, similar to the Commission's work with local authority profiles, which will compare costs between health authorities. These are based on existing sources of information but presented in a different way. # Nationalized industries # The relevant Secretary of State of each nationalized
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="0"/>
<context>
played by the Comptroller and Auditor General (C &; AG) and the various Select Committees of the House of Commons. The C &; AG's role is more properly understood if his full title is given:' The Comptroller General of the Receipt and Issue of Her Majesty's Exchequer and Auditor General of Public Accounts'. He is not a civil servant but is a direct Crown appointee who can only be removed from office by an address from both Houses of Parliament. As his title suggests, he has two functions. As Comptroller General he is <head>charged</head> with authorizing the amounts paid out to spending departments by the Paymaster General, in accordance with the votes specified in the Appropriation Act. As Auditor General he audits, on behalf of the House of Commons, accounts of the transactions of the Consolidated Fund, National Loans Fund and every Appropriation Account. He submits reports on these and other accounts to Parliament. His more general role was discussed in chapter 6. The (all-party) Public Accounts Committee considers the accounts of each government department and the reports on
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Audit is an ex post event and improvements in this important function may be of little long-term value if they are not coupled with more general reforms of the accountability of government. The expanded audit mandates discussed in chapter 6 mean that auditors are no longer solely concerned with fiscal compliance; rather they are now <head>charged</head> with assessing and reporting on management's efforts to develop effective programmes as efficiently as possible. One consequence of the National Audit Act 1983 is that the Comptroller and Auditor General (C &; AG) has adopted a new publishing policy. These reports are now published separately and not, as previously, treated as appendices to the reports of the Public Accounts Committee or the Appropriation Accounts. The intention behind this policy is to reach a wider audience, with consequently greater publicity and public awareness of the investigations undertaken
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="0"/>
<context>
financial accountability and how it should be achieved externally, through financial reporting, and internally, through managerial accountability is then considered in greater detail. This chapter, therefore, mainly concentrates upon the theory of what should be done as opposed to what is done. Such an analysis is an important prerequisite to much of the discussion that follows in succeeding chapters. # Alternative Concepts of Accountability # Public accountability is a essential component for the functioning of our political system. Glynn (1985, p. 143) states that' public sector accountability means that those who are <head>charged</head> with drafting and/or carrying out policy should be obliged to give a explanation of their actions to their electorate'; the electorate being a composite group that includes clients, employees and taxpayers. As Heald (1983, p. 155) states: The growth in the public sector, both in terms of its scale and the diversity of its activities, has outstretched the traditional machinery of public accountability, heavily dependent upon the formal relationship between the executive and the legislative. There have emerged alternative views of what accountability
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="0"/>
<context>
in a humanitarian manner. At this point the manufacturing entity, which was the largest facet of the organization in terms of people, initiated a change effort that was very creatively managed. Although the starting point was the requirement of reducing numbers of employees, this requirement was translated into a productivity-improvement program that was implemented under the leadership of a transition-management team composed of high-potential managers. The team members solicited improvement suggestions from the entire organization, received several hundred, and culled these to approximately fifteen. Then they set up fifteen study groups, each of which was <head>charged</head> with designing a new state for one of the fifteen suggestions. When the study-group reports and recommendations had been submitted and approved by the hierarchy, transition teams were established to manage the process of implementing the recommendations. Finally the new states began to emerge. This change process enabled the manufacturing entity to effect not only the required reduction in numbers of employees, but also an improvement in operation. With many fewer people, ideas that had been considered impossible, such as combinations of major functions, were now
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="0"/>
<context>
pointing out the inequities in the situation, the CEOs have raised a dust storm that seems to obscure other important issues relating to corporate auditing and accounting. First, the Big Six document ignores the very real presence of an audit crisis involving huge corporate failures and frauds, particularly in the banking and insurance industries. Given the nature of these failures, and their reasonably clear association with audited accounting information, it is not surprising that auditors become legally implicated. It is corporate failures and the auditor's role in them which should be of fundamental concern to professionals <head>charged</head> with protecting the public interest -- not with their economic self-interest, which is a secondary issue in professionalised activity. Second, there are numerous examples in recent years of audit failures which have resulted in public comment, action and professional disciplining. For example, it is not just private organisations and individuals who take legal action against auditors. Regulators can also be seen to be indicting firms. And auditors are found guilty in court, censored by regulatory investigators, and have even had their practising licences suspended in
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="0"/>
<context>
to talk about the wonderful services that you get in Western Europe but are clueless about how much it costs the middle class. There will most undoubtedly be a revolution in this country were we to be taxed at anything close to these rates! It is the same reason why this country was founded. Stop the moronic spending and the country will thrive! A big joke! 75% what in F.. >> the French leftist are smoking? Why any one in world would have an inttiative to open a busines or create jobs so they can get <head>charged</head> 75%. It will lead to higher un employment and yeah do nt hold your breath that people will stick around so they can get raped yes raped out of 75% of their income. and i assure you is not going to stop the riots of freloaders. Firstly a french citizin will still be regarded taxable to the french laws if his family lives in France. So his wife and children will have to imigrate and start living in a different country, different language, different culture.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="0"/>
<context>
based on the terms in effect when the listing goes live and when it renews. Advanced listing upgrade fees for auction-style listings. In addition to the advanced listing upgrades above, the following upgrades are specific just to auction-style listings. Supplemental service fees.If you use supplemental services, or other services offered by eBay or third parties, then charges associated with those services may also be treated as fees. Depending on the service, and at eBay's option, these charges may be included on your seller invoices as a fee, which may be <head>charged</head> to your automatic payment method on file, if any. Supplemental services include, but aren't limited to: Examples of fee calculations. You're selling a lightly used hardcover book. You select a starting price of $2.00, with a shipping cost of $3.50. You've listed fewer than 50 items this month. The winning bid for the book is $10.25, so the total amount of the sale is $13.75. The final value fee is $1.24, or 9% of 13.75.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="0"/>
<context>
and are nonrefundable. Fee amounts are based on the terms in effect when the listing goes live and when it renews. We require payment in full each month on accounts with an amount due of $1 or more. If you haven't paid the amount due by the payment due date each month, late fees may apply. Learn more about payment requirements, due dates, and late fees. We may limit the exposure of duplicate auction-style listings to ensure a positive buyer experience. If you list duplicate, identical auction-style listings, you'll be <head>charged</head> the full insertion fee for each listing even if a listing doesn't appear on eBay for the full duration of the listing. See the duplicate listings policy for more information. Seller fees don't purchase exclusive rights to web pages on eBay. We may, in our sole discretion and without consent from or payment to sellers, display third-party advertisements (including links and references thereto) and listings from other sellers on any eBay web page. When you submit your listing, it might not appear
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="0"/>
<context>
the rate for senior citizen couples will rise by 50p to 14. The increase in the adult rate is 1 going up to 14. At the same time we have decided to calculate family membership at twice the adult rate (28). Although this represents a greater increase (7) than in the other categories, it seems only fair that two single adults should not have to pay more than a family. However, to ease the transition, existing Friends renewing their family membership for 1993/94 will be <head>charged</head> a special reduced renewal rate of 26. There will be no increase in the cost of life membership. The new subscription rates still represent exceptional value. For 54p a week, a family of Friends enjoys, among other benefits, free entry to all Historic Scotland monuments and, from the second year of membership, to all English and Welsh CADW monuments (with half-price admission in the first year). There is also the satisfaction of supporting work which will ensure the preservation of Historic Scotland's properties
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="0"/>
<context>
International Motor Cycle Show Britain's biggest bike show, with everything for the motorbike enthusiast. Crufts Dog Show Details of events listed are correct at time of going to press, but please check all information before booking your Warm Hearted Weekend. Dial TICKETlink for immediate information on concerts, theatre, events, ticket prices and availability. Calls <head>charged</head> at 36p per minute cheap rate, 48p per minute all other times (prices correct at time of going to press). It is very simple - from 22 per person per night, depending on your choice of hotel. The price is clearly indicated for every hotel featured in the brochure. This includes full English breakfast, service and VAT. A single room supplement of 8 per person per night applies at hotels indicated.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="0"/>
<context>
For letters and packages up to a weight limit of 2kg you can simply pay 1.95 in addition to the normal airmail postage for the weight and destination and affix a red SWIFTAIR sticker to each item. Alternatively, for items up to 150g, you can buy pre-paid SWIFTPACKS which come in three different sizes at the following prices: These prices are fully pre-paid to anywhere in the world for items up to the weight limits designated above. If you wish to send an item that exceeds the weight limit on your pre-paid SWIFTPACK the excess is <head>charged</head> at normal airmail rates. Simply calculate the extra weight and add the correct value of stamps for that particular weight and destination. SWIFTAIR stickers and SWIFTPACKS are both available at your local post office. SWIFTPACKS can also be purchased by mail order from the address given in this leaflet. Companies with a regular collection can include SWIFTAIR items in their post if they are separated from other mail by an elastic band. Larger users can take advantage of an account facility.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Chef Jeremy Ashpool will arouse your tastebuds with 6 course haute cuisine feast amongst flaming tarts, comedians, falling angels, dancers, and string quartets. 24hr information line Dial 0891 600 305 anytime, day or night, for recorded information on Festival events and ticket availability. This line is voice activated and enables the caller to select which information they require. Easy to follow instructions on how to use this service are given by ringing the above number. Calls are <head>charged</head> at 36p min. off peak and 48p at all other times. A Festival information point is situated in central Brighton at 111 Church Street, open daily during Festival, 10am-5pm. Information is also available at the Tourist Information Centre, Marlborough House, on the Old Steine, 9am-5 pm Mon-Sat, and at TICs throughout the region.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="0"/>
<context>
If you want to change any details of your booking (e.g. transfer to a different holiday, departure date or airport), we will do our best to help. We charge an Amendment Fee of 12 per person named on the booking for each detail of the booking changed. However, if within 6 weeks of departure you change your booking to a later date, the cancellation charges will apply as shown in paragraph 4 unless the new holiday departs on or before the original departure date, when the normal fee of 12 per person will be <head>charged</head>. Where the price varies depending on the number of persons booked into the accommodation and you wish to change that number of persons, the price will be restored on the basis of the new party size as shown in the price panel. Any increase in price per person payable as a result of a part cancellation is not a Cancellation Charge and so is not covered by Norwich Union Insurance. A separate Cancellation Charge will be levied in respect of bookings cancelled in accordance with paragraph 4.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Vera Nicholls served up teas on a charity stall -- and was sacked on the spot by her boss, who ran a cafe opposite. Barry Jones boiled over when he saw 63-year-old Vera brewing up for a local hospice on her day off. The charity cuppa cost 30p, while Mr Jones <head>charged</head> 60p. Shocked granny Vera said last night:' I was washing up cups at the time and he told me he didn't agree with what I was doing.' When I protested he accused me of being lippy.' I am very upset because the stall was for a good cause.' Mr Jones, 43, who runs the cafe in Ross-on-Wye, said:' I took exception to the fact that she was selling teas outside our door without informing me first.' He said
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="0"/>
<context>
In Norway recently, I noticed that most buildings had a flag pole with their national colours flying. Why are we in Britain made to feel guilty about flying the Union Jack just because on occasions it is used by extremists?. What a racket in the supermarkets. Twice I've picked up goods on a shelf marked reduced and then found, because of the bar codes, I was <head>charged</head> full price at the pay-out desk. Friends confirm that it happens often. My husband applied for disability allowance in April 1991. After supplying medical records and repeatedly telephoning the department, we were told in September that they had mislaid his file. We started again. Early in August, after sending the department a recorded delivery letter every month from January, I was finally informed that my husband would be granted his claim.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="0"/>
<context>
It includes the employing of up to five hundred extra staff to help speed up the initial determination of claims. It also includes plans to withdraw advice and assistance under legal aid green form scheme in asylum and other immigration cases. Necessary legal advice and assistance will be available from the United Kingdom Immigration Advisory Service whose grant will be substantially increased. Controls at entry ports will be strengthened to improve identification of applicants who arrive from safe countries. Carriers bringing passengers from abroad without valid documentation will be <head>charged</head> at double the current rate. Improved document checks abroad and better screening procedures for identifying undocumented asylum seekers will be introduced. None of these measures will prevent the entry into the United Kingdom of the genuine immigrant or asylum seeker. These are the very people who will most benefit from the proposed changes. The genuine people. They are precisely the ones who will gain from the accelerated handling of clearly unfounded cases. The Home Secretary has made it absolutely clear that he remains committed to meeting our obligation to
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="0"/>
<context>
otherwise be appropriate, it would contravene article 9 of the Bill of Rights 1688 or Parliamentary privilege so to do. The facts are fully set out in the judgments of Vinelott J. at first instance 19901 W.L.R. 204 and of the Court of Appeal 1991Ch. 203. Shortly stated, the taxpayers are nine masters and the bursar employed by Malvern College (' the school'). For many years the school has run a concessionary scheme under which members of the staff are entitled to have their children educated at the school on payment of only one-fifth of the sum <head>charged</head> to members of the public. In the relevant tax years, 1983-84,1984-85 and 1985-86, children of one or more of the taxpayers were educated at the school on payment of the concessionary fees only. It is common ground that the concessionary fees more than covered the additional cost to the school of educating the taxpayers' children. The school had a capacity to accept 625 boys but in the relevant years the school was not full to capacity. The admission of the taxpayers' children to the school therefore did
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="0"/>
<context>
such references might constitute a breach of parliamentary privilege? I will consider these issues in turn, but first I must set out the Parliamentary history of sections 61 and 63 by reference to which the case was argued before us. For reasons which will appear it is necessary first to refer to the legislation affecting the taxation of benefits in kind before 1975. Under the Finance Act 1948, section 39(1), directors and employees of bodies corporate earning more than 2,000 per annum were taxed under Schedule E on certain benefits in kind. The amount <head>charged</head> was the expense incurred by the body corporate' in or in connection with the provision' of the benefit in kind. By section 39(6) it was provided that references to expenses' incurred in or in connection with any matter includes a reference to a proper proportion of any expense incurred partly in or in connection with that matter.' Employment by a school or charitable organisation was expressly excluded from the charge: sections 41(5) and 44. These provisions were re-enacted in the Income and Corporation Taxes Act 1970.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The words' in connection with' have the widest connotation and I can not see how they are to be restricted in the absence of some context permitting such restriction. The strongest argument in favour of the taxpayers is the anomaly which would arise if the employer's business were running at a loss or was subsidised by endowment. As I have explained, in such a case the adoption of the literal meaning of the statutory words would lead to a result whereby the taxpayer is assessed at an amount greater than that <head>charged</head> by the employer to the public for the same service. The Crown have no answer to this anomaly as such. But there are other anomalies which arise if the taxpayer's argument is correct. For example if, unlike the present case, the school could have been filled with boys paying the full fee, the school would have lost the fee income from the places occupied by the children of the taxpayers for whom only the concessionary fee was payable. Without deciding the point, it seems to me
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="0"/>
<context>
the Public Health Committee. Understandably, the south of the borough, where areas such as Tidal Basin had death rates nearly seven times higher than wealthy wards in the north such as Park and Upton (see, for example, West Ham Medical Officer of Health 1918) received prior claim. By far the largest provider of maternity welfare in the south was the Plaistow Maternity Hospital. Originally established in 1889 to' provide for the poor of the neighbourhood... nursing in their own homes in maternity and other cases' (Plaistow Maternity Hospital 1903), it <head>charged</head> no fee for the attendance of a midwife where the husband's wage was less than 21 shillings. In 1910,4793 cases were attended (ibid. 1936). Of less significance as a provider, but in the long term a more powerful agent of change, was the Canning Town Health Society. It was established by the Canning Town Women's Settlement in 1906, with a wide brief to improve local health by giving advice and information, investigating sanitary conditions and promoting improvements. A baby visiting committee was immediately
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="0"/>
<context>
the matter and its importance to the client. This translates in reality into the use of time charging plus a mark-up for the profit element and for the care and conduct of the matter. For the latter, half of one per cent of the value of the matter to the client is common. Clients are often aggrieved by the size of the bill delivered at the conclusion of the business brought to the solicitor and, save perhaps recently for conveyancing work, advance estimates of total costs are not common. There are three ways clients can challenge the fees <head>charged</head>. First, they can always return to the solicitor to seek more details of the basis of charging; many bills are uninformative about this. Secondly, they can require the solicitor to obtain a remuneration certificate from The Law Society to show whether the fees are fair and reasonable. This involves the solicitor submitting full details of the transaction for consideration by The Law Society. If the fees certified by The Law Society are lower than those in the bill, only the lower sum is recoverable by the solicitor
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="0"/>
<context>
are within the tribunal's jurisdiction, i. e. those facts which the tribunal alone decides, and those facts which are outside its jurisdiction, i. e. facts which must be established as a condition precedent for the tribunal to exercise its power. In our example the courts would classify the condition of the house, " furnished, " as a jurisdictional fact. If this is not established the tribunal would have no power to act. If it did act, it would have made a jurisdictional error and its decision would be a nullity. The amount of rent <head>charged</head> would be a matter within the jurisdiction of the tribunal, a matter on which it would have the power to err. Other courts might not agree that the rent was fair but unless there was a right of appeal, they would not be empowered to intervene. A major difficulty of this approach is that no foolproof method of distinguishing between jurisdictional facts and facts within jurisdiction has been developed. It also severely restricts judicial review in that it does not allow any review for abuse of power, an essential
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="0"/>
<context>
of an acceptable credit standing. Since 1981, the Bank no longer continuously' posts' or announces the terms on which it will deal in bills. The Bank has made it clear that the implied interest rate in such deals will be designed to discourage the use of the lender of last resort facility by the discount houses. Thus, when the discount houses offer to sell bills to the Bank, the latter is in a strong position to influence rates of interest in the bill market by refusing to buy at the rates quoted. The implied interest rate <head>charged</head> by the Bank on loans to the discount houses will usually be higher than the market rate on bills. Thus, the discount houses may be making losses on the loans they are repaying to the commercial banks. The discount houses will want to repay the loans from the Bank quickly, and so will reduce the price at which they bid for the next issue of Treasury Bills, thus increasing the Treasury Bill rate. As funds are attracted into the market for Treasury Bills from other parts of the money
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="0"/>
<context>
is that the consumer, in economically difficult times, is more likely to be attracted by the opportunity to save money than by incidental free offers or competitions. Price promotions are predominantly used by fast-moving consumer goods producers, especially in the grocery trade. Premium offers are marketing techniques which give extra value to goods or services in the short term as part of a promotional package. Under this category are the following. An offer of merchandise is communicated to the customer in, on or off the pack. The price <head>charged</head> to the customer covers the cost of the item to the promoter. The promoter is able to purchase such merchandise in bulk and thereby pass savings on to the customers who feel that they are getting good value for money. Such promotions are usually linked with the necessity to collect labels or cut out tokens, etc., from a number of purchases of the same, or same range of, products. Thus the premium need not necessarily be connected with the product that carried the premium; the idea is
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Target jointly and severally liable for the transferor group's VAT for the prescribed accounting period in which it joins the group registration and the next following prescribed accounting period, and Newco should therefore request an indemnity for any resulting VAT liability of Target. Conversely, the vendor may ask Newco to provide a counter-indemnity for VAT attributable to Target's supplies (and acquisitions of goods from other EC member states) for which the vendor or another vendor group company will be liable to account as representative member of the vendor's VAT group. Alternatively, no VAT will be <head>charged</head> to Target if the hive-down of the business is a transfer of a going concern as described in 5.1.3 above and the requirements of Art 5 VAT (Special Provisions) Order 1992 are satisfied. Purpose There are various reasons why it might be desirable to transfer Target's business to Newco after the acquisition. If this is not done and a future purchaser of the business wishes to buy assets rather than Target's shares, it will be necessary to distribute the proceeds of disposal
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="100">
<answer instance="100" senseid="0"/>
<context>
applies, there is simply a Schedule E income tax charge on the managers to the extent of the benefit they have received, on the basis that this constitutes an emolument from their office or employment. If s19 applies, ss160 and 162 will not (see s162(11)). If ss160 and 162 apply, their effect is to treat the " beneficial element " of the Newco shares as if it were an interest-free loan to the managers, and tax them under Schedule E on the " cash equivalent " of the beneficial loan, ie tax on notional interest <head>charged</head> at the official rate while the " loan " remains outstanding. A further Schedule E income tax charge can arise when the shares are disposed of " by surrender or otherwise " so that the manager concerned no longer has any beneficial interest in them. Such a disposal is treated as if the outstanding amount of the notional loan had been released or written off. There should be no element of double charge when the manager disposes of his shares because the " notional loan " element should not also be liable
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="101">
<answer instance="101" senseid="0"/>
<context>
position of the money market. Favourable financing from the Public Works Loan Board is still made available to the local authorities, although the money market rationale has largely disappeared and local authorities borrow only limited amounts directly in the capital markets. But with questions raised about the credit worthiness of some local authorities, is the provision of cheap finance from central government the best way of financing such institutions? Ought they to be forced to borrow more directly in the capital market, so that their credit worthiness can be assessed in the market and an appropriate interest rate be <head>charged</head>? The absence of new gilt issues for a period from 1988 to 1991 and the steeply inverted yield curve for much of that time meant that the eurosterling bond market developed strongly. To some extent this market was tapped by UK corporate borrowers who then swapped the funds to achieve LIBOR related funding. Such long term fixed rate financing opportunities may not be so readily available in the future, with the chance of the corporate sector being crowded, or priced, out of the long end of the market.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="102">
<answer instance="102" senseid="0"/>
<context>
course of action is followed a further 140 will need to be spent to rectify the faults. Answer guide: This question needs to be split up into its constituent parts in order to take the student through the progression logically. First of all the sale needs to be dealt with. If we assume that the customer has paid for the goods then the first entries would have been to increase the bank by 600 and include in the profit and 1088 account sales of 600. We would also have reduced the asset for goods in stock by 400 and <head>charged</head> this amount to the profit and loss account as an expense for the period. We can now examine what should happen in the alternative situations outlined above. In this case we need to reduce the bank by 100 and reduce the profit and loss by 100. Whether the latter is put through as a reduction in sales or a rebate should be discussed in terms of the effects of these alternatives on the usefulness of the profit and loss account as a guide to the future.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="103">
<answer instance="103" senseid="0"/>
<context>
are treated as part of the net cash flow of the business and are available for use as transfers from fixed assets to current assets and possibly back again, in whatever way is most beneficial to the business. What has actually happened to them is not always clear from the balance sheet. The calculation of depreciation for tax purposes is governed by the tax authority's rules and is not necessarily related to the amounts actually <head>charged</head> in the business accounts. In bookkeeping terms the depreciation amounts are regarded as debit entries in an intermediate account which is then transferred to the profit and loss account at the end of the accounting period. The corresponding credit entries go to the asset account concerned, reducing the written down value, and to a depreciation reserve account. Balances of both depreciation reserve and asset accounts are carried forward to the end of the useful life of the asset. At this point any scrap value received is credited to the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="104">
<answer instance="104" senseid="0"/>
<context>
stations. Whereas before the War, the peak had come with lighting demand in the late winter afternoons, it was, for some years after the War, between 8 and 9a.m. when the domestic space heating demand was at its height. Inevitably the industry came under some pressure from the Government to control this burgeoning demand from domestic consumers, without which the capacity crisis would have been a good deal less serious. The first years of nationalisation were thus regularly punctuated by government demands for consideration of rationing by price or by direct load limitation. The prices being <head>charged</head> by the industry after the War were undoubtedly excessively low, and this in itself had artificially stimulated consumer demand. In the decade prior to nationalisation, electricity tariffs had hardly increased at all in money terms, and the average domestic price of electricity had fallen faster than in any other decade in history, both in real terms and relative to the price of its major competitors, gas and coal. By 1948, although living standards in general were no higher than a decade previously, the average domestic consumer
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="105">
<answer instance="105" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Area Boards to shift to' two-part' or' block'tariffs which had been adopted by most of the larger, progressive undertakings before nationalisation. These encouraged greater electricity use and more accurately reflected the underlying decreasing cost structure of domestic supply. Under a two-part tariff there was a basic standing charge (aiming to cover costs of servicing the account, connecting supply and providing generating capacity) and a low charge per kWh of electricity purchased. Under a block tariff, the initial kWh purchased carried a high price, but if consumption increased the extra blocks of kWh were <head>charged</head> at a significantly lower rate. The effect of both tariffs was the same: the more, electricity the consumer used, the less he would on average pay per kWh. The Boards directed their marketing policy to the same expansionary end as their electricity tariffs: trying to sell those appliances -- particularly cookers and water heaters -- which used additional large quantities of electricity. Whereas a consumer using electricity only for lighting, an iron, a radio and a vacuum cleaner might use under 300kWh a year, the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="106">
<answer instance="106" senseid="0"/>
<context>
simple, assume that the gymnasium was built and paid for in cash within a year. Assume also that a specific loan was raised to finance the building cost. The journal entries would be: During the subsequent year, as the law requires, provision would have to be made for the principal and interest repayments on the loan in the revenue account. The repayments in this first year are: Together these amounts are called' debt charges'. The figures assume that the loan is to be repaid using equal annual instalments over 20 years and interest is <head>charged</head> at 10 per cent of the reducing balance. The number of years over which loans could be repaid was a matter for each individual authority, subject to maxima laid down by the Government for given categories of assets. The only other two entries in the accounts relate to the collection of taxes and tax-related grants of 50m and net expenditure (before repayments of principal and interest) of 52m. The accounts for the year would be as follows: Now the debt charges would have to be paid to the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="107">
<answer instance="107" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Company Financial Information and, from last month, the Infocheck Global Scan service. Also available are a range of City and business services including FT Profiles, Infomat Industry Watch, Citiwatch, Infocheck M &A; database and Daily Business Brief, UK and European versions of Kompass and of course the indispensable Electronic Yellow Pages. Telecom Gold requires a PC and a suitable modem (which many offices will have anyway) and costs are by subscription (40 plus 5.50 a month) with services billed on a' pay as you go' basis. The new Global Scan service will be <head>charged</head> on a transaction bases and other services may follow this pattern, although this will require some alterations to BT's own billing software. Now most credit managers will be familiar with farms such as CCN and Infolink, so why should they go through British Telecom? Clearly, high volume users are probably better off accessing the databases of their choice directly, and are probably able to negotiate discounts, but Mr Rosenbaum says that BT's own
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="108">
<answer instance="108" senseid="0"/>
<context>
considered in the Consumer Safety Act, 1978, which draws up regulations to minimise risks to consumers from potentially dangerous products, such as oil heaters, electric blankets and certain children's toys. 9. Moneylenders have abounded in every society, and in recent years have achieved great importance in developed economies because of the stimulus that their services have given to trade. However, it has become increasingly important, too, that borrowers should not be exploited unknowingly. In Britain the Consumer Credit Act, 1974 requires that borrowers should know the true rate of interest being <head>charged</head>, and, where an agreement is signed away from trade premises, the person is entitled to change his mind. There are also conditions preventing consumers from being unfairly penalised, if they get into arrears. The Act affects all transactions between 50 -- 15000. 10. Another protection for consumers in their dealings with commercial organizations is provided by the Unfair Contract Terms Act, 1977, which protects individuals against possible loss of rights from exclusion clauses and disclaimer notices on posters, tickets etc. Under the Act a
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="109">
<answer instance="109" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Obviously, when a post can not be filled by a British executive because it requires a more cosmopolitan background a client would turn to headhunters with a strong overseas network; and there was a general feeling that in these cases long-established major international search firms were preferable. Such consultancies were seen as being prestigious in the eyes of candidates, having a wider field from which to chose, an extensive research resource immediately to hand, and the largest data banks. The smaller, specialised firms, on the other hand, offered more personal contact and service; <head>charged</head> lower fees; and, because they had fewer clients than the large consultancies, had access to a wider range of candidates because fewer executives were off-limits. The consultant whom the client first met to discuss the assignment would be the same consultant who would undertake the work. It was widely felt that smaller firms offered a better service for nationally-based positions. Specialised assignments were often given to smaller firms offering particular expertise in that sector, with generally good results. The balance of usage between the two types of
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="110">
<answer instance="110" senseid="0"/>
<context>
the total volume of other types of new credit extended and outstanding mortgage debt is far greater than the total of all other forms of consumer credit put together. # TV rental is strictly speaking a form of credit, and is now the dominant way of getting television sets. But the ways in which we have been asked to look at consumer credit use are hardly relevant to TV rental. The great majority of consumers get their fuel on credit, in that they pay monthly or quarterly in arrears, though of course the cost of this credit is not <head>charged</head> separately to them as interest. The amount of credit outstanding for fuel is now approaching 1,000 million; that is to say, for every 1 that consumers owe for other purchases they owe perhaps 10p for fuel. This was the subject of a full NCC report to the Secretary of State for Prices and Consumer Protection 1976 (Paying for Fuel. NCC/ HMSO, 1976). Rather than discuss it again in this report, we shall briefly recall the main points of those of its conclusions relating specifically to
</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
