<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="0"/>
<context>
he validity of observational data on the police. However, an increasing awareness of this omission has led some specialists in the area of ethnographic work on the police to address systematically the problems they encountered in the field (Punch 1989; van Maanen 1988). In the case of the RUC it is essential to reflect on the problems that arose in the research. We believe that results can only be properly evaluated if the problems connected with the study are made manifest rather than concealed. We do not wish to <head>commit</head> the mistake that Woolgar believes is widespread in social science: namely, of suggesting that the only knowledge which is not subject to the influence of contingent historical, cultural, and social processes is that which we ourselves have written (Woolgar 1988b). This reflexivity, what Woolgar more accurately calls benign introspection (p. 22), is thus a virtue rather than a limitation because it provides some of the necessary contextual background to help evaluate the study. We will look first at problems arising during the field-work

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="1"/>
<context>
act like a gouger by being rough-looking and dirty or disrespectful to and disliking the police,' giving lip' and swearing, coming from' a problem family'and being of low intelligence (' not all there',' air getting in',' not right',' a few bricks short of a full load'). In short, gougers are life's losers. Because the typification is very inclusive, covering known criminals and people who look as if they might be, it gets its meaning partly from practical experience of people who typically <head>commit</head> crime in Easton, but also from prejudices that derive from middleclass notions of respectability. Local knowledge is therefore one important influence on the application of the typification. For example, on one occasion a youth was caught urinating in the street late at might, and was very respectful and deferential when caught in the act, but, upon the policeman recalling that he had recently been one of a group which had shouted abuse at him, an act expected from gougers, he was arrested, and the incident

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="2"/>
<context>
proof of fault, at least at the level of subjective recklessness? Further offences of endangerment may be found in the Firearms Act 1968. Section 16 contains an offence of possessing a firearm with intent to endanger life, which corresponds to the offence under section 3 of the Explosives Act. Again, the circumstances of the possession are likely to raise an inference of intent, unless the possession was clearly connected with some authorised shooting activity. There are then three possession offences of a slightly different type. Section 18 penalizes the possession of a firearm with intent to <head>commit</head> a crime or to resist arrest: this is a more specific variation of section 16, catering for the defence that the firearm was being carried for use in a robbery but with no intention that it would actually be used to endanger anyone, only to frighten -- that would be a section 18 offence. Section 19 penalises possession of a loaded firearm in a public place, presumably in circumstances where the section 16 offence can not be proved, but on the argument that the mere possession is sufficiently dangerou

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="3"/>
<context>
attempted rapist intends to have sexual intercourse but is merely reckless as to the woman's non-consent. The strong argument in favour of classifying such offences as attempted rape rather than merely indecent assault has now been recognized by the Law Commission's draft Criminal Code, and the Court of Appeal has recently found its way to this conclusion by' interpreting' the Criminal Attempts Act 1981. # (c) Indecent Assault # In English law the offence of indecent assault is charged for all forms of sexual assault other than rape, buggery, and attempts to <head>commit</head> those crimes. Until 1985 the maximum penalty for indecent assault on a female was two years' imprisonment, compared with ten years for indecent assault on a male -- a legacy of the horror with which homosexuality was viewed, and of the undervaluing of female sexual and physical autonomy -- but the maximum penalty for both forms of indecent assault is now ten years. This is a far more realistic maximum for cases involving forced oral sex and other indignities, but the real question is whether such serious forms of

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="1"/>
<context>
both religious and non-religious people, to appreciate the metaphorical nature of the language they are using. The term " father " was never intended to be taken literally. The question of whether God is male or female is supremely bad theology. It is like saying that if Jim Bloggs is an ass it means he has got long ears and brays. In our society we would normally not interpret a phrase like that wrongly, because everyday usage confirms that when we say someone is an ass we mean they have been rather stupid. But in theology we <head>commit</head> enormous howlers. The point of the metaphor of father is to indicate the experience which religious people have of God as a loving creator. It has nothing whatever to do with gender. Of course this does not mean that we should not be careful about the metaphors which we use. It is possible that if a metaphor ceases to mean what it used to mean in another society then we should abandon it. This is often seen with regard to metaphors like shepherd for example. Work with pupils can

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="2"/>
<context>
we have therefore to turn to Schedule 1. The most relevant paragraph of Schedule 1 is paragraph 7(1), which provides:' In the case of a fugitive criminal accused of an extradition crime, if the foreign warrant authorising the arrest of such criminal is duly authenticated, and such evidence is produced as (subject to the provisions of this Schedule) would, according to the law of England and Wales, justify the commital for trial of the prisoner if the crime of which he is accused had been committed in England or Wales, the metropolitan magistrate shall <head>commit</head> him to prison, but otherwise shall order him to be discharged. The applicable law, if a person is accused of committing a crime in this country, is to be found in section 6(1) of the Magistrates' Courts Act 1980, which provides that:' if a magistrates' court inquiring into an offence as examining justices is of opinion, on consideration of the evidence and of any statement of the accused, that there is sufficient evidence to put the accused on trial by jury for any indictable

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="4"/>
<context>
by Erzsebet Schmuck, president of the National Conservationist Federation and Gyorgy Droppa, of the Danube Circle. Schmuck said existing political parties were failing to make the environment a priority and that economic and environmental restructuring can be combined. East-West Environment, June 1993 # Environmental Politics # Hungarian Greens verge on anti-semitism The Secretary of the Hungarian Green Party, Tibor Elekes, has issued a statement describing " Neo-Zionism " as the world's greatest environmental threat. Elekes claimed that the party was not against Jews as such, but " the neo-Zionists, the international criminals, who <head>commit</head> their crimes taking cover behind the Jews ". In common with much of eastern Europe, Hungary has witnessed a growing number of anti-Semitic attacks in recent years. Hungarian Radio, 13 July (BBC Summary of World Broadcasts) # Environmental Politics # US judge questions legality of free trade agreement The US Justice Department has lodged an appeal against a ruling by a federal judge that the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) violates federal environmental law. NAFTA has been strongly criticized by environmentalists on the grounds that

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="5"/>
<context>
Is he aware that among women serving life sentences in Bullwood Hall women's prison for murdering their husbands there are several whose lack of command of English meant that they were not aware that there was anywhere that they could run to, that some women who had tried to run away from extreme brutality were dragged back by their families, and that some were terrified of leaving their children with a brutal partner, and that therefore they had to wait until they could do something about it and were driven to <head>commit</head> murder? Technically, they did not qualify for the defence of provocation, but their cases are heart-rending and should evoke a change in attitude towards the type of defence that women in those circumstances can claim. Mr. Baker My hon. Friend has been to see me about this matter with a group of colleagues. I am sure that she will appreciate that I can not comment on individual cases, particularly those among the ones that she has mentioned that might come before me. I understand the concern that has

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="6"/>
<context>
They say he expects people to shoot the other chap in the back, if they possibly can.'' Sticks in the craw, a bit, that,' Peacock said.' One can't help sort of including the other chap in the general area of fire,' Blunt said,' but I don't see the need to go out of one's way to <head>commit</head> murder. Do you?'' No, no.'' Of course not.'' The way I look at it,' Blunt said,' the chap can't stay up if his plane won't fly. And it seems to me that everyone overlooks a very vulnerable spot. Next time we meet a Hun, I know what I shall have a pot at.'' What's that?' Callaghan asked.' The propeller. One bullet in the right place,

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="7"/>
<context>
Toyota Sera, BMW-3-series Judges Ken Greenley, course leader, Vehicle Design, Royal College of Art, London; Carl Olsen, transportation design chair, Center for Creative Studies, Detroit; Peter Robinson, European editor, Autocar ; Motor, David Vivian, associate editor, Autocar ; Motor The sponsor PATRICK MOTORS GROUP Patrick Motors' interest in car design goes back to the' 30s when the company designed and built its own' Patrick Specials'. Today the group concentrates on retailing quality cars through its network of Midlands outlets # The worst sin you can <head>commit</head> when designing a small car, according to Renault's design director, Patrick Le Quement, is to make it boring. It's an assertion that needs no lengthy qualification when you look at the Twingo, Renault's hugely characterful and versatile Clio alternative. Renault's new front-drive, 1.2-litre, one-box baby looks confident in a way that small cars seldom do; it's cute without being jokey, radical without being controversial. The nub of the Twingo, of course, is that it's small only

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="0"/>
<context>
run by the author, who is a local education authority (LEA) special education adviser. He reports on the feedback from the members of the course: Teachers seem to appreciate an attempt to be positive about the Education Reform Act. So much of what has been written is of the doom and gloom variety. (Bailey 1989: 82) His stance is as much an attempt to influence the outcomes as it is a prediction of the likely consequences of the Act. If teachers believe that the National Curriculum can widen curriculum opportunities for all, and <head>commit</head> themselves to this cause, then it may turn out to be so. Much of the writing that followed the Act has borne this' make the best of it' message, alongside attempts to muster the collective will to the task ahead: Before resigning ourselves to permanent depression and a feeling that special needs have slipped from the political agenda, it may be useful to look again at some of the implications for change for the better... We have to be optimistic but we must also accept that the

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="3"/>
<context>
itself an equitable one, talk of strict estoppel was inappropriate, and he was content to put forward the alleged assurance and other matters to be considered in the exercise of my discretion. I agree with him. On receiving the planning permission in February 1983 Mr. Cooper, to whom I have already referred, was concerned by condition 2. In a letter to the chief executive of the plaintiff dated 14 March 1983 he wrote:' However, we are extremely concerned about condition 2. I am sure that your council will understand that the company can not <head>commit</head> itself to the long term investment programme, or expose itself to the commercial risks involved in the project, unless the facilities can be planned in a climate of security. This is so necessary for port facilities and absolutely vital if we are to attract the long term users necessary for the prosperity and long term employment prospects of the port. The company can not proceed without the position being established beyond doubt. Can your council assure my company that when carrying out the proposed review under condition 2, it

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="8"/>
<context>
most powerfully moulded the values and beliefs on which society is based, just as in a Muslim country for example the religion to be handed on would be Islam. This approach recognizes the seriousness of failing to induct pupils into the heritage of a great tradition. The recent debate concerning the role of RE in the new legislation of 1988 has shown how powerful this attitude towards religion still is among politicians, the church and the public at large. Many fear the collapse of a society which is not undergirded by religious principles to which the young are trained to <head>commit</head> themselves. The dogmatic attempt to hand on religious faith through education is very much alive within religions other than Christianity also. Indeed the presence of a significant number of people of other faiths in our society has given fresh courage to many Christians to try to reassert the " confessional " approach to RE. If for example Muslims want to bring up their children within their own faith, perhaps in Muslim schools, surely it is time -- so the argument runs -- to reverse the anti-confessional trend and teach Christianity

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="9"/>
<context>
manager who can understand each issue clearly can develop a repertoire of managerial qualities. # Self-development # A typical school policy statement about staff development will include definitions such as " it is essential that we continue to grow in professional stature and experience, backed by the support of a comprehensive programme of in-service opportunities designed to help all of us to meet the growing demands with confidence, a sense of purpose and, as can be the case, an increased personal job satisfaction " (Hewton 1988:88). The progress made towards that increase allows " individual staff to <head>commit</head> themselves to their own professional development and makes it possible for management to accept responsibility for implementation " (Hewton 1988:89). Implementation includes establishing a structure and a sharing of responsibility between the head, other senior members of staff and individual teachers who carry out the tasks involved in identifying staff development needs, with formulating a programme and with evaluating its implementation. In this last stage self evaluation is included and in a commentary on the White Paper on teaching quality (DES 1983a), John Elliott's characterization

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="10"/>
<context>
contains covenants by the buyer (to observe restrictions or to erect a fence, or on a joint purchase) the document vesting the property in him, her or them will require execution. In that case have it signed before sending it to the seller's conveyancer, otherwise you'll be required to give your undertaking to have it executed after completion, and to supply a copy of the execution to the seller's conveyancer. Even when there are no covenants by a buyer, if the purchase is in joint names execution by the buyers is necessary to <head>commit</head> them to the terms on which they hold the property as set out in the transfer. When your client is buying leasehold property on the creation of the lease (as with a new flat or maisonette) and is also the original lessee, the counterpart will of course always require your client's execution; so will the mortgage if your client's borrowing part of the purchase monies. Lastly, there's space for listing any undertakings that require signature by your client. When the buyer calls to sign

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="10"/>
<context>
on title. (c) Undertakings When giving an undertaking, remember that unless you make the contrary very clear you will be personally responsible for carrying out its terms if your client fails to do so -- see the pronouncements of the Law Society published in the Law Society's Gazette at various times over the years. This isn't to say that you ought not to give such personal undertakings; on the contrary, unless you have reason to distrust your client, you should be prepared to take this very small risk to facilitate completion. But don't <head>commit</head> yourself unwittingly to any liability exceeding a few pounds. And see the warning in Chapter 11 (Mortgages) p135 on undertakings to discharge mortgages. Most building societies refuse to execute a discharge of their mortgage until they have actually received the redemption monies; ie after completion has taken place. In such a case when you act for a building society-mortgagee, therefore, you will hand over an undertaking to the buyer's conveyancer, undertaking forthwith to redeem the mortgage and to send the redeemed mortgage or (as

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="10"/>
<context>
and the new husband. This latter conveyance (for which there is a suitable precedent which can be adapted from Kelly's Draftsman, 15th edn, p655) will require stamp duty of 50p and the production of the original conveyance to the wife. (b) Contract Where the arrangement is agreed between the parties, the practitioner must consider whether or not it is desirable to have a binding contract. If the husband is purchasing a house for himself with the proceeds of sale of his interest in the matrimonial home, then, as he will have to <head>commit</head> himself to a contract in respect of his purchase, it is suggested that there should be a contract relating to the sale of his interest in the matrimonial home so that he is fully safeguarded. This should ensure an adherence to a timetable which otherwise might be lacking in the case of an agreement between the parties not supported by a binding contract. (c) Conduct of the conveyancing It is appropriate for the husband's solicitors to obtain the title deeds so that they may act as vendor's solicitors

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="4"/>
<context>
probably ensure that US carbon emissions would not be any higher in 2000 than in 1990 see report in Global Warming section. New Scientist 9 May International Herald Tribune 30 April Guardian 28 April # UNCED # UNCED facing failure, environmentalists allege Environmental groups have warned that the forthcoming UNCED summit faces failure, with differences between North and South more clearly defined than ever. A statement issued by over 100 groups and alliances, including the Brazilian Forum of Non-Governmental Organizations, the Pan-African Movement, Friends of the Earth and Greenpeace, is critical of the North's failure to <head>commit</head> itself to concrete moves on fair trade, debt reduction, poverty alleviation and technology transfer. It also denounces the US failure to act on greenhouse gas emissions. UNCED's Secretary-General, Maurice Strong, has acknowledged that there will be " serious failures " at the summit, and added, in an oblique reference to the US, that " some countries are not going nearly as far as they could ". Financial Times 2 April Guardian 3 April # UNCED # Prince Charles calls for third world aid,

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="4"/>
<context>
International satellite programme to monitor changes The space agencies of the United States, Russia, Europe, Japan, China and Brazil have agreed to a joint programme which will use both existing and new satellites to monitor changes in the global environment. One of the main aims of the programme will be to collect information over the next 15 years to measure the impact of global warming. Initially, the temperatures of sea surfaces and the circulation of heat through the oceans will be measured. Guardian 1 May # Global Warming # China fails to <head>commit</head> itself to carbon cuts The Chinese government has refused to agree to binding targets for cuts in carbon emissions, but is prepared to co-operate " in principle " with international efforts to combat the greenhouse effect. Its position was outlined by Prime Minister Li Peng during talks with Germany's visiting Environment Minister, Klaus Tpfer. Its present priority was to double the country's economic power over the next decade. The government has, however, announced plans to introduce energy efficiency measures to reduce the amount of coal used

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="4"/>
<context>
expect to double their spending on cutting pollution over the next decade. A poll of 173 of the world's largest companies led to the conclusion that environmental expenditure would rise from 2.1 per cent of sales revenue to 3.3 per cent by the year 2000. The figures were announced at an ICC conference on industry and the environment held in Rotterdam. Its chairman, Helmut Sihler, said that environmental concerns would add tens of billions of dollars to industry's costs. Over 200 companies have signed the ICC's Business Charter for Sustainable Development, which urges industry to <head>commit</head> itself to the development of products which require the minimum amount of energy and natural resources to produce, and which can be recycled or disposed of safely after use. Among those supporting the Charter are ICI, Du Pont, Ford, General Motors, Volvo, Volkswagen and Shell. The ICC is to work with the UN Environment Programme on exploring means of assessing companies' compliance with the Charter's aims., The Chemical Industries Association in the UK has predicted that environmental spending by its member companies will

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="4"/>
<context>
not feel it had the necessary expertise or information to produce warnings on " nuclear winter " effects, ozone depletion and acid rain. Scientific opinion was divided over the consequences of the war, and some environmentalists were felt to have overstated its negative effects. " We've got to protect our reputation and we have to make sure that we know what we're talking about " said Weir. Independent 21 August # Global Warming # Major criticises US over global warming stance The British Prime Minister, John Major, has spoken out against the US's refusal to <head>commit</head> itself to a declaration concerning targets and schedules aimed at controlling emissions of greenhouse gasses. Although nearly all the industrialised nations have set themselves targets for stabilising or reducing carbon dioxide emissions, the US, by far the biggest emitter, has consistently refused. Washington continues to challenge the scientific claim that global warming is in part caused by emissions of carbon dioxide. According to Major: " The threat of global warming is real (and includes) the spread of deserts, changed weather patterns, perhaps more flooding

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="4"/>
<context>
United Distillers' portfolio of leading brand names and broad geographical spread has enabled the company to make further progress in a difficult year. Turnover increased by 6 per cent to 2,583 million, with trading profits up 3 per cent to 769 million. Investment in brand building, marketing, distribution and productivity improvement has again been increased. The all important contribution of our people has been underpinned by a continuing focus on development and training. This is supported by a commitment to developing a culture which enables people working at all levels of the business to understand and <head>commit</head> to a central mission, and to share common values and principles. During 1992 in the Asia/Pacific region, the slowdown in the Japanese economy has naturally had an effect upon business. Johnnie Walker has however continued to demonstrate its resilience. Over the last five years, sales of both Black and Red Label in Japan have effectively quadrupled. Elsewhere in the Asia/Pacific region, depressed economic conditions have in the main continued, notably in Australasia. United Distillers has however maintained or grown market share in a number of

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="6"/>
<context>
Many readers of the first edition of The Birmingham Magazine have asked for more information about current courses ran by the University. It is impossible to list here the hundreds of post-graduate, professional, and continuing studies courses that might be of interest to alumni. The following list is just a sample of new courses and schemes, many of which illustrate the way that the University is developing new ideas to meet the needs of people who want further training but who are not in a position to <head>commit</head> themselves to full-time study. If you would like to know more about these or other courses run by the University, please write in the first instance to the Editor at the address on page 3. # Diploma in Social Learning Theory. # This part-time course, run jointly by the School of Psychology and Glenthorne Youth Treatment Centre, Birmingham, provides training for practitioners in the use of behaviour therapy. # Part-time courses in teacher training. # From September 1990 the School of Education will offer two-year part-time PGCE

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="4"/>
<context>
two awards since it was televised last autumn. It has won the Silver Nymph Award at the International Television Festival in Monte Carlo and the Royal Television Society's Award for' Best Drama Serial' of 1989. Meanwhile, David Lodge's first stage play' The Writing Game' had a three-week run at the Birmingham Rep earlier this summer. A Birmingham graduate, Professor Lodge taught in the English Department until 1987, when he retired to become a full-time writer. # HIGH-TECH FIBRE UNITES THE CAMPUS # Birmingham is one of the first universities in Europe to <head>commit</head> to the provision of a high speed data communications network using fibre technology. The 3m budget has been agreed for the project and the first phase of the programme, costing approximately 500,000, is due to be completed soon. This work has involved the laying of a' spine' of fibre cable across the campus -- to which ultimately all faculty and school computer networks will connect -- and the installation of satellite networks in all the Schools of the Engineering Faculty together with the provision of hardware bridges to allow

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="9"/>
<context>
The problem we in Europe face is that Japanese companies have been active in scaling up production for some years, whereas in Europe the emphasis has been on high-quality research, which has only been significantly exploited in the area of basic liquid crystal materials. One of the major recommendations of the report was that future emphasis should be based on not just large scale production, but also on building an effective infrastructure for display-related technologies such as filters, polarisers, glass production and inspection equipment. Of course none of this will happen if European electronics companies do not <head>commit</head> themselves to the manufacture and use of flat panel displays. It's a vicious circle from which the only escape is to bring all parties together with some common framework such as Eureka with the prospect of Government support in order to reduce the very real financial risks involved.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="3"/>
<context>
You can generally borrow up to 90% of the value of the new home, and you can borrow as much as three times you salary: the loan will usually be for a maximum of 25 years. The choice is between a repayment mortgage which is a straightforward loan, an endowment mortgage which includes life assurance, and a pension mortgage. # BRIDGING LOAN # You may have to <head>commit</head> yourself to buying a new home before you have sold your existing one, in which case you may need to take out a bridging loan to tide you over until you sell. These are generally expensive so you would only usually take out such a loan if you already know how long the delay will last. # HOW TO GET A LOAN # This is quite simple. If you already have an account, you can talk to one of the staff in your branch or see the manager.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="6"/>
<context>
The awakening of the Church in Asia needs to be sustained. It needs to maintain the dialogue between the culture of the Church and the culture of the people. It needs to understand more deeply the issues that confront the peoples of Asia. It needs to rediscover the latent power of the media in preaching the Good News of justice, freedom and peace. As Christian communicators in Asia we place ourselves at the service of those challenges, well aware that we need to conscientise people as much as we need to be conscientised. We <head>commit</head> ourselves to maximise the potential of communication in the task of nation-building and the Church's mission. How we are to rise to the challenge is articulated in our plan of action, which follows: # 1. # We intend to undertake a process of study that will lead us towards new paradigms of mission and service and of communicating the Gospel in an inter-religious context. # 2. # We intend to persuade the Church to engage in policy studies with the aim of developing people-oriented policies for the communication task

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="1"/>
<context>
core units get to grips with them, or you can attempt to draw enemy missile troops into an exchange to divert fire from the core units as they advance. Once the core units are engaged you can pile in alongside them or form them up beside the core units to block enemy attacks from the sides. In this supporting role your Orc units don't need to be so large and there is less need to provide standards or characters. Goblins are a different story altogether. Some players find Goblins hard to use because they imagine they are fighters and <head>commit</head> them to combat as if they were Orcs. This is very rarely successful. Goblins are primarily support troops -- their role is to ensure that your core troops get into combat against their chosen target. The different sorts of Goblins can do this in different ways but the objective is the same: either attack an enemy unit and bog it down in a protracted combat, or stand in the way of an enemy unit to prevent it attacking your core units. In either case you will need to gear

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="5"/>
<context>
They are also capable of making high quality picture transfers because of their advanced circuitry and mechanical design. If you are considering the purchase of an automatic controller as a part of your editing set-up, check first that it is compatible with both your video machines, by test if possible, before you <head>commit</head> to buying. The process of shot assembly is strictly a sequential one: each shot has to be copied and edited to length one by one in the correct order. If you reach the end of an assembly and then wish to change your mind about one of the edits, you will have to repeat, not only that edit, but all the others from that point onwards.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="11"/>
<context>
card to both of us', but he couldn't tell her.' Early in marriage a re-ordering of priorities is necessary, and some couples can run into trouble if their commitment to, or dependence upon, healthy robust parents can not be allowed to take second place to their commitment to their new partner. But it is unwise to assume that parents will inevitably pose a problem when they are placed first. Some marriages are based on a tacit, if not explicit, agreement that parents have prior claims. Some people marry into families rather than <head>commit</head> themselves to a partner. Later in marriage a particularly keen sense of commitment may be felt towards aged or ailing parents. Obviously there is less conflict if the commitment is shared by both partners, but it can become a source of tension and disagreement. Parents are not the only people to be relegated when couples are establishing a joint identity. We have already referred to those who find it difficult to give up' playing the field' and continue to behave as if they are still single. Ordinary

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="9"/>
<context>
The Faculty of Humanities has five Departments: English, Media and Theatre Studies; European Studies and Modern Languages; History; Music; and Philosophy and Politics. Through these Departments the Faculty offers an unusually wide range of courses and options. A special feature is the principle of delayed and informed choice by which students gain a broad foundation in the study of the humanities and do not have to <head>commit</head> themselves to their degree programme until the end of the first year. This allows each student, with the help of their Adviser of Studies, to develop the programme of study best suited to their individual aptitudes, interests and objectives. The essence of the humanities is the study of how we have interpreted the world about us, how we have expressed our understanding through language, literature, philosophy and the arts, and how differing views of human life and various forms of society have shaped our history.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="4"/>
<context>
of the people visited do not receive financial help from the Society -- their poverty takes other forms, e.g, bereavement, loneliness, hospitalisation, being housebound, -- the list is endless. Frederick Ozanam died in 1853, at the age of 40 years. Members and friends of the Society continually pray for his beatification, that he will become a saint for the Society, a saint for the POOR! # Hospital Visitation # MOTHERWELL DIOCESE # Motherwell Diocese has SVDP conferences in 72 parishes with 604 men and 156 ladies totalling 960 members and increasing. Members <head>commit</head> themselves to a weekly meeting and visitations. The weekly meeting is held in a spirit of fraternity, simplicity and Christian joy. Our conferences form into 8 Groups which meet 4 times per year, praying together, planning and exchanging ideas. The Presidents of the Groups are members of the Diocesan Council which meets every 2 months. The Diocesan Presidents are members of the National Council. The SVDP have both Junior and Youth Conferences. # DIOCESAN SPECIAL WORKS # Motherwell Diocesan SVDP have furniture projects in Wishaw and

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="11"/>
<context>
for the church choir. (Choirs have always thrived best in well-rooted provincial communities.) Today's mobility, the five-day week, the range of leisure pursuits, sport and predictable weather all militate against recruitment, especially of the young. Nevertheless, in America considerable use is made of junior choirs in addition to those consisting of adults. One response to a difficult situation, which is not without its merits, is the growth of ad hoc choirs and groups, singing on special occasions. These may consist of able musicians who are unwilling or unable to <head>commit</head> themselves on a regular basis. Another response is the formation of music groups which sometimes include all who want to play or sing in them, regardless of their ability. Because they are heavily dependent upon the quality of their leadership special music groups tend to come and go. # Encouragement, Training and Employment of Church Musicians # On the whole, correspondents did not believe that church musicians receive as much encouragement as they deserve. There may be grounds for dissatisfaction with some church musicians, but many have

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="8"/>
<context>
We share the same liberating visions and commitments as our biblical foremothers. We are not called to' empathize' or to' identify'with their struggles and hopes but to continue our struggle in solidarity with them. Their memory and remembrance -- rediscovered and kept alive in historical reconstruction and actualized in ritual celebration -- encourage us in historical solidarity with them to <head>commit</head> ourselves to the continuing struggle against patriarchy in society and church. It should be noted that what we are said to share with them is their vision: there is one continuing struggle against patriarchy. Biblical interpretation is to be done' for biblical communities today

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="8"/>
<context>
The irresponsibility of this helped me to escape the force of the problems, but at the same time I was constantly troubled by suspicion. I had entered fully into the shared joys of Christian experience, but I had never quite gained the satisfaction that other Christians seemed to have. I was on the inside of Christian faith, yet in my mind I was also on the outside looking in. I was not prepared to <head>commit</head> myself completely in every situation, as I found myself as the actor and the spectator at the same time. At times, in fact, there was a sense of hollowness about much of my faith. This came home to me when I was travelling alone in the Far East for some months. I knew almost no one, and because of the language barrier I could speak freely with few people.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="6"/>
<context>
I would love another child but I have to be aware of the possibility that I'm not going to be able to have one of my own,' she said.' That's why adoption appeals. What I'd like is to adopt a multi-racial child. In fact, I'd love a whole bunch.' Although in Britain to launch a new retrospective of her astonishing recording career, Greatest Hits 1965-1992, Cher is looking firmly to the future. She said:' I just want to make sure that, when I <head>commit</head> to it, I have enough time. A child takes an awful lot of work, and I'd want to make sure I was through the bulk of my career stuff.' I'm not quite at that point yet, so it's something I'm projecting for maybe three or four years ahead.' Maternal instincts are nothing new to Cher. Daughter Chastity, from her marriage to former singing partner Sonny Bono, is now 23, while son Elijah, from a second trip down the

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="4"/>
<context>
The script was handed to him by Casper Wrede, a director friend from the Royal Exchange who directed him on screen in One Day in the Life of Ivan Denisovich.' I had done Moliere's The Misanthrope with him and The Hypochondriac, which is much more difficult and not such a good play. I really struggled with that one,' says Courtenay. Plans had to be put on hold when the Royal National Theatre decided to stage The Miser in London but the actor was keen enough on the project to <head>commit</head> himself to the project months ahead and risk turning down more lucrative work. What annoys him is people who say Moliere is not funny:' I don't read reviews although I understand we have done extremely well, but a couple thought it has to be very serious.' It's absurd and it's profound about parents, children, human selfishness and obviously greed. But he was a genius and it's one of his best plays and most pertinent today. Everyone understands about money.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Could the bank have been more long sighted? Given the problems, only a drastic reduction in overheads could have stopped the haemorrhage, but a massive capital investment would also have been essential. Is a bank justified in taking the risk that the future dealing style of a firm may show a winning streak? ANY serious backer of an art business must be prepared to <head>commit</head> long-term support and understand that morale is as important as money. There must be belief in the quality of the business. A dealer can not sustain the approach which recommends selling in a hurry when the monthly figures look bleak. This demands faith on the backer's part, and restraint on the dealer's. Most good dealers are compulsive buyers, and it takes a sympathetic backer to control without stifling flair. So the issue must be faced: has the backer faith in survival after recession

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="4"/>
<context>
He refused to elaborate, but is known to have expressed dismay at a proposed increase in prize money for doubles which would give singles only a 70-30 advantage. It probably did not help Lendl's mood that the net posts were adorned, in large letters, with the words' ATP Tour'. He has been asked to <head>commit</head> himself to 10 of the new Grand Prix tournaments next year, aside from the four Grand Slam events.' Ten, including the Grand Slams, would have been fine for me,' he said. The apparent indifference seems to have spread to Lendl's attitude to the remainder of this year.'

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="12"/>
<context>
The Canadian frequently came to the net, so Petchey had to rely on his passing shots, but not enough of them found the mark. Pat Cash is to request a wild card entry for Wimbledon, but it is open to question whether it will be granted. Though Cash is a former champion, he is no longer willing to <head>commit</head> himself full-time to the game. Next month he will commute from his home in Fulham to a club in Hamburg, where he will prepare for the grass-court season by playing on clay for a club in the Second Division of the German League. David Lloyd, the former Davis Cup player, and his son Scott, 16, reached the semi-finals of the Remington Family Tournament with a 6-3, 6-2 win over Peter and Michael Ratcliffe at Brentwood yesterday, writes Bill Edwards.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="11"/>
<context>
The manager may be the only member of the team who is present in the office full time to fill these gaps and the responsibility of ensuring continuity for clients may make a manager reluctant to take on a large team of very part-time volunteers. # Increasing the Demand on Volunteers # Until recently, volunteers in the CAB were required to <head>commit</head> themselves to four hours' voluntary service per week. This was usually in the form of one day or two half-day sessions. It will be mentioned in several contexts that the complexity of CAB advice work over the last few years has increased considerably. Statistically this is often expressed as an increase in casework or in the number of' repeat' clients whose problem entails a second or third visit to the bureau to bring it to a satisfactory conclusion. 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="6"/>
<context>
I mean, you've been indulged for too long. You need taming.' Alyssia blushed. He was right, of course, but his remark made her sound so young. She doubted that he would ever have had reason to suggest that to Nicole. She seemed a woman with her head very levelly screwed on.' What would you suggest?' she asked lightly.' A diet of discipline and early nights?'' I would suggest that you think a bit more carefully before you decide to <head>commit</head> yourself to another long-term relationship.' His statement pulled her back down to earth. Why did she let herself feel so safe with him, when to him she was nothing more than a hot-tempered child with a woman's body?' Yes,' she replied tersely,' I'll make sure that I draw up a balance sheet next time. Pros on one side and cons on the other.' He shrugged.' That could work. I think there's a lot to be said

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="8"/>
<context>
spots during both morning and afternoon, where you concentrate on relaxing muscles, slowing your breathing down and calming your mind. Take time out to assess the cause of your' hurry sickness' and' hostility'. Is it due to a need to feel important? Is it designed to avoid some activity or person? Is this hostility the result of feeling threatened and insecure about the present situation? Make a deliberate effort to develop enjoyable leisure activities and hobbies. Look back on the activities you have enjoyed in the past and select one to develop. <head>commit</head> yourself fully to participate in such activities. Don't allow all your energy to be channelled into work. Try not to bottle up emotions. Ventilate your feelings. Talk to others about your problems and about how you feel. Allow yourself opportunities to express anger, frustration, and sadness. A problem shared is a problem halved. # INCREASE YOUR SOCIAL SUPPORT NETWORK # There is substantial evidence that social support, at work or at home, may provide an effective insulator or buffer against the effects of

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="6"/>
<context>
At first I gave her oral sex while she was sitting in an armchair and then we had full sex with a condom. What I really want is to meet someone who I can have a bit of fun with, but who is in it for the pleasure and doesn't want paying. After so many years of being on my own I really don't want to settle down and <head>commit</head> myself to a relationship. I have a feeling that most women want more than just a casual affair. At the same time I enjoy the excitement of prostitutes, the sense of anticipation and the variety. I feel a lot more at ease since I've been using prostitutes. I'm surprised at my abilities and how easily it has come to me.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="11"/>
<context>
watched helplessly as their children, their bodies overheating uncontrollably, suffer a painful and harrowing shocking death. As the victim's temperature rises higher and higher, they suffer internal heatstroke and all their organs gradually fail. # Severe Sixteen people have died within the last two years.But for every death there are at least 100 other people who suffer severe mental disturbances. There can be a lifetime of after-effects. Relatives have to cope with mental illness that so often changes the personality of their loved one. Some parents have even had the anguish of having to <head>commit</head> a child to a mental hospital for its own safety. Users claim Ecstasy gives them a buzz and an energy high. The only instant adverse side effect is a desperate thirst, stiff aching muscles and a loss of appetite. But after the high comes the low. The sweating, the agitation, and incoherence. One million youngsters are estimated to take the 10-15 a time pills. They are sold, along with other drugs like LSD by pushers who prey on raves -- such as the weekend event

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Application to adduce fresh evidence to excuse contempt -- Whether fresh evidence admissible -- Criminal Appeal Act 1968 (c. 19), s. 23 In an action for breach of an agreement embodied in a Tomlin order the plaintiff was granted an injunction against the defendants restraining them from' selling disposing or otherwise dealing with seeking to sell dispose or deal with' property of which they owned the freehold. Thereafter the defendants executed a charge on their property in favour of the second defendants. The plaintiff served on the defendants notice of motion making application to the county court to <head>commit</head> them to prison for the alleged contempt of court entailed by breach of the injunction. The defendants did not appear before the judge on the hearing of the motion and no adequate explanation was given for their absence by the solicitor then acting for them. The judge found them to be in contempt and committed each to prison for a term of four months. # On the defendants' appeal and application for leave to adduce fresh evidence: -- # Held, (1) granting the application, that (

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="2"/>
<context>
before the court at which he was to have surrendered to custody. In reckoning for the purposes of this subsection any period of 24 hours, no account shall be taken of Christmas Day, Good Friday or any Sunday. (5) A justice of the peace before whom a person is brought under subsection (4) above may... if of the opinion that that person -- (a) is not likely to surrender to custody, or (b) has broken or is likely to break any condition of his bail, remand him in custody or <head>commit</head> him to custody, as the case may require, or alternatively, grant him bail subject to the same or to different conditions, but if not of that opinion shall grant him bail subject to the same conditions (if any) as were originally imposed. Section 7, both in subsections (4) and (5), refers to' a justice of the peace;' consequently, the procedure under section 7(5) must come within the closing words of section 121(1) of the Act of 1980,

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="6"/>
<context>
GREECE'S three-month-old government will resign today, opening the way for fresh elections, probably on 5 November. When the right-wing New Democracy party and the Communist-dominated coalition of the left agreed after inconclusive elections in June to support a temporary administration headed by the conservative backbencher, Tzannis Tzannetakis, its mission was strictly defined: to clean up the scandals that unseated Andreas Papandreou and his socialist (Pasok) government; and' to restore the prestige and normal functioning of democratic institutions'. After the summer's inquiries, MPs decided to <head>commit</head> Mr Papandreou and a handful of ex-colleagues for trial on charges of ordering telephone tapping and accepting bribes. This momentous decision -- it is the first time a former Greek prime minister has been indicted by parliament -- was complemented by measures the left coalition in particular regards as vital to prevent abuse of power by single-party governments in future.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="11"/>
<context>
This is bankruptcy as applied to companies. Finally, if enforcement is not working because no assets can be found, you can arrange for your debtor to attend court for an oral examination as to his financial situation. This is done under oath and may reveal the whereabouts of previously secreted assets. Any lying by the debtor during the examination constitutes perjury, which is a serious and punishable offence. If your debtor does not attend court as ordered the judge will repeat the order. If he fails to attend a second time the judge has power to <head>commit</head> him to prison for contempt of court. This applies not only to individuals but to companies where the directors can be examined and to partnerships where the partners can be examined. Oral examinations are intended to be a cross examination of the severest kind and your debtor will be required to bring his books, papers and documents into court with him. Although such examinations can be carried out by a court officer it is usually best to do it yourself and, indeed, some courts will even insist on this

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="13"/>
<context>
the experiences will be more powerful if they relate directly to children's current theories, and offer them the opportunity to test them and consider alternative accounts. # (5) CREATING AN APPROPRIATE CLASSROOM CLIMATE # The techniques for eliciting and extending children's ideas which I have described will not be entirely successful unless the teacher adopts a role which is supportive and non-threatening. Children are often reluctant to express their ideas for fear of being wrong. The climate in the classroom must be one where children feel that their ideas are valued so that they are willing to <head>commit</head> themselves in public. We have found that creating this climate involves a number of factors. Teachers need to take children's ideas seriously, and avoid making them feel that they have to search for the right answer, hidden somewhere in the teacher's head. Open questions might start with phrases such as: What do you think...? Can you explain why you think that...? Can you tell me about...? This does not mean that children are led to believe they are always right.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="14"/>
<context>
mostly advisory. By contrast the nursing officer and administrator were the managerial heads of large numbers of staff. But although nurses had acquired heightened managerial opportunities they were ill-equipped by tradition or training to take advantage of them and often simply managerially incompetent (Strong and Robinson 1990), an ineffective counterweight to the medical members. The co-option of general practitioners and consultants into management was largely on their own terms. Most used their power of veto to protect their members' interests and those who wanted to take a more corporate approach to district policy-making had no power to <head>commit</head> their colleagues. Acute medicine retained its traditional dominance and the DHSS almost openly acknowledged its inability to make central objectives stick when it watered down its projected growth rates for the priority services in The Way Forward, produced in 1977. The 1982 reorganisation tried to simplify some of the worst complexities of 1974 by pruning the consultative machinery, abolishing the area tiers, simplifying the planning machinery and advocating greater devolution of decision-making to units of management at the level of hospitals and community services. But it did nothing to

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="5"/>
<context>
better appreciation of air movement, and the way in which wind is a resultant from changes in barometric pressure. So, in summary, we're looking for a clear site, exposed to wind, preferably on rising ground or on beach dunes where there are no buildings to break up the breeze. # The launch # Now we're ready for that first flight. No matter whether the kite is a simple Diamond in polythene, or a commercial Flare in ripstop nylon, it pays to check that the bridle is set at a reasonable angle before we <head>commit</head> the kite to the air. Using a fishing snap-link on the end of the flying line, hook it onto the bridle (commercial kites should come with a ring on the bridle) and suspend the kite upside down. Take note of the angle at which the kite hangs. It must be with the tail hanging lower than the nose. The angle can be anywhere between 10 and 25 degrees at this stage, and only a flight test will show whatever change is needed. The tail need not

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="7"/>
<context>
As we prayed for him it was clear that the Holy Spirit was touching him powerfully, and he began to speak in tongues for the first time. He was not only healed but wholly overcome with joy as well. Such stories abound and are important in that often the first thing that needs to be broken in us is pride, fear of men and the need to be in control. Instead we need to learn to <head>commit</head> our minds to God and listen to his voice and then speak in obedience to him. In my brief experience, to do so is well worth the risk involved! # Consistent love # Sometimes, far less risk is involved: a prophecy will simply be an expression of God's love for the congregation. The following is recorded by Bruce Yocum in his thorough book, Prophecy: Yes my people, my beloved children, come into my presence, be with me today. 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The figures speak for themselves,' said the Minister. # Call of equality # THE Opportunity 2000 campaign, which aims to promote the cause of women in the workforce, was launched in Belfast today by Lady Elspeth Howe. Lady Howe, chairman of the nationwide campaign and wife of the former foreign secretary Sir Geoffrey Howe, called on local employers to <head>commit</head> themselves to equal opportunities. She was speaking at the launch of Opportunity 2000 at the Ulster Bank's offices in Donegall Place. The bank's parent company, National Westminster, is a strong supporter of the scheme in Great Britain and the Ulster Bank is one of the first firms to sign up in the province.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="6"/>
<context>
It showed that the junior had driven a long pin right through the patient's brain. Luckily there's a lot of brain that you don't really need, and he was comparatively OK. IT'S quite common to let people die in extreme cases. The whole thing is done by sleight of hand and happens perhaps one night in ten nationwide. If I were the patient I would hope someone would have the common sense not to operate on me. But it's a dangerous thing to come out and <head>commit</head> yourself to publicly. It's a grey area. Death often happens almost by default. You are a junior, it's the middle of the night, and you're exhausted. How reliable are the decisions you make? I remember one case late at night when someone had a cardiac arrest. The staff started leaping up and down on him.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="1"/>
<context>
had prevented any clear view that an attempt to seize General Noreiga would succeed. As the details of the US involvement are revealed, the administration is coming under fire from normally dovish Democrats on Capitol Hill for not acting swiftly and decisively enough to take advantage of the opportunity to end General Noriega's rule. In their defence, administration officials reply that if they had used more force -- for example, to block a third road used by Noriega's reinforcements -there would have been an unacceptable risk to American troops and Panamanian civilians.' You do not <head>commit</head> American lives on somebody else's time frame, somebody else's plan and somebody else's schedule,' said Mr Baker. But he said that does not mean the administration has ruled out the use of force in future efforts to oust the general. As far as the administration is concerned, the debate over what to do next is governed to a large extent by what the American people say they are prepared to sacrifice to force General Noriega to retire or return to the United States to answer drug

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="4"/>
<context>
A move to a single currency that was not backed by convergence between the two economies of the member states of the Community would be a recipe for economic disaster. That is not in the interests of this country, or of our partners in Europe. This country is in the first rank of the European Community and will remain so. But I am not prepared to <head>commit</head> our country to a single currency. We must be able to judge nearer the time -- Parliament must judge nearer the time -- whether a single currency is in the interests of Britain. We should not achieve what is best for Britain or the Community by giving up now our right to independent judgment then.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="1"/>
<context>
I don't think your problem is whether or not this man is the right one or not. Rather, your problem is one of why you find it difficult to make a commitment to the relationship. I suspect that however right you feel someone is, you are always going to have this problem. commitment is based on trust. We <head>commit</head> ourselves to the surgeon when we go into hospital for an operation; we commit ourselves to the hairdresser, to the dentist and so on... These are comparatively easy commitments to make because we can rely upon on both reputation and upon recommendation. But personal relationships are different. So often, what has happened to us in the past determines whether or not we find it easy to trust both ourselves and others emotionally as adults. Could this apply to you? If so, all I would say is 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="5"/>
<context>
wings and fly into the forest. Flutter here and there amongst the trees, sensing the life all around you -- the plants, birds, animals and insects. Feel yourself as a part of this living forest. And now fly up above the forest, and take on a human form. Look down on the trees, lakes and mountains far below as you soar through the air.... When you are ready, fly towards a mountain peak, and land. Stand on top of this mountain, and shout out to the world below:' I <head>commit</head> myself to my own growth.'' I trust my inner wisdom and guidance.'' I am breaking free from the past.'' I am opening myself to new possibilities.' (Or whatever feels appropriate and right for you.) Then gently come back to the room. # Take one cosmic egg # Once you understand the symbolic nature of physical reality, then you will no longer feel entrapped by it. You have formed the symbols and therefore you can change them.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="6"/>
<context>
It amazed her that she'd ever believed herself in love with him, that she'd deluded herself into seeing his arrogance and his egotism as positive qualities. That she should have wasted time crying over him was not just amazing, it was incredible. And that she couldn't stop thinking about him now was infuriating, never mind that the thoughts were angry ones and not the sloppy, sentimental stuff that had made her weep the first few nights after she'd left Rome. She'd finally realised that what she needed was to <head>commit</head> mind, body and soul into something challenging and exciting. She grimaced as she took another swig of Coke. It seemed absolutely logical that that' something' should be her new career, but the schools had a different idea.' Sorry, but we're booked,' said the admissions officer at one.' Classes have already started,' said the clerk at the other. And then, one Saturday, as she walked listlessly through a Matisse exhibition at the Museum of Modern Art,

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="6"/>
<context>
Although Mrs Thatcher's majority was not quite large enough to avoid a second ballot, the victory was clearly a decisive one.' He concluded that' a mandate is a mandate and that she will derive real strength from having overcome so tough a challenge', a stirring endorsement, weakened only by Thatcher's withdrawal from the contest at about the time the column reached the chattering classes' breakfast tables. I concluded my own column of that week as follows:' After sneering at Lord Mogg, I suppose I should <head>commit</head> myself to a conclusion of my own from the last ten days' dramas. Here it is: Neil Kinnock will never win an outright parliamentary majority as leader of the Labour Party. And I'm not going to pretend I haven't said this. If he does become prime minister (with the aforementioned majority), I will eat one copy of the edition of the New Statesman in which you are reading this article.' I can't claim to have been entirely candid about my promise after

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="11"/>
<context>
projects and donors in individual countries is a source of confusion for which donors themselves are almost entirely responsible. Even the World Bank regularly despatches different missions to an individual country unaware of each others' presence, or who may meet by accident in a permanent secretary's outer office. The consequences for the country, especially in the many cases where the recipient government is not able to sort out the resultant confusion, can at worst be disastrous. There is, for example, the problem of matching finance in local currency, which governments are generally required to <head>commit</head> to each donor-assisted project. In effect governments take on a commitment to support a part of the costs of several hundred projects at any one time, such' counterpart funding' in countries like Kenya or Tanzania frequently amounts to a nominal commitment of about $200 million per year. In reality it becomes almost impossible to find this amount in the budget, and projects have to limp along on an underfunded basis or with the overseas donor financing an increasing proportion of the total costs. commitments to matching finance are

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="4"/>
<context>
rather than abdication of this responsibility to others -- will safeguard against having those air lines become the casualty of a bottom line result in a distant board room in London, Atlanta or Paris. Civil aviation is a major industry with an economic impact on the employment market of at least 21 million jobs, and which is the core of a world travel tourism activity representing 5.5 per cent of the gross national product of the entire world. Despite the current returns on capital invested in a so-called deregulated environment are such as to ensure that no sensible investor will <head>commit</head> further of his resources to the industry. Therefore to suggest that an undertaking of this enormity with its potential to contribute to various national and word; d development activities should be allowed to become the vehicle for economic experimentation or the advancement of narrow short term profit motivation without proper examination of the alternatives, is clearly a path which we will tread at our peril. # LETTERS # British Rail privatisation # Sir, I read with great interest your leader on rail privatisation

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="15"/>
<context>
to be made to Pearson's 1992 profits, which have been affected by several disappointments, predominantly among the non-publishing divisions. In addition, the conglomerate label that Pearson proudly wears does not at present find particular favour with institutional investors. By contrast, Reed's image of a group devoted to publishing/information is appealing. There is also the practical point that an investor wishing to share in the fortunes of say, the oil service industry is better off buying Schlumberger straight than Pearson, which is seen to have all that publishing clutter. And a fund wishing to <head>commit</head> money to the international media industry has in Reed/Elsevier an obvious candidate for such an investment. Pearson would not get through the screening process. # Overseas publishing # The overseas publishers proved a mixed bag in terms of their performance between 28th June 1991 and 30th September 1992. The Bookish Portfolio, having just missed buying News Corporation at its low of under A$4.00 early in 1991, achieved an unenviable record in terms of consistency by failing to participate in the 232% advance of that share during the period under review

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="4"/>
<context>
such as a customer's VAT number and a two character country code.' OUP distribution director Neil Killip said the new VAT regime had complicated an already difficult situation.' OUP has spent considerably more than 100,000 adapting its computer system to cope with the new requirements. Our major problem was that the authorities were late in finalising the small print. We knew that VAT was going to be an issue, but because everything was so vague we found it impossible to draw up detailed plans in advance, which meant that at the last minute we had to <head>commit</head> unbudgeted and unplanned resources to enable us to be ready for January.' A recent survey conducted by the accountancy firm Arthur Anderson showed that four out of 10 companies in the Community were unprepared for the new VAT regime. The survey said that fewer than 40% of companies had collected the VAT numbers from fewer than half of their customers. Rob Newmarch, projects director of Vista, was not surprised by the findings.' Some countries have not even got the new legislation on the statute books.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="4"/>
<context>
by the burgeoning cost of the programme. Mr Baker had said that industrial sponsors would pay' all or a substantial part' of the capital costs. The lack of sponsors has meant the taxpayer has had to foot more of the bill. The Department of Education and Science said yesterday that the Government had spent 19.7m on CTCs and there was a further planned expenditure over the next three years of 106.2m. So far industry had contributed 44m. Sir Cyril Taylor, the Government's adviser on CTCs, who had earlier been successful in persuading Mr Baker to <head>commit</head> more government funds to the 20 schools, had been hoping to get more money for a new round of schools. But sources have confirmed that this has been ruled out by the Treasury in the current round of public expenditure talks. But yesterday, Susan Fey, of the CTC Trust, said,' We were only ever given a target of 20. We have never been to Treasury to ask for funds for more than 20. Of course there have been discussions between the Trust and civil servants

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="15"/>
<context>
I believe that GPs, whether fund holders or not, recognise, like everyone else in the NHS, that Labour's plans to turn all the reforms upside down and to throw away all the gains that have been made in the past three years are the last thing that the service needs. The hon. Gentleman can <head>commit</head> no more money. All he can commit himself to is undoing everything that has been achieved in the past three years. # London Health Services # Mr. Jim Marshall To ask the Secretary of State for Health what assessment he has made of the adequacy of the internal market as the mechanism to determine the future pattern of health services in London.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="9"/>
<context>
Is not that a disgrace? Will the Minister confirm or deny that his Department is now threatening local authorities that plan new builds, by saying that it will take away discretionary housing grants? Sir George Young I can deny that. No departmental official of mine has told a local authority not to build new. In one case -- I think it was in Warwickshire -- a local authority, on reflection, revised its bid and decided to develop its relationship with housing associations rather than <head>commit</head> its allocation to its own project. I notice that the housing investment programme allocations to the city of Durham rose from 1.8 million in 1988-89 to nearly 3 million in the current year. On top of that, 358,000 was allocated to housing associations. I urge the local authority in Durham to develop a relationship with housing associations so that it can make faster progress in meeting the problems to which the hon. Gentleman referred. Mr. David Nicholson In answer to an earlier question the Under-Secretary of State mentioned the vast

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="4"/>
<context>
The UK has extensive geothermal resources and its research into this form of renewable energy is the most advanced in the world. According to an assessment by the department's Energy Technology Support Unit the cost of electricity from this source could be anything between 12 and 60 pence per kilowatt-hour. This would make it between 4 and 15 times as expensive as power from either coal-fired power stations or the new breed of combined-cycle gas turbine plants. To date, Britain has spent over 40 million on geothermal R  Over the next three years the government plans to <head>commit</head> just 3.3 million on this field and to redirect British research towards collaboration with other European countries. An international consortium involving RTZ Consultants and French and German companies is being formed. For the first two years, the consortium will undertake a feasibility study into the best location for a geothermal demonstration project. Since 1977 the main focus of British R  into geothermal energy has been its so-called hot dry rocks project (HDR), based at a disused granite mine in Cornwall. Drilling and circulation experiments have been

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="4"/>
<context>
the lift generated depends on the ratio of two flow patterns (created by the cylinder's rotation and the wind acting on the cylinder) a sudden increase in wind speed while the rotors turn at a constant speed reduces the lift in proportion. This compensatory effect produces a steady power curve. # Buckau is converted # Some arguments could be answered unequivocally only by operating a rotor ship. They concerned principally profitability and factors such as optimal vessel size. In spite of all the work done by Ludwig Prandtl and his colleagues, it was a daring step to <head>commit</head> the resources of the mighty Germania yards, in early 1924, to install two metal cylinders more than 12 m tall on the elegant schooner Buckau, so soon after the idea had ignited Flettner's imagination in 1921. The outer shells of the Buckau rotors sat on pivots that came to about two-thirds of their height. They had a diameter of nearly 2.7 m and were topped by discs a little more than 3.6 m across to prevent the pressure gradient spilling over the top. Two electric motors below deck

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="14"/>
<context>
However, the departmental system of budgeting contains no mechanism to identify those individual parts, nor any mechanism to bring them together to give a total for orthopaedic surgery. This limitation is crucial, of course, to our ability to plan expenditure in health care terms. # 2 # Doctors -- in discharging their clinical duties -- make decisions which <head>commit</head> resources for which they are not the budget holders. Thus, when a doctor asks for an X-ray or path lab test, or prescribes drugs, or decides that a patient should remain in hospital for a further two days, he is making a financial as well as a clinical decision. However, he is not presumed to be financially accountable for such decisions.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="14"/>
<context>
That, of course, is crucial. However, there are many other changes within the White Paper which clearly do impact on the financial structure and the need for better financial information and management. Indeed paragraph 1.17 of the White Paper lists five important aims of the changes proposed, four of which are financial: # 1 # To improve the information available to local managers, enabling them in turn to make their budgeting and monitoring more accurate, sensitive and timely. # 2 # To ensure that hospital consultants -- whose decisions effectively <head>commit</head> sums of money -- are involved in the management of hospitals; are given responsibility for the use of resources; and are encouraged to use those resources more effectively. # 3 # To contract out more functions which do not have to be undertaken by health authority staff and which could be provided more cost effectively by the private sector.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="4"/>
<context>
One of the members of the campaign, Richard McCance, stood as an openly gay candidate for Labour, winning with a 13 per cent swing a seat which the Tories had held for forty years. The strength of the local campaign was an important factor in the council's decision to <head>commit</head> funding to this area of work. A number of Scottish councils adopted the kind of policies proposed by the 1981 STUC resolution, but none of them has set up a unit or appointed specific anti-discrimination workers. Some Scots activists argue that this is more effective in the context of the more collectivist Scottish political culture.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="15"/>
<context>
The idea of the bond is both to demonstrate the financial security of the firm and to provide funds to rescue its clients if it goes out of business. But it can place a large burden on operators and travel agents and any increases in the size of the bond are seen as likely to further the pressures for rationalization in the industry. The problem in this area arises because of the advanced booking process in which customers <head>commit</head> their money or some part of it well in advance of actually taking their holiday and without' seeing' the service offered. In 1986 the fund paid out 1.3 million to customers of fifteen failed holiday firms. A typical travel agent's income is made up of two-thirds from holiday traffic and one-third from business traffic. Approximate sales turnover in 1984 is shown in Table 11.11.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="4"/>
<context>
the reluctance to take account of the new obligations imposed by government to consider the housing needs of the working classes also derived from more political motives. Since their inception in 1888 and 1894 rural councils had remained largely in the hands of landowners and farmers. A rough rule-of-thumb was that landowners controlled the rural county councils and farmers the rural district councils (which were given responsibility for housing). As the principal ratepayers in the locality -- even after the de-rating of agricultural land in 1927 -- they pursued a low rateflow expenditure policy and therefore were extremely reluctant to <head>commit</head> local authority expenditure to the building of houses which could become a burden on the rates. They were particularly reluctant to subsidize council house rents out of the general rate in order to allow farm workers access to local authority housing. Not until 1935, when the government offered rural councils no less than 80 per cent of the cost of construction of houses for agricultural workers, was legislation successful in moving recalcitrant rural authorities. Although the provision of public housing had been established as a principle in rural areas by

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="4"/>
<context>
support grant took account of both variations in need and variations in resources among local authorities. Although the new grant takes account of variations in need, it takes no account of variations in resources, and this will disadvantage inner cities who were the main beneficiaries of resource equalisation. The revenue support grant will be phased in over four years to prevent sharp falls in grant, but this will simply soften the impact. It is difficult to obtain precise figures of private sector investment in the inner cities, but there may be reasons to doubt industry's willingness to <head>commit</head> billions of pounds to inner city developments. So far the response of the private sector has been a very cautious one. In spite of their support of the Conservative Party, the leaders of British industry have made it plain that there are limits to the extent to which they are prepared to sacrifice profitability in giving support to the government's inner city policies. In the short term some sacrifices may be made, but eventually there must be a reasonable return on investments. For the government strategy to work

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="9"/>
<context>
Nevertheless, the move has been generally welcomed by companies in Scotland involved in the European market. In recent months the deepening troubles of Eastern Europe have been pushed to the edge of the world's stage by the Gulf crisis. The transition to democracy and market economies will call for much patience and persistence. If the price of crude oil remains high and volatile then this will impose severe strains on economies which are already under pressure. In these circumstances it is not surprising that businessmen are hesitant to <head>commit</head> resources to forge new relationships in Eastern Europe. Of course, Western Europe is providing financial and technical help and opportunities exist for experienced exporters, but a realistic, long-term view is essential. The Council's business development services continue to prove popular and participation numbers remain high. The growing importance of the Western European markets is reflected in the Council's Euro-drive and this programme has attracted valuable private sector sponsorship.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="4"/>
<context>
ommon shares of Southern New England Telecommunications Corp at a rate of 8.358 shares for each $1,000 in principal, subject to Sprint's right to pay cash equal to a five-day average of the closing price of Southern New England's common shares. # IBM FINANCINGS # International Business Machines Corp and IBM Credit Corp appear to be seeking $4,600m of revolving credit in the international syndicated loan market, Reuter reports from New York; the loans are said to be being arranged by Credit Suisse and syndicated to a group of relationship banks, each of which has been asked to <head>commit</head> around $500m. The deal is said to be divided into two portions, with $3,000m for IBM itself and $1,600m for IBM Credit Corp. # COMPANY RESULTS # Cam Data Systems Inc has reported first quarter net profit down 50% at $100,378, on turnover that rose 27.6% to $2.6m. Net per share fell 58.3% to $0.05. # Datametrics Corp saw fourth quarter net up 74.6% at $475,000 on turnover down 2.5% at $6.1m; net profit for the year was up 98.1% at $1.3m on turnover that rose 6.4% to $22.4m

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="4"/>
<context>
if USL fulfils its promise and introduces a unified version of SVR4.0, System V.4.2 ES/MP, next year. The company said it will' seriously consider' the software when it is available rather than the alternative Unix-based operating system OSF/1, from the Open Software Foundation. SCO, which licenses its Unix code from USL, has been reluctant to name the successor to its version of Unix, SVRV/386 3.2.4, because it says it is unwilling to <head>commit</head> its claimed six million users to a product -- SVR4 -- which is at present available in four different versions. USL currently ships the System SVR4.0 kernel; the desktop System SVR4.2; the security System SVR4.1/ES and the multi-processing version, SVR4/MP. SCO claims to have the equivalent of all four in one version -- SVRV/386 3.2.4. SCO's main objection for licensing OSF/1 is not the technology but OSF's lack of market support. A SCO spokesperson said' we will only license technologies that are widely accepted by

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="1"/>
<context>
at Pleiku in South Vietnam. Johnson immediately approved a plan, code-named Rolling Thunder, which launched bombing raids on North Vietnam. The objectives were to hit the main source of supplies to the Vietcong and to undermine the morale of the North Vietnamese people. But hopes that the bombing would bring the North to the conference table proved totally unfounded; instead, Ho Chi Minh sent detachments of his regular army into the South. Moreover, fears for the safety of US air bases led in the spring of 1965 to the most fateful decision of all: to <head>commit</head> large forces of American ground troops to bolster the South Vietnamese army. Kennedy's earlier warning now proved correct. A process had begun that would be increasingly difficult to reverse. General Westmoreland, the American commander in Vietnam, soon called for further reinforcements, claiming that peace was " just around the corner ". The number of US troops rose to 185 000 by the end of 1965; to 400 000 by the end of 1966; and eventually to over half a million. Meanwhile the full and

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="11"/>
<context>
The fortunes of Levi Strauss have been restored by junk bonds arranged by Salomon Brothers. The jeans maker's bonds are trading above par, even in a badly depressed market. Kroger, a client of Goldman Sachs, has become the country's second-largest grocery chain with the help of junk bonds. Such success stories are being ignored. The institutional investors that charged into junk bonds in the 1980s have now headed off at a gallop in the opposite direction. The market is scarcely functioning. Drexel, which used to <head>commit</head> $3 billion-5 billion of its own funds to market-making, has stopped even quoting prices on 3,000-4,000 junk bonds. Mr Greg Meredith, a bond specialist at Salomon Brothers, notes that only two recent junk-bond issues have been floated successfully: by Goldman Sachs for Kroger, and by Merrill Lynch for Sullivan Graphics. Amnesia has blotted out all memory of the companies that prospered after issuing junk bonds. Only the failures linger. Many of them, like the stores empire assembled by Mr Robert Campeau (owner of Bloomingdale

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Thai saw-mill operators were also turning to loggers in Laos, Cambodia, Indonesia and Malaysia to replace their lost supplies. This was causing concern over a possible acceleration in deforestation in the region as a whole. The Mexican federal government announced on July 15,1989, that it would <head>commit</head> $13,750, 000 to " regenerate " Mexico's rainforest over the following 10 years. The decision followed reports that up to 250,000 hectares (2,500 sq km) of subtropical forest in Mexico's Yucatn peninsula had been destroyed by a series of fires believed to have been started by farmers and ranchers seeking to extend their land holdings. # WWF criticism of Japanese timber imports In a report published on April 13,1989, the World Wide Fund for Nature (WWF) accused Japan as the world's biggest timber importer

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="7"/>
<context>
expensive, wasteful and sometimes of doubtful quality and flavour. Now... there's KIBUN PRAWN STICKS that will meet the growing demand for interesting Seafood products, superb in taste and texture, there really is no substitute! New Kibun Prawn Sticks are extremely versatile. In addition to salads use them as starters with avocados or as dips with your hors d'oeuvres. Serve them hot or cold, you'll be a great success with Kibun Prawn Sticks! # Susanne Hsu tells how she makes the greatest stir-fry in South Ken. # Before you do anything else, <head>commit</head> the following phrase to memory' HOT WOK, COLD OIL'. It's the first thing I learnt about traditional Chinese stir frying and it's the most important clue to the whole principle of the Wok -- things happen fast. Because China was often short of material to fuel ovens, a cuisine sprang up where a strong flame cooked food very quickly. Nowadays, of course, unless you have a raging open fire to hand, the only way to get the same responsiveness is with a gas

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="14"/>
<context>
times when deliveries were made to them.) (2) The information about the prices was not clearly severable from the rest of the sales information. (3) Neither the sales information in general, nor the information about the prices in particular, though of some value to a competitor, could reasonably be regarded as plainly secret or sensitive. (4) The sales information, including the information about prices, was necessarily acquired by the defendants in order that they could do their work. Moreover, as Goulding J had found, each salesman could quickly <head>commit</head> the whole of the sales information relating to his own area to memory. (5) The sales information was generally known among the van drivers who were employees, as well as secretaries, at quite a junior level. This was not a case where the relevant information was restricted to senior management or to a specific category of staff. (6) There was no evidence that the plaintiffs had ever given any express instructions that the sales information or the information about prices was to be treated as confidential

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="4"/>
<context>
and to the lecturer -- especially if he is also the examiner; (4) obtaining familiarity with the types of question which have been consistently set in the past, and making a tentative guess at the likely questions for your examination. # Swot Cards Reference is made in chapter 4 to the value of making good notes but, as the time of the examination approaches, it is good policy to transfer key facts and figures on to swot cards. Under the present examination system, where a good memory is of real assistance, it is necessary to <head>commit</head> these facts to memory, and this is where the swot cards help. They can be carried round in the pocket and referred to frequently -- on the bus, while taking the dog for a walk, while shaving, almost anywhere. Use ordinary white postcards, or 5 in. X 3 in. index cards, and coloured pencils for major and minor points, for grouped facts and memorable principles. Do not hesitate to throw a card away after rewriting it in a better form.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="1"/>
<context>
and vowels and simple digraphs (ch, gh). The second is more advanced; it has beginnings, middles and endings. So, for example, the beginnings include as separate units ch, ph, qu, wh, wr; the middles ai, au, ou, ee; and the endings ck, ff, gh, mb, sh. In addition, the middles (vowels) are on a different coloured card. The pupil builds up the words he wants in a stand, and can test out his ideas without having to <head>commit</head> them to paper yet. The great advantage of the Word-Maker is that the word can be corrected without confusing the speller by crossings out and insertions. Wrong letters are lifted out, and right ones inserted, leaving the corrected word as a unit. Its physical manoeuvrability makes it easy to demonstrate syllable structure or to emphasise tricky bits. Teachers who use Breakthrough find that their pupils become conscious of the construction of words, and tend to play with words in a way which is helpful for their spelling.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="1"/>
<context>
although experience does make it easier. Do not be surprised if you reject as many as 50 per cent of the candidates at this stage. If you are in two minds then give the candidate the benefit of the doubt and allow him or her to come for interview and elaborate on the details given on the form. Although application forms can be very thorough and very revealing there are some questions which can only be asked face to face, and in an interview where a good rapport has been established. For example, people may be understandably reluctant to <head>commit</head> their personal financial details to paper, or discuss the real reasons why they may have left one of their previous jobs. # Using the application form to plan the interview # Application forms (or c.v.s if application forms are not available) should be used as the basis for the candidate's interview. This will be a far easier task if the initial advertisement/job description has been accurate enough to attract people with the right qualifications and experience. These candidates will then have been able to gauge their answers to

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="13"/>
<context>
it simply needs to be expressed and released. Guilt can also be a form of self-punishment -- anger turned against the self, in the absence of self-love and self-forgiveness. All too often, it is also a form of manipulation -- a way of hurting or punishing others, or persuading them to do what we want, in the absence of honesty and integrity. Guilt does nothing but harm. # YOUR GUILT # If you suffer from guilt, write down what you feel guilty or ashamed about. (If you are reluctant to <head>commit</head> yourself to paper, speak to yourself in a mirror.) You do not need to confess to anyone else. just be honest with yourself. What are your shameful secrets? What are the dastardly deeds, thoughts and fantasies which your Negative Ego pokes and taunts you with? Now examine your list. What is the hidden resentment that lies beneath your guilt? Who are you angry with? Who are you trying to manipulate? Is your guilt based upon a belief that you should not have fun

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="7"/>
<context>
after all a residual topic and that once orthodox language has been subtracted all that is left is a rubbish heap of nudges, shrugs, pouts, sighs, winks and glances -- or to put it another way that non-verbal communication is simply the behavioural exhaust thrown out of the rear end of an extremely high-tech linguistic machine. And yet... is it all that easy to subtract language in the first place? Can one really strip away the lexical component leaving behind a non-verbal residue which has nothing to do with communication in words? The fact that one can <head>commit</head> words to paper without any apparent loss of intelligibility suggests that there is, in fact, a clean division between the lexical and the non-verbal component of human communication, and that the so-called kinesic variables such as facial expression, posture, and hand movements are just optional extras. But this conclusion overlooks the fundamental distinction between the meaning of an utterance and the meaning which the utterer wishes to convey by means of that utterance. Because although it could be argued that what an utterance means is readily recoverable by

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="9"/>
<context>
articulated policy which can clearly be applied to a case, development control and appeal decisions tend to abide by it. However, some areas do not have plans; some plans do not cover issues that arise in individual planning applications; and much development control has to rely on unwritten policy and professional skill and judgement. Can the situation be improved? Obviously more written statements of policy would help, and this the authors recommend: for both central and local government. But there is a limit to which governments at any level wish to, or can, <head>commit</head> policies to paper. The more this is done, the more inflexible will planning become, the less will it be able to adapt to changing circumstances, the greater is the likelihood of conflict between policies, and the more confusing the situation will be. The great merit of the British development control system is its flexibility and adaptability to differing and changing situations. # 5 # Chapter 5 PLANNING, LAND AND LAND VALUES # It is clear that under a system of well-conceived planning the resolution of competing claims

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="11"/>
<context>
And the copyist left a blank in one other movement: the instrumental bass line of the song' Ye gentle spirits of the air' -- one of the' new' songs, placed just before the Haymakers' scene. After the first ten bars. he wrote in only a few important imitative leads -- bars 17-18, 25-26, 30-34 and 97-105 -- which suggests that the composer had yet to <head>commit</head> the remainder to paper. The missing passages have been supplied, in a very distinctive greyish ink, by an 18th-century hand. The same writer, using the same mix of ink, also headed several of the vocal numbers with the page numbers on which they appear in the second volume of Orpheus Britannicus, published in 1702. Finally, another of the' new' songs, the famous Plaint,' O let me weep, is not in the manuscript at all

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="12"/>
<context>
It's like drinking, it's like smoking. I don't think it's a pop song that dictates to them. It's what they have in their heads. They hear a song and it's rave, rave, rave.' Someone will say:' Oh, someone told me that they take drugs at that party.' Then another kid will say:' Oh, do they? I'm going to do it, then.'' It's like these people who <head>commit</head> suicide over a song. It's what's passed around, it's not what's said in the music.' # My Twiggy gets better with age # LEGAL EAGLE KINSEY'S VERDICT ON A MODEL WIFE #' At the airport she looked so lovely I caught my breath' # PAULINE WALLIN # SHE was the face of the Swinging Sixties, a pale, waiflike figure who captured the mood of an era. Now, at 43, Twiggy has matured into the breathtaking beauty of the Nineties

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="3"/>
<context>
the right to self-determination is to have any meaning for those who are weak or bedridden (e.g. responding to a request to bring pills), but not all are like this. In McShane (1977) a woman was convicted of an attempt to counsel her mother's suicide by repeatedly encouraging her to take an overdose, and it was shown that the mother's death would greatly alleviate the defendant's financial problems. It is for cases of this kind, where the evidence shows that there was active persuasion rather than compassionate assistance to someone already determined to <head>commit</head> suicide, that a substantial maximum penalty is thought necessary. For this offence and for the proposed suicide-pact offence, the Criminal Law Revision committee (CLRC) recommended a maximum of seven years' imprisonment. This grading of the offences may be seen as a compromise between the compassionate elements in the offences, which are related to the right to self-determination, and the need to protect the vulnerable from persuasion on such a crucial matter as the ending of life, an argument also derived from the right to self-determination

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="8"/>
<context>
Herakleophorbia was eaten in excess it caused illnesses like tumours and cancer in humans. Both creations frightened people. Frankenstein saved a girl from being drowned. When he reanimated this girl on observer shot him because he was terrified of this ugly creature.' The Food of the Gods' became a political issue. Frightened people joined the party against Herakleophorbia and fought against the giants using weapons in an attempt to kill the result of this terrible creation.' Frankenstein' and' The Food of the Gods'have bleak endings. Frankenstein dies and his miserable creation decided to <head>commit</head> suicide because his conscience troubled him.' I shall die and what I now feel will be longer felt. Soon these burning miseries will be extinct. I shall ascend my funeral pile triumpantus and exult in the agony of the torturing flames.' At the end of' The Food of the Gods' the giants are fighting against the little people, for freedom. Neither side will compromise which will result in the deaths of yet more people, unfortunately. A giant says:' Tomorrow whether we

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="8"/>
<context>
how Fazisi had to struggle and how great their achievement was. Fazisi was a different sort of campaign. There were many crew changes therefore lasting friendships did not have time to mature. Skip brought a few friends on the boat when he found the Soviets were not skilled ocean racers (it became most apparent in Alexei's case). The crew may have resented this. Throughout his book Skip conveys no feeling of deep friendship, maybe because men tend not to share their feelings and problems with each other. Possibly this led co-skipper, Alexei Grishenko to <head>commit</head> suicide during the stop over in Uruguay. There were several reasons why disputes happened on Fazisi that were not shared with other yachts in the fleet. They included language difficulties and the ostracization of crew who joined the boat after building work had been completed. The men also tended to have different political views as they came from such a huge and diverse country. Russia contains 20 different races of people all with deep rooted beliefs, values and rivalries between each race. Russia also tends to have no class

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="6"/>
<context>
1968, when I was first in government, we tried to develop a new hybrid of social justice and a market economy. Even at that time we were approaching a liberal social-democratic model on Scandinavian lines. Any of Lenin's theories were unacceptable for us then, while from Marx one could only draw some methodological ways of thinking. In these respects I had many discussions with Guevara, who himself disclosed his loss of marxist illusions. The Cuban intellectuals were saying that after listening to Valtr Komarek for 14 hours he had lost his socialist ideals and went to <head>commit</head> suicide in the Bolivian jungle. So we had already experienced the general loss of illusions in socialism. We could say that having lost these illusions in socialism we have studied economic theories much more thoroughly than Western intellectuals have done. We studied the phenomenology of Heidegger, all Western theorists including Hayek and Milton Friedman and the convergence theses and new visions of Galbraith and Bell. 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="1"/>
<context>
This experience had such a dramatic effect on the Pole that he hanged himself some days later. No further reports have been documented, but possibly people who have seen a replay of the awful scene wish to remain silent not wishing to discuss the macabre subject. In the 1920s a local man was in a terrible state of nerves and he too visited the bridge with the one thought in his mind. Yes, he did <head>commit</head> suicide on that bridge but he drank from a bottle of lysol which would mean a swift but painful end. I wonder if he is seen too? # THE HIGH WYCOMBE FOOTSTEPS # A recent story, quite unexplained, was related to me by Mr G. Leslie who is employed by British Rail in the London area. This story concerns the sounds of footsteps walking in the ballast; no one was seen but the sounds were very convincing and one respects the account of this mystery from Mr Leslie,

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="5"/>
<context>
Investigation failed to produce any reason why such an evil atmosphere should pervade that area. Now the track has gone and a road covers the scene. Many years later, but before the tracks were removed, a tragic event happened on the line. A well-known member of a prominent fishing company whose life had been plagued by tragedy and illness decided to <head>commit</head> suicide. On the particular afternoon he decided to end his life he had been watching the marshalling of the fish vans from his office window. He waited for the right moment, walked calmly across the road, knelt down, put his neck across the railway line and waited for a loaded van to sever his head.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="12"/>
<context>
It is better by far that there should be no others born.' Afterwards Mrs Gracie found a letter in Paul's room, torn in two. It was not her business, she decided, to show it to anyone. Out of loyalty to Mrs Dinah, nobody should ever know why Mr Paul had tried to do away with himself. She took the two halves of the letter away, tore them in fragments, and burned them in her grate. It was, accordingly, never certain why Paul Arkwright had tried to <head>commit</head> suicide; it must, everyone said, have been because he was going mad. # Dinah and her father were discussing his forthcoming production of Macbeth over supper. Dinah was peeling some fruit. She did not let the knife slip from her hand when the door burst open, and Nathan Holland appeared, having thrust his way past the servant. His face was chalk-white.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="4"/>
<context>
He is Chairman and Managing Director of the Gmez Emporium, a big store in the centre of Buenos Aires. When it is burn down he lose everything, so...' He shrugged.' You wrote that he was arrested.'' Yes. The company was in difficulty. This is at the beginning of the Malvinas trouble. It was thought he may have set a match to it himself. For the insurance, you see. But nothing is proved, so he is released. That was about a year before he <head>commit</head> suicide. The insurance people are still fighting the claim in the courts.'' And his other son? What happened to Eduardo? You don't mention him, except to say that he was a biologist and that he went to England to work for two years at the chemical weapons experimental establishment at Porton Down.

</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
