<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Mobbed The girls are just as popular as the guys. Scorpio, a former school high jump champ, gymnast and one time Miss Isle of Man said:' We couldn't believe it. We were mobbed wherever we went. The 5ft 9in <head>model</head> and actress with a 38-23-36 figure said it made a change for women to be seen as tough and strong.' Most of the action you see on TV is reserved for tough guys like Sylvester Stallone.' Women are usually the weak ones who get rescued all the time.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="0"/>
<context>
And' what did my daddy look like?' And' why did he go away and leave me?' All too many women like you are deserted even before their babies' birth. Some are forced into single-parenthood by a man who walks out on his wife or partner, often for a younger <head>model</head> and a quiet life away from nursery squalls. I daresay that as a result of your letter and my few words, I'll have an angry response from men who'll say,' what about the women who abandon their children for other men?' True, there are some of those, but there aren't droves of them.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="0"/>
<context>
THERE are some real gems of bargains to be had in the old jewellery market claim Bonhams, the London auctioneers. For example, a good engagement ring bought at auction will cost you half what a high-street shop would charge. A beautiful diamond necklace which recently fetched 11,000 at Bonhams would be twice the price in an ordinary jewellers. But not all Bonhams' baubles are so expensive -- the entire collection our <head>model</head> is wearing went for 450 the other day. Don't expect to make a speculative fortune with old jewellery, but it is fun to collect and should hold its price, whereas you'll be lucky to get half your money back on anything bought in a shop.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Men find her trim figure and neat little face with its impossibly turned-up nose, very appealing. She seems surprised at this but says:' That's very nice.' And smiles her Cheshire cat grin.' I get a little fan mail. Men have been known to write and ask for a picture of me in a bathing costume.' I cut a picture of a <head>model</head> in a swimsuit out of Vogue and posted it back to one man. He wrote back to thank me for it. He obviously hadn't noticed the difference!' She lets out a surprisingly earthy bellow of laughter.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The 26-year-old man will also be questioned about the murder of teenager Katie Rackliff six weeks earlier. He was being held at a Liverpool police station overnight and will be driven south today for questioning in London. Former <head>model</head> Rachel, 23, was butchered in front of her two-year-old son Alex on Wimbledon Common last month. Like hairdresser Katie, 19, she was stabbed repeatedly and sexually assaulted. Detectives arrested the suspect at his home in Toxteth after a lengthy cat-and-mouse game involving surveillance experts. Officers are planning to raid five addresses in London after applying for search warrants.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="0"/>
<context>
I bet you remember her. Esther Williams was glamorous, she swam like a fish and somehow never got her hair wet. Her underwater extravaganzas were some of the biggest hits of Hollywood's golden age. So whatever happened after she climbed out of the pool? Hugh tells us DOWNS voice-over She dove into our hearts in the 1940's and literally became MGM's " million dollar mermaid. " Esther Williams, champion swimmer and former <head>model</head>, earned between $80 and $90 million for the studio in just 11 years. Her movies were called aqua-musicals and they were sheer spectacle. Esther appeared on 15 magazine covers a year and was one of the top ten money-making stars in 1950.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="0"/>
<context>
He knew her. He trusted her. And that's how they got him there. You don't think that someone he met- Meyer Lansky had the best saying; He never spoke to a guy he hadn't known for 15 years. The woman who the FBI used to set up Marion Barry was a 38-year-old former <head>model</head> named Rasheeda Moore, whom government sources allege had a long-standing intimate relationship with Barry. These sources further allege that Moore and Barry had used drugs together in the past. Moore was installed in a room in the Vista International Hotel on M Street. According to the prosecutors
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="0"/>
<context>
says it's gotten way out of hand. John McKenzie explains why. JOHN MCKENZIE: Donald Trump, it is said, is a man with more than a billion dollars to his name, a man who likes seeing his name on his airline, his office buildings, his casinos. Married to Ivana, a former <head>model</head>, Donald went looking for the limelight and found it. But what happens when after 12 years of marriage this public man walks out on his wife? Headline news. This story has taken New York by storm as the media here scrambled for any scrap of news or gossip about the couple's breakup.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="0"/>
<context>
I wasn't excited about movie people, because the people that had approached me up to then to do films had just been such creeps. I mean they would come on to me. Really, Bogdanovich was the first movie person that I liked. Every <head>model</head> I knew was taking acting lessons, and I'm kind of a stubborn kind of person, I don't know; if everybody else is doing it, I usually don't do it. I think it was because I didn't want the part and I was very blase that I probably got it, it gave me a real position of power.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Her eyes slipped away from his as she spoke. " There's a theory that you met him once, " said Latham. His voice was amused. " Tony Valentino? I don't think so. He looks sort of male bimboesque. I guess I could have seen his head shot if he was a <head>model</head>. Was he ever in England? " Emma shifted in the chair. She knew her face was giving her away. Her cheeks were on fire. She had to brazen it out, but he knew. He knew. Would he let her off the hook? No, he wouldn't. p179 " He was an actor, at the Juilliard. Word is you visited his end-of-term play, A Streetcar Named Desire. He played Stanley. Odd that you don't remember his face. It's rather
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The secretary who entered the room was beautiful and haughty as befitted God's handmaiden. She didn't wait to be invited in. She held a manila envelope. " Mr. Latham asked me to deliver this, " she said. She walked across the room like a <head>model</head> on a catwalk and laid the envelope in front of Emma Guinness. " Thank you, " said Emma with the coldness she reserved for good-looking women of a lower status than herself. She reached for the envelope and eased open the pins that held the flap. She pulled out the handful of prints and leaned forward eagerly to look at them.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="0"/>
<context>
My mother is the envy of all her friends because she's thin. But to me she doesn't look good. She looks too thin. Her collarbones protrude like a clothes hanger. On good days, when she has slept and eaten healthily, she has the angular features of a <head>model</head>, though still perhaps trimmed a little too sharply. On bad days her face is unrelenting in its thinness. On these days it makes me sad just to look at her. What wrinkles, I wonder, were plowed at my birth? " I think I'll do twenty sit-ups every night, " she says. " For a whole week. " Kindled by the doctor's praise and by Jackie's psychosomatic idolatry
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="0"/>
<context>
of clothes and a spoon and the poems of Basho in a sack over my shoulder; and on the walk I met an old man who taught me to fly-fish, who said one morning as we stood in the black cold water of a stream that wound like a dream out of willows, said: I know the woman of whom you speak, and she is dead. Celest would tell me a story about wearing a red dress. A sashay story full of night cries and lust. Then she would speak of her years as an artist's <head>model</head>, of standing on the sagging wooden pedestal in a cold room under a wan northern light, contorting her limber body into the alien shapes the painter David Conn requested. She said, My body would lock. Bent, broken into the shape he wanted me, she said, I would eel it lock and then I would feel sensation begin to leave----it felt like p2 2 small men running down my arms and legs -- and then it would be as if I didn't have a body at all
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="0"/>
<context>
I never dreamed... He reached out to comfort her, but she shrank from him, as if she felt herself too unclean to be touched. " Melinda, my dear, " he said, " sooner or later you'll have to tell me everything, won't you? " She nodded miserably, but kept her eyes averted from him. " She called me up one day, " she said. " I hadn't seen her or Filippo for weeks, not since the wrap party. I'd been working as a <head>model</head> in Milan and I'd been home only a couple of days. " " So you do live permanently in Rome. " " Yes. I have a little apartment just off the Via Veneto, up near the Villa Borghese. You know, the park? " " I know Rome quite well. Go on. " " She presented it as just another job. She told me all about you and how she'd been married to you and all and about how you were in a kind
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Perhaps it is not one of Mr. Griffith's best. He is directing for Famous Players and apparently has to get out so many pictures a year. It is, however, one of Miss Dempster's best and that is of immense importance. She plays a newsgirl who grows up to be a <head>model</head> and subsequently an actress. Also included are the hilarious W. C. Fields and a cyclone. # Mannequin. Some time ago $50,000 was posted by Famous Players for a prize scenario, the same to be serialized in Liberty, and Fannie Hurst came first. This is the picture. It does not seem to be a desperately original invention, dealing as it does with a girl (Dolores Costello) stolen in babyhood
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Cooling The ash cloud has been moving around the earth at 75 mph at an altitude of about 15 miles up in the stratosphere. Because there is little wind that high to split the particles up, it could stay there for years. So the cloud absorbs sunlight, heating the stratosphere up but stopping warmth from reaching the Earth. Now the NASA experts have recorded an average cooling of 0.2C already and their computer <head>model</head> predicts that will increase to 0.5C by the end of the year. And they claim that the knock-on effect is that weather patterns change. They point to statistics which show that six to 18 months after volcanic eruptions, eastern American states and most of North West Europe have lousy summers.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="0"/>
<context>
After the 1990 floods, when farmland was submerged, many sheep were lost and Perth was inundated, the engineers Babtie Shaw and Morton were called in to draw up a preliminary study. There were two main recommendations -- a flood warning scheme should be established, but as important, an in-depth study should be carried out to create a hydraulic <head>model</head> for Perth and look for flood alleviation measures. The first was carried out, the second was not, in spite of warnings from the engineers:' The preliminary study has highlighted the high damage costs associated with flooding on rural and urban communities, and the very real possibility of more extensive and serious flooding of Perth occurring in the future.'
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="0"/>
<context>
This photofit may amount to 1 in 10,000 or 1 in 100,000. At the moment CATCHEM is the baby of Derbyshire police force who bear the cost of its operation. It is hoped that in the future the computerised detective will be used as a <head>model</head> for a national profiling scheme. In January this year the Home Office promised 350,000 to help set up an offender profiling unit which will record not only child murders but serial killings and rapes. It will emulate the FBI's behavioural science unit which describes its work as an odd mixture of detective work and psychology.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Alternatively, rival parties could be given control of different public television stations: so BBC 1 and Channel 4 might become' conservative-right wing' channels while BBC 2 and ITV become' socialist-left wing'channels, which could then compete for an audience. The situation in some European countries approximates that <head>model</head>. In Britain the idea of openly partisan broadcasting was pioneered by the Scottish Nationalists' clandestine and illegal Radio Free Scotland in the 1960s and more recently by Southern Sound, who used a discarded former commercial radio band to set up their entirely open and legal Conference Radio FM to cover the 1990 Conservative Party Conference from an unashamedly pro-Conservative viewpoint.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Military violence had led to civil coercion in many forms, of which the Secret police in peacetime was the most notorious example. It had also led to the adoption of military influences in Bolshevik governmental organization and propaganda jargon which did not disappear at the end of the Civil War. Trotsky's idea of converting whole regiments into Labour Armies had failed, but it was symptomatic of the time. Makarenko revived the military <head>model</head> in microcosm, and his strict pedagogical methods were adopted on a vast scale in the 1930s by Stalin, who reawakened many other lingering aspects of military-inspired government. Often in NEP when thoughtful leaders at many levels became exasperated by the seemingly chaotic situations they saw about them, they dreamt of, and sometimes put through, as in Makarenko's case, schemes which looked forward to the methods of the 1930s.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="0"/>
<context>
It is for this reason that we can treat both imperfect competition and the separation of ownership and management as creating a problem for the legitimacy of corporate managerial power. Thirdly, one of the cardinal features of the market <head>model</head> of legitimation was that economic power was exercised through exchange transactions in the market. Yet as the company grew in size it was plain that much economic activity was being withdrawn from the sphere of the market and being replaced by a hierarchical, bureaucratic organization within the company.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="0"/>
<context>
before directors enter into long-term service agreements with their company, or substantial property transactions with their company, they must disclose the details of these transactions and obtain the consent of the shareholders. What these legislative reforms seem to be suggesting is that all is basically well with the traditional <head>model</head> where the directors of the company manage the company but are supervised in that task by the shareholders who, if given the requisite powers, can be relied upon to ensure that directors do not use their powers for their own purposes.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The charge of political bias laid at the door of critics, and the claim that their own scientific activities were neutral, leaves only one way out -- to make out that the problem lies in technical factors of production that constrain maximum yield performance in maize, and not in the interrelationship between social conditions of inequality and the new technologies which CIMMYT and IRRI were developing. The next section discusses a <head>model</head> of soil conservation which derived from the perceptions and objective political economic conditions of the' colonial period', stretching from about 1880 -- 1960. Since that period has passed, and we can benefit from hindsight and a somewhat altered world view,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="0"/>
<context>
All the same, however, it is at least tempting to think that' why?' here demands a switch of attention from rules to the intentions and motives of the agent. Weber makes the switch by applying a microeconomic <head>model</head> of rational action in order to understand action which is a calculated means to an end. Action occurs within a framework of shared meanings -- rules and collective values -- but is not dictated by that framework. In the style of economists, we are to reconstruct the agents' choices, given their preferences and information sets, assuming that they are rational agents.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Much of the public debate has, indeed, been about contractual (strict) accountability. It is interesting, therefore, that the evidence of the UK accountability projects suggests that teachers operate with a very different <head>model</head>: one that is grounded in concepts of answerability or responsibility. In this context Elliott has pointed out that the association of answerability, responsibility and accountability with specific audiences
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="0"/>
<context>
His emphasis on systematisation, objectivity and the utilisation of indicators by which the achievement of objectives might be measured reveals a conformity to the classic, positivistic or behaviourist tradition. As we pointed out earlier, the kind of <head>model</head> for insider evaluation that Shipman proposes has a long history and there is little evidence that it has been significantly displaced by newer alternatives. Undoubtedly its appeal rests on a simple logic that those inside and outside schools can readily comprehend;
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="0"/>
<context>
he reason why at present independence is thought to be achievable only by involving a different force is that investigations of police operations typically involve suspicion of malpractice. It is natural, therefore, to think that impartiality within the same force is doubtful. By contrast, the <head>model</head> suggested here is not primarily directed to uncover malpractice or breaches of discipline. Its main function will be to ascertain whether the results of the first investigation would appear as firm to another team going over the same ground.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Although technical monopoly may be a rarity, as already noted markets are commonly dominated by a small number of large producers. In such circumstances by colluding or in virtue of the structural properties of oligopolistic markets companies are able to obtain variable degrees of protection from competitive pressures. In addition to the relatively small number of producers, other requirements for perfect competition are also unlikely to be met in practice. Thus, an uncompetitive market structure may be maintained indefinitely because of barriers to entry and exit; products are not, as in the <head>model</head>, homogeneous, but have differentiating characteristics which enable producers to raise prices without causing a total shift in demand to their rivals; and finally, purchasers lack perfect information and hence may pay higher prices than they would if aware of alternative, cheaper, sources of supply. The effect of these various imperfections is to cede to companies a zone of discretion in relation to products and prices and the wide range of factors connected with the production process.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="0"/>
<context>
the Prime Minister has wide access to a network of policy-making cabinet committees, and' deals' can be made in inter-departmental committees, cabinet committees, or between the Prime Minister and individual ministers. Business laid before the full cabinet has often been the subject of previous informal agreement between the Prime Minister and certain colleagues in order that opposition may be outmanoeuvred... In brief, the actual Westminster <head>model</head> is that of authoritarian single-party governments in a House of Commons dominated by the Prime Minister and composed largely of disciplined parties with most votes in the House of Commons being highly predictable; every three or four years there is a general election held under a crude simple majority electoral system with minimal participation by the electorate in the choice of who shall be their candidate, though they do have the choice between the candidates who are selected by the party activists; between 20%,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Second, although there is a clear relationship between school size and management structure there is limited scope for extended curriculum leadership roles, let alone year-group responsibilities, in smaller schools -- the relationship is not inevitable. Some medium-sized schools had shifted to a three-tier <head>model</head>, while some large schools were still operating a rather unsatisfactory and somewhat stressed version of Type 2 or even Type 1. Generally, however, by the end of the period in question, larger schools tended towards Types 4, 5 and 6.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="0"/>
<context>
the Conservatives would have had roughly 285 seats (and not 397), Labour 180 and the Alliance 160, resulting in a hung, three-party, parliament and a scramble to form a coalition. Two-party dominance was at its greatest in the period between 1945 and 1970 when the Conservative and Labour Parties won all but 8 per cent of the vote and 2 per cent of the seats. The <head>model</head> of responsible party government was born of this experience and it tended to elevate the politics of the moment into a law of nature that has distracted attention from the more fluid aspects of Britain's political experience.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="0"/>
<context>
At the beginning of the 1980s a group of community activists, trade unionists, community educators, peace workers and feminists met and agreed that what was needed was a reappraisal of previous efforts in the field, a conscious effort to determine their own social and political position and to choose an educational <head>model</head> or approach which reflected the latter. This group felt that the community movement of the 1970s had been too romantic, too naive, too easily influenced by the popular educational theories and conventional wisdoms of the decade. They applauded the attempt to cross the sectarian divide to stress the problems common to members of the working-class in both communities.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="0"/>
<context>
It has survived from the early 1930s because of its craggy independence, its non-institutional base, its ability to adapt to new social movements thrown up by the working-class and oppressed groups and, most important, its radical philosophy and perspective. With this as a <head>model</head> and financial support from various trusts and charities, the Ulster People's College was established in 1982. It is situated in Belfast and has short-term accommodation for 30 people. This central resource is used to complement and strengthen the work in the field;
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="0"/>
<context>
and general courses which by their nature and structure attract the unemployed. The MSC courses in 1985 included a Pre-Tops' Breakthrough' course, a Business Skills Workshop, New Skills courses, and Adult Preparation Training (funded through the Adult Training Strategy and using a modular approach). Unfortunately, many non-waged people are unable to benefit from these MSC courses since they are only available for those with UB40 cards. The courses are obviously based on a training <head>model</head>, and all colleges running such courses should evaluate longitudinally whether participants do in fact secure subsequent employment or further education and training. It is also important to evaluate other outcomes of these courses. Do they lead to increased self-confidence, and if so
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Bureaucratic power has thus been a reference point for many outside observers of the Soviet Union, in particular, in their attempts to identify the distinctive nature of communist political systems (Lane 1978, Ch. 6). The' bureaucratic politics' <head>model</head> of communist government has four major elements that distinguish public administration under state socialism from its counterpart in the liberal-democratic state: the political dominance of a centralized and bureaucratized party; the absence of party competition
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Contingency theory as a tool of management predicts that organizational performance will be maximized when there is a structure of management appropriate to contingencies deriving from the circumstances of technology, environment, scale and other factors. Contingency theory thus combines elements of technological and social determinism. The concept of technology, which plays a part in determining the appropriate <head>model</head> for the structure of authority in the organization, originally referred to levels of complexity in decision-making and manufacturing processes in industrial firms. But it has been developed by Perrow to apply to the actions which administrators perform on the objects of their decision-making
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="0"/>
<context>
their clients, the political executive, legislative assembly and public are more complex than some economic models of bureaucracy allow, especially in the welfare services. Here the one-to-one relationship between professional and client in such cases as family breakdown, mental illness, physical disability, child care under conditions of deprivation, or homelessness is not easy to fit into the market <head>model</head>. Public administration also often has to satisfy equity criteria in its treatment of individual cases, especially when acting in a quasi judicial role. It is not obvious how this can be guaranteed by bureaus competing for business in quasi-market conditions.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="0"/>
<context>
In contrast to the life histories of timber species, about which little is known, the drivers and impacts of logging in the tropics are well known and operate virtually identically across the globe. Logging in the tropics follows the same economic <head>model</head> as is evident in most of the world's ocean fisheries: The most-valuable species are selectively harvested first, and when they are depleted, the next-most-valuable set is taken, until the forests are mined completely of their timber and the land becomes worth more for agriculture or ranching than for forestry
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The database we used for our analysis did not afford us measures of self-determination such as indicators of self-assessment, self-advocacy, or self-reflection. The database did contain a measure of locus of control, which we included in our <head>model</head>. Locus of control is the degree to which people perceive positive or negative events as being a consequence of their own actions and under personal control. People are judged internally controlled if they believe they exert control over their successes and failures, whereas externally controlled people attribute their performance to outside forces beyond their control
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The tools for Big Data are very different. Many of the fundamental algorithms for predictive analytics depend crucially on keeping the data in main memory with a single CPU to access it. Big Data breaks that condition. The data can't all be in memory at the same time, so it needs to be processed in a distributed fashion. That requires a new programming <head>model</head>. " # This can be hard for traditional data users to understand, He watches students attack Big Data problems by creating a sample, but that defeats the value of Big Data with all its potentially informative outliers. # Businesses are catching on to the promise of Big Data said Luke Lonergan, chief technology officer at Greenplum, an analytics company that was acquired by EMC. # " Every business is looking for ways to get tighter connection with its customers, to improve prediction and and move them along
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="0"/>
<context>
and they need some way to keep that state " fresh " on the client, so that it can be used throughout the interaction. To make OPTIONS work well, you'd be forced to design your own caching <head>model</head> -- silly when HTTP already has one. # Likewise, you can't easily work with OPTIONS in a browser; there isn't a link for the OPTIONS representation, so you need to have a different way to talk about it. This is because it effectively creates a separate, alternate " silent " representation for a resource.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="0"/>
<context>
systematized and repeated. Alongside mass production, according to this approach, went mass consumption, so that the system could be sustained by general state-inspired (Keynesian) economic management, which encouraged a continued growth of demand for the products of the generally centralized industries with their large production units. Post-Fordism, on the other hand, is characterized by the growth of flexible specialization, which implies a more widely variegated and less standardized set of products, as well as the ability to change the nature of those products in response to changes in the market. Such a <head>model</head> also implies a change in the driving force of economic decision-making. Under Fordism mass consumption was a consequence of mass production; whilst with post-Fordism, it is changes in consumption and the identification of specialist markets which are said to determine changes in production. Post-Fordism implies that management, too, has to be decentralized and forms of work discipline changed, because they can no longer be organized through hierarchies in which standardized messages are passed from above and implemented in any very straightforward fashion. Workers are expected to be
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The active participatory method of treatment used to combine once-weekly dressing, compression bandaging and, most importantly, client participation, resulting in joint agreed contracts of care between client and nurse. Orem's model of nursing was chosen to assess how clients could be assisted with universal self-care demands. This <head>model</head> emphasises the individual's contribution to his or her own health. In a state of health, individuals will be self-caring, but during illness, injury or disease, additional self-care needs may be present and the nurse will need to help meet these demands. Considerable savings were made in the surgery during the six months after introducing this treatment.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="0"/>
<context>
MOTORIST Janet Glover put her new 10,000 Toyota Corolla in for its first service -- and got it back with an unwanted extra. A sunroof. Blundering mechanics had got it mixed up with an identical <head>model</head> parked next to it in the workshop. Janet, of Denmead, Hants, said yesterday:' It was lovely and streamlined before -- now it looks awful. The sunroof looks cheap and nasty. The local firm, Hampshire Car Sales, offered a free car alarm and servicing in compensation.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="0"/>
<context>
They have also developed additives which prevent the fuel from frothing so that it no longer spills over your shoes every time you fill-up. And they have agreed a uniform black colour scheme for all garages to prevent mix-ups with petrol, which used to be common in the early days of the diesel revolution. The best-selling small diesel <head>model</head> is currently the Ford Fiesta, followed by the Peugeots 205 and 106, and the Renault Clio. The most popular small family models are the Vauxhall Astra, Citroen ZX and Ford Escort. In the upper-medium sector the big sellers are the Peugeot 405, Vauxhall Cavalier and -- during the first half of this year -- the Citroen BX.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The most popular small family models are the Vauxhall Astra, Citroen ZX and Ford Escort. In the upper-medium sector the big sellers are the Peugeot 405, Vauxhall Cavalier and -- during the first half of this year -- the Citroen BX. A rapidly-increasing number of executive models are diesels too, with the Mercedes 200 and 190, and Vauxhall Carlton being the favourites. Latest tests indicate that Citroen's new Xantia diesel <head>model</head> is actually quieter than a petrol-engined Ford Mondeo. Another common feature of all new diesels is instant starting. Formerly there were glow-plugs which had to be warmed before the engine would fire. The performance of diesels has been transformed by the availability of turbochargers on most models, giving the majority of them cruising capabilities in excess of 100mph. Some now come with the option of automatic transmission, and a small number are even available with air conditioning -- previously the exclusive domain of the ultimate petrol-engined executive express.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="0"/>
<context>
WITHOUT going as far as opponents Ford, Vauxhall has said that airbags will be available as standard or as an option on most of its cars for 1994. Airbags are already standard on every Cavalier and Calibra, while half of the Astra range has one fitted. The same airbag system will be offered as an option from now on in new Corsas. Meanwhile, as part of the <head>model</head> year package of improvements, a new bhp 16-valve 1. litre engine becomes available for the Vauxhall Astra. On the Vauxhall Cavalier range, there's a new 1. litre economy engine, similar to the Corsa's Eco unit, which produces close to miles per gallon at a constant mph. Most of Vauxhall's changes come on the Cavalier and Calibra ranges.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The most glamorous newcomer to the Golf range is the revamped GTi 16-valve with a new bhp engine under the bonnet. Equipment now includes anti-lock brakes with traction control, central locking and an RDS sound system, while prices run from 16, for the three-door. The VW Vento range gets a new entry level <head>model</head>, the Vento L with a 1. litre engine and costing 11,198. Equipment looks good with central locking and power steering included. Also new for is a range-topping automatic version of the Vento VR priced at a competitive 20, -- not bad for a V 2. litre engine.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="0"/>
<context>
In the past Ford has been criticised for lack of security on certain models, but they have certainly got their act together with this time. The Mondeo has a visible identification number, a shielded double locking system, antitheft alarm with starter motor disabling and, audio system security and tailgate/ boot lid immobilising. The <head>model</head> I had on test was the five door two litre Ghia, which is right at the top of the saloon range, selling for 17,450. However, the family starts at 11,200 for the 1.6 four or five door and the two litre Ghia estate costs 18,450. The test care had a top speed of 129 mph and 0 to 60 mph time of just over nine seconds. It consumed 25 mpg around town, 46 mpg at 56 mph and 32 mpg at 75 mph.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The rugged vehicle will be on sale in time for August delivery, and will cost 15,995. Fourtrak The seven seater Defender County Station Wagon is available with both petrol and diesel engines. The two <head>model</head>s cost 16,495 and 15,887. Another new four wheel drive vehicle to be launched before August is the new Daihatsu Fourtrak, although the company is being rather sheepish over details of the machine. However, I do know that it features a new, wider stance and a longer body than the present model along with wider wheel-arches and new wheels and grille. It will be powered by the proven 2.8 litre turbo diesel engine. Oo, la, la! What a guide IF YOU are thinking of a driving holiday in France this year it is well worth being able to parle a little motoring Francaise and the AA, along the National Tyre and Autocare have come up with ways of helping to make yourself understood.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="0"/>
<context>
I HAVE an Amstrad computer 464K and a green screen monitor. It is only 12 months old and I now wish to purchase a modulator to convert it to a colour monitor for use with a domestic TV set. I have been told by computer shops that Amstrad have stopped making this <head>model</head>. It seems a bit unfair to people who can not afford to update their computer every 12 months. Can you find out from Amstrad if there is anywhere I can get one?
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The high fifth gear, which pulls 26.6mph per 1000rpm, provides refined cruising and helps give good fuel economy with 25.9/47.1/37.2mpg in the urban/56 and 75mph cycles. The 10pc more torsionally rigid body has sharpened handling compared with the previous <head>model</head> and allowed sportier suspension settings, including gas pressure shock absorbers, without compromising ride comfort. The new convertible incorporates all the extensive chassis improvements introduced with the launch of the hatch, saloon and estate models.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="0"/>
<context>
There is a sensible dashboard layout too with instruments at or near the fingertips. Only in the back does a problem occur. No argument over the legroom or headroom, but with five adults aboard the middle passenger is forced to perch on a solid hump with neighbours shoulders a touch too close for comfort. Boot space is perfectly adequate quite shallow but long. The <head>model</head> included standard goodies such as electric windows and mirrors all round, power steering, central locking and catalytic convertor. And the test car, which had a full service history, also featured alloy wheels and burglar alarm. Security is spot-on. This is a strongly-built machine throughout and the doors close with a prison-like authority.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="0"/>
<context>
But its fortunes have changed now thanks to the revival in Sixties music and style. Crestworth Trading, the company which originally made the lamp, started work on them again in 1990 and turnover has tripled in a year and a half. A spokeswoman said:' Fashions changed and they went from being very trendy to being very suburban. But this revival has seen business booming.' We have changed the <head>model</head> slightly to fit in with the look of now. But we have kept the Sixties colour and feel while appealing to a younger market.' Astro lamps are sold at Fenwicks, in Newcastle, Objects, in York, Camilion Cards, in Darlington, and It's Anonymous, Middlesbrough
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Radio Rentals is Britain's leading rental specialist. We employ more than 1,500 highly qualified service engineers and have an extensive network of High Street shops. Each of our shops is staffed by a small friendly team of experts. Call in and meet them. They'll be delighted to advise you on how to get the most from your current equipment or suggest a new <head>model</head> you might like to try. If you're confused by the latest hi-tech advances in stereo TV or Satellite Television these are the people to cut through all the irritating jargon. No matter what help or advice you need, call in or phone your local shop.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="0"/>
<context>
MITI organized a leasing corporation to lease only Japanese computers on competitive terms to those available abroad. The industry was protected until the early 1970s by the rule that foreign machines (including IBM machines produced in Japan) could only be purchased if a suitable Japanese <head>model</head> was not available. While Japanese computers were hardly a factor in the boom years, they were to become a major force in the 1980s. It is difficult to draw a neat conclusion. MITI clearly pushed strongly to develop certain key industries.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="0"/>
<context>
In 1984 Tyler was tried and convicted for theft and conspiracy, and served four months behind bars. Refusing to let the matter end there, however, he slapped a $53 million suit on the two neighbors and the county for intercepting and recording his private conversations without a search warrant. If Tyler had been using a conventional telephone, his case would probably < have been solid. Unfortunately for him, the phone was a cordless <head>model</head>. Not only did that allow his neighbors to intercept his communications -- unwittingly at first -- on their own cordless unit, it apparently left him with virtually no legal protection. Citing precedents from other cases, two lower federal courts ruled that it was not necessary to obtain a warrant before surreptitiously listening to cordless phone conversations.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="0"/>
<context>
with his hands over the side he pushed the cart to the nearest security clock, but he could not reach high enough to insert the key. The security inspectors would be summoned on the hour that the clocks had been interrupted or not turned. He was found several hours later. I washed the dishes and then watched a holiday program on our black and white television, a small table <head>model</head> that my mother left behind. She owned the first set on the block, a distinction that raised our stature, but she never watched much television then. The programs ended, even the test pattern was out; he had not called and it was past midnight. I was insecure when there was no answer at the mill.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The Mercedes SL roadster is small, beautiful, precise, and finely crafted. In other words, the very last thing you'd want for an automobile in New York City. The Range Rover is a much better choice. # People have the Range Rover thing all backwards. They think the Range Rover is a country car, and so, for that matter, do its manufacturers. There's even a Range Rover <head>model</head> called the " County. " But, actually, it is the little Mercedes SL that ought to be packed with picnic hampers, motored down rustic byways and parked on the grassy verge of woodland ponds with car keys insouciantly left in the ignition. And the SL's size is an ideal excuse for not taking your children's friends (or even your own children) to the beach house for the weekend. Mercedes has built an exurban vehicle ideal for everything except cleaning out the barn.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="0"/>
<context>
he Federal Trade Commission offers these additional considerations: Call several car-rental companies and get price estimates. Many companies have toll-free numbers, and many companies offer weekly and weekend specials. Decide on what <head>model</head> and size car you want, but remember that each car-rental company may have its own vehicle classification system. The terms " compact, " " mid-size, " and " luxury " sometimes differ among companies: Know that there may be additional fees that could increase an advertised base rate substantially. These costs might include: airport surcharges and drop-off fees; under-age driver fees; out-of-state charges; and equipment rental fees.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Although no longer the technological juggernaut of earlier decades, IBM still has many advantages over its competition. One is its brand-name recognition overseas, especially in Europe. With the introduction of its RS/6000 <head>model</head> this year, IBM finally appears capable of being competitive in work stations-high-powered units used by engineers and other technical workers. That is a crucial step. Sales of work stations and personal computers, which are increasingly linked in office networks, are expected to grow 10% to 15% annually over the next few years. And if IBM's overall earnings grow about 10% a year, its stock could move from a recent $104 a share to $140 within three years
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The AAA wangled the car for $980 below its $15.157 sticker price -- roughly $1,070 over dealer cost. While conceding that a tougher buyer might have been able to negotiate a lower price, Schmoll says: " I'm happy. I avoided all the hassle. " Indeed, that's the main attraction of buying services -- avoiding hassles -- because sometimes your own hard bargaining can get you the car you want for slightly less. # Most buying services work the same way. First you tell the service the exact <head>model</head> and color you want and pay a fee of $150 to $800; local AAA buying services collect their $75-per-car fees directly from dealers. (To use an AAA buying service, you must join the organization. Cost: $18 to $65 a year.) Then the pro typically delivers the car to you at $100 to $1,100 above the invoice price. A low-cost national auto broker called Car/Puter (800-221-4001) operates a bit differently. For $22, the company refers you to the nearest of its 600 affiliated
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Over ten years ago an engineer named Lohmann built an electrical smelting furnace which succeeded in dissolving iron, aluminum, sodium and other metals into new and dif- ferent substances, as well as making diamonds out of wolframite. The latest <head>model</head> of Lohmann's furnace can create a heat of 4,000 degrees centigrade. German scientists are debating what will happen when Miethe's experiment is tried in Lohmann's furnace. # It is obvious to economists and bankers that should a commercially feasible method of manufacturing gold be worked out, it would have far-reaching results. Probably a huge period of inflation would fol- low. Bonds would on paper remain still
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="0"/>
<context>
This Spring the balloon tire and the four-wheel brake were novelties; now they are practically standard equipment. With the present new crop of " latest models, " the chief feature consists in selling eight-cylinder cars in the moderate price field, and selling sixes at or under the existing prices for fours. The last Buick is such a six-cylinder <head>model</head>. What tomorrow's " new feature " will be, no one knows, least of all the manufacturers themselves. 736316 Owing to the successive failures of the cotton crops of the past few years and to the high current price for cotton, this year's crop is being watched with unusual attention. The reports of the Department of Agriculture on the condition of the cotton crops as of June 25
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="0"/>
<context>
This exceptional output clearly affected the figures for total national October car-production. # In November the Ford plants continued active on the balance of their unfilled orders, but many other concerns reduced their production schedules. When Ford has " caught up " with the orders for his new <head>model</head>, a considerable falling off in Ford and in other car-production is expected, as a regular seasonal feature of the business. # The present surplus stock of cars in the hands of dealers is estimated at 500,000, although some students of the industry question the accuracy of this figure. The total number of motor vehicles in use in the U. S. today is more than 15,000,000
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="0"/>
<context>
However, strangely it was never completed in terms of constructing the machine he had designed; it was only half built. He then came up with a second Difference Engine, which was an improvement on the uncompleted first Difference Engine, capable of returning mathematical results up to 31 digits. He never completed building this one either; though he did complete the designs for these machines that have since been proven to work. In 1991, his second <head>model</head> of the Difference Engine was constructed and was demonstrated to work by doing a series of calculations. In 2000, the printer he designed that hooked up to the difference engine was constructed and also shown to work.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="0"/>
<context>
it wasn't blowing the doors off the joint. It's certainly faster, but the 3GS wasn't hurting on speed to our eyes, so it's not as wildly noticeable a leap as the 3G to the 3GS. # As usual, Apple isn't fessing up about the RAM situation, though we have on very good authority that the iPhone 4 has 512MB onboard, a big step up from the 256MB in the previous <head>model</head> and the iPad. We would have liked to see it futureproofed with something like 1GB, but then again, Apple's got to sell a new phone in a year. As far as internal storage goes, you can buy the new iPhone in either 16GB ($199 on contract) or 32GB ($299 on contract) capacity
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="0"/>
<context>
but a promenade will be constructed above road level and people will be able to look over the wave wall.' Sefton's Chief Tourism Officer Phil King is attending a conference in Scarborough and was unavailable for comment. # Rubbish on Southport's seafront and, inset, fun figures which could brighten the area K3D Corsa is recalled after blazes # SOME of Vauxhall's new Corsa cars, featured in an extravagant 3m TV commercial with top <head>model</head> girls, have burst into flames, the company said yesterday. Vauxhall announced on May 28 that all 5,128 of its UK Corsas were being recalled because of an electrical fault. But yesterday the company confirmed that faulty wiring had, in some cases, led to cars burning.' It's a question of some of the wiring not being routed in the correct way and in some cases
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The distribution of responsibilities between local, national, public and voluntary sectors has also become less rather than more clear, which reduces the possibilities of accountability. # Another interpretation of the changes would see them as part of a longer-term shift towards new relationships between government and the wider political economy. # Like Cockburn, Hoggett stresses the links between changes in the organization of local government and those of capitalist management. But the <head>model</head> he develops tends to distort the past in order to exaggerate the extent of change. It remains unclear why the changes he identifies have taken place and what the implications are. # There is some evidence that relationships between local government and business interests have become closer and more institutionalized, and this seems to support an interpretation which identifies a significant shift (or structural change) between the late 1960s and the late 1980s.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Publicis' first work for Super Nintendo breaks this week and runs until early June with a media spend of 1.5m. # FDG, the Hampshire agency, has been appointed by Britax Restmor, maker of baby transport and nursery furniture. # Honda is supporting the ads for its new Civic <head>model</head> with a 750,000 direct marketing campaign through Jane Porter Direct. # Oxfam is to stay with incumbent agency Pearson Paul Haworth Nolan following a fourway pitch. # Public enemy Number one. Haywards: TV burst # MEDIA # ITC threat to C5 over vcr retuning
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="0"/>
<context>
So here is an attempt to try to answer some of those questions by direct substitution or with a small amount of modification. After all, with time, money and patience, but no sense, it would be possible to fit a V12 Jaguar engine into an 80 inch! Rover's policy of utilising parts which were already in production for a different <head>model</head> when building a new vehicle is particularly useful in places where spares are not as readily available. These lists are not exhaustive -- if they were they would fill the entire book -- but work on the principle of: if it looks as if it will fit, then it probably will
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="0"/>
<context>
I doubt if at present you can have it reregistered on an age related basis, but when you write to DVLC ask them at the same time. Certainly, you will not be able to use the vehicle's former military number plate on public roads. I am rebuilding a 1955 Series 1 and would like to know more about it please. The number is 170600671. Your vehicle is a 1955 Series I 86n wheelbase right hand drive home market <head>model</head>. Recently I purchased a Series III SWB petrol from a local salvage dealer. The vehicle had been stolen and recovered and the number plates have been. removed. I wish to apply for the log book to retain the original suffix. The chassis number of the vehicle is 90168943A
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Depending on use 18 to 23 mpg. I run a One Ten V8 and advice on fuel consumption would be appreciated. You mention fitting SD1 carburettors and a Range Rover camshaft. What are the necessary part numbers needed to complete the job in one attempt? The vehicle is a 1989 <head>model</head> with 7,000 miles covered, could you offer a guess at the likely improvement in fuel consumption? SD1 carbs are best sourced from a breaker's yard as they are readily available for about 25 per pair. A small overhaul and clean and they are ready to fit The cam is part number ERC 2003.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="0"/>
<context>
This means that even the best of gyros will always be a little too late to prevent any unwanted movement. Note, too, that once a particular movement has become established, the gyro will try to preserve it. What a gyro does do, however, is to damp out unwanted movements and allow the pilot more time to react. It is worth pointing out that virtually all of the current best <head>model</head> helicopter pilots learned to fly them before the existence of a practical gyrostabiliser. They did it' the hard way' and so can anyone else with sufficient determination. The gyro has made it much easier to learn to fly but, once you overcome the basic hurdle, it merely serves to smooth things out and make your flying tidier
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Here is a beast of impeccable breeding, and with reputation all-important in the used car market, you can't get a much higher image than the BeeEm. It's a proven symbol of success. The test car was a cool looking two litre multivalve <head>model</head> in glacier blue, first registered in October 1990 and supplied by Georgesons of Breck Road, Anfield. # Motorway magic It was a delightful car to drive, purring effortlessly round town, but at its best on the open road. There's no strain on the ears as you heap on the gas. It's swift and easy acceleration-60 in fractionally under 10 seconds and creamy smooth all the way to the red line.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="0"/>
<context>
At first I found the car uncomfortable, but the driver's seat and steering wheel adjustment is so good you soon find a near perfect position. There is a sensible dashboard layout too with instruments at or near the fingertips. Only in the back does a problem occur. No argument over the legroom or headroom, but with five adults aboard the middle passenger is forced to perch on a solid hump with neighbours shoulders a touch too close for comfort. Boot space is perfectly adequate quite shallow but long. The <head>model</head> included standard goodies such as electric windows and mirrors all round, power steering, central locking and catalytic convertor. And the test car, which had a full service history, also featured alloy wheels and burglar alarm. Security is spot-on. This is a strongly-built machine throughout and the doors close with a prison-like authority.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="0"/>
<context>
When is a Porsche not a Porsche? When it isn't fitted with Genuine Porsche Parts. Sadly, this is a fact a lot of drivers seem to forget when they buy replacement parts. But they soon remember. Because non-Porsche parts are often of a lower quality than the real thing. That's why at an Official Porsche Centre, you'll find 3,000 parts that have been specially made to fit the exact <head>model</head> and year of your car. And even if your Centre doesn't have the part you need, if they order it from our National Parts Centre before 3.30pm, provided it's in stock, it will be delivered to any Centre in the mainland by 10.30am the next day. So if you own a Porsche, buy Genuine Porsche Parts. And you won't have to make excuses.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="0"/>
<context>
and the door mirror housing were modified until rain was successfully deflected clear of the side windows. Another ingenious development is BMW's wiper system, fitted to the 530i and 535i. When driving at speed, the engineers noted that headwinds and crosswinds caused the blades to lift off the windscreen. To remedy this, they designed a motor in the driver's wiper pivot that increases pressure on the screen as the car increases its speed. So there is no lift during take off. But there's further evidence of BMW's enlightened attitude towards safety; every <head>model</head> is fitted with ellipsoid headlights. They don't reflect the light in the way that a conventional headlight does. They project it through a special lens. Which means they're 30% brighter and better directed so as not to blind oncoming drivers, while minimising back glare in fog. One more dazzling feature is the anti-dazzle rear view mirror.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="0"/>
<context>
However, the overlap between designs and copyright has been eroded by section 51 of the Copyright, Designs and Patents Act 1988 which states that it is not an infringement of any copyright in a design document or <head>model</head> recording or embodying a design for anything other than an artistic work (or a typeface), to make an article to the design or to copy an article made to the design. In this context, " design " has the same definition as it does
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The revelers went back inside with their glasses of champagne. They complimented the ice peacock and the vegetables that had been carved into the shapes of lilies and birds, and the tall wedding cake with an Indian maiden, a cowboy, and a <head>model</head> of the Eiffel tower that looked more like an oil derrick than the real thing some of the younger men had seen in Paris during the most recent war. Belle was tipsy and laughing. Horse hadn't seen her that way for so many years that he sat back and watched her. Lyle Dilly, Old Sam's brother, wore a stovepipe hat. He made a long, drawn-out speech to Belle.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="0"/>
<context>
"Yes, but guesswork can sometimes help. " They came to the edge of the platform and stopped. This interior world stood mostly at a level about one hundred p177 meters below them. There were other platforms in the distance, and they could see a large number of such structures below them. It looked almost like a cityscape, a scale <head>model</head> on a tabletop, and everything was linked together by a maze of curving cables. The microwave emitter, which had been set on the tallest nearby structure, sharply delineated the staggered blockiness of the scene by throwing long, dense shadows. Here and there cables reached toward the " sky. " There was a sudden change in the texture of the objects they were seeing and Sealock looked back toward Methol and Krzakwa. They were gazing about. He shifted his suit optics from microwave to visible light and
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Mary, Britain's domestic queen, universally beloved for her interest in better housing of the poor, is to receive the most magnificent doll's house ever made as a token of affection from her subjects. Sir Edwin L. Lutyens, designer of the Cenotaph, London's great war memorial, conceived the idea, enlisted the coperation of the greatest artists and artisans in England to carry it out. The house is a miniature <head>model</head> of a completely furnished royal palace, eight feet high, and everything in it is on a scale of one inch to a foot. Thumbnail paintings by Orpen, Sargent, Lavery, Cope, Holliday, of the Academy; murals by Nicholson; decorations by Edmund Dulac; etchings by Stanley Anderson; a staircase by Frampton
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="0"/>
<context>
the wagons were pulled by relays of horses but in 1820 the Duke of Portland bought Scotland's first steam locomotive, which was named The Duke. The engine operated until about 1848 but proved to be too heavy for the line and was never entirely successful. Unfortunately, The Duke was not preserved but a <head>model</head> of it can be seen in Troon Town Hall. In the beginning, only coal was transported on the line but by 1814 passengers were being conveyed from Kilmarnock to the coast at Troon, at weekends and on holidays. The fashion of railway excursions became very popular over the next 100 years, spreading throughout Britain and far beyond, and it is seldom realised that this leisure pursuit began in Ayrshire
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Many of the programmes do little to stimulate the mind and sitting in a chair staring at a screen is not too good for the body either. Think of how you could be spending your time instead; you could go swimming, make <head>model</head> aeroplanes or learn to yodel -- it doesn't matter what you do as long as it is fun! Legs came before cars, mind and hands before videos and computers. Try using them more often and you will get more enjoyment out of life and be healthier too.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Monofilament is used for fishing. It reels easily, rarely tangles, has acceptable cross-section for its breaking strain, and it has a lot of' give' so it can handle variations in tension. It is also used for <head>model</head> glider towlines for these reasons, and in particular, nylon monofilament has enough elasticity to catapult a model glider to greater height than the line length when launched with a strong tension. Nylon makes a 100% recovery to its original length but does so rather slowly. When under full tension and stretched, it has a reduced cross-section and consequently a reduced breaking strain.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="0"/>
<context>
It meant a lot of work for the Director preparing his camera script because he had to know exactly where to put his cameras to get the shots he wanted. We used to work with protractors on paper, measuring out the four angles viewable through each of the turret lenses. So when you got to see the Designer's scale <head>model</head> of the studio sets you knew that if you wanted to put an actor in one spot, in mid-shot, camera one would have to be precisely in such-and-such position with one lens, camera two would have to be precisely in another position with another lens, and so on. There was no hit and miss about it as can happen today where you can put a camera virtually anywhere and zoom into the position for any shot you want. Everything had to be worked out with great precision.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Inspiration for their shape came from some of Buckminster Fuller's geodesic shapes and principles, coupled with some of the aviation structures devised by Barnes Wallis. Shawcraft <head>model</head>s were contracted to build the three robots the budget would allow, plus the model of their city on stilts. Ray Angel and Brian Hodgson were entrusted to come up with a suitably electronic-sounding voice. Each Mechonoid was moulded in fibre-glass on a circular base and, like the Dalek, fitted with castors enabling it to roll along the floor.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="0"/>
<context>
The Yesterday's World main complex building has tripled in size with many new Victorian and Edwardian shop and room displays, push-button commentaries, animated life-size figures, old fashioned Penny arcade machines and much more... Outside there is a beautiful English County Garden with a refreshment kiosk, picnic area and Children's play area. Situated in the historic Almonry building surrounded by delightful gardens, come and see history unfold before you eyes on the town <head>model</head>. From 1066 and Battle of Hastings, you pass through the Abbey Gatehouse and see how the town has developed over the years. From the days of gunpowder, clock-making and leather products, you will be shown, in a sound and light experience
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Non-intervention' is routinely practised in British hospitals, where life-prolonging treatment is halted at the request of patients who have had enough. Some doctors may even hasten death with the pain-killing drugs they administer at this time, but their' intent to kill' or otherwise, is rarely tested in a court. Holland's liberal attitude is held as a <head>model</head> by many pro-euthanasia campaigners. Though mercy killing is still officially illegal, the law turns a blind eye to the 2.4 per cent of Dutch deaths which are accounted for by it. In Britain, however, patients on life-support machines or in a' permanent vegetative state' can not ask for the machine to be switched off. Doctors are obliged by law to keep them alive while there is a chance of recovery.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="0"/>
<context>
A mood of total defeatism had set in. Many of the party leaders appeared to have given up Rocked by an interminable succession of scandals, shamed by its inability to stop the inexorable rise of unemployment to a record three million, and increasingly alienated from ordinary people after more than a decade in power, the Socialist Party was no longer simply ailing; it was moribund. The latest scandal, this time involving the Prime Minister himself, Pierre Beregovoy, hitherto regarded as the very <head>model</head> of honesty and integrity, seemed like the last straw. M Beregovoy may claim that he has nothing to reproach himself with, but his acceptance of an interest-free million franc (125,000) loan from a shady businessman looks suspicious to say the least.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="0"/>
<context>
by pushing to the outer limits of her authority, making decisions with small groups of ministers and advisers, and closely involving herself in Whitehall promotions and the policies of departments,' the repertoire of Prime Ministerial tasks has been extended'. The very forcefulness with which Mrs Thatcher has projected her views and style, separate from those of her Cabinet, has also established a <head>model</head> of premiership. It is one which, whether measured in terms of winning elections or carrying through policies, has been remarkably successful. Thatcherism has been both a matter of style -- combining impatience with much of the status quo and a relentless promotion of new attitudes -- and policies. Both Lloyd George and Churchill were helped by the fact that their style suited the temper of the times.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="0"/>
<context>
That makes you want to fight for that little boy SAWYER To bring you up to date, we asked when Caroline Keller might be leaving Odyssey House, and we were told that no one knows. It could be a few more months, it could be another year. She will still have to find a job and a place to live with her children, though Father Fagan does say that she has been a <head>model</head> patient, and drug-free while she lived at Odyssey House. Officially, Derek is still a ward of the state. The Dades are still trying to re-open the case, but under the law, the odds are stacked against them.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="0"/>
<context>
they even wrote a sophomoric screenplay together about a perfect crime. It begins with the son murdering his wealthy parents. Nor did the Menendezes' troubles stop in Calabasas. Lyle was suspended from Princeton for cheating on a paper. Jose immediately flew back to try to get him reinstated. on camera So Lyle and Erik were not exactly <head>model</head> kids. Still, those kinds of family problems are hardly evidence of a desire or motive for murder. But what about the motive given by the prosecution- financial gain? voice-over The wills left by Jose and Kitty bequeathed their $14 million estate to the boys
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="0"/>
<context>
And I don't know how we- there's no way of judging how Ted or Mickey or Mays or Henry Aaron would have acted if they'd had $3 million a year at the age of 25. In other words, Jose Canseco is the very <head>model</head> of the modern major superstar: pampered, worshipped, paid a king's ransom. He's not rotten. Maybe he's just spoiled rotten. Now he must choose: to be Batman and walk among the legends of the game, or be the Joker- in which case, no way, Jose.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="0"/>
<context>
For armor she wore a string of pearls and on her fingers only her gold wedding ring. A scarf, a frilly blouse, sometimes gloves, were her badges of womanhood. She projected an image of stern femininity until she smiled or laughed and then her sexuality flashed out brilliant as lightning. She was feminine without being flirtatious; she was strong without a hint of masculinity. She was, in short, the very <head>model</head> for the first woman President of the United States. Which she must become if she signed the declaration on her desk. Now she was in the final stage of her run, emerging from the woods and onto a road where another car was waiting. Her detail of Secret Service men closed in and she was on her way to the Vice President's mansion.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="0"/>
<context>
"Let them also pick up the bums. " Although a few exiled felons were apprehended by U.S. immigration officials, most were not. " The conditions were too crowded, " says U.S. Army Col. Juan Armando Montes, who coordinated the reception. At the peak in early summer, he says, some 3,500 people were arriving every day. # As a result, within months of the boatlift's end in September, some Mariel refugees had committed murders, burglaries or hijackings. Yet many others became <head>model</head> citizens. Indeed, says Lisandro Perez, chairman of sociology and anthropology at Miami's Florida International University and himself a 1960 Cuban refugee, Mariels were driven less by politics than by economics: " They wanted to get ahead, make money and put their kids through college. "
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="0"/>
<context>
He was very sorry and totally misinformed. # Premier Herriot himself then mounted the tribune, explained what a sincere, simple chap M. Clementel was, how valuable his services had been to the Government and France, but condemned him out of hand for overstepping his authority and misrepresenting the Government, without, however, denying what the Finance Minister had said. His speech was a <head>model</head> of equivocation. He assured the Senate signifi- cantly that he would introduce a bill for the improvement of the Treasury's (Bank of France's) position. 720202 As the result of the suspension of the Dean (Dr. Louis Barthelemy) and Faculty of the Paris Law School and the closing of that institution, all of which took place in consequence of the students' strike
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="0"/>
<context>
We must not murmur at the conduct of his providence; we shall find it is all in wisdom and adore it. O God, what do I see in the course of the stars, in the order of the seasons, but thy will which they accomplish? Let it also be fulfilled in my soul. Jesus said, in speaking of his heavenly Father,' For I always do those things that please him;'' may we learn how far we can follow this example. He is our <head>model</head>, he whose life was devotion to the will of God. May we be united to him in this spirit; may we no longer follow our own inclinations, but may we not only pray, and teach, and suffer, but eat, drink, and converse, - do all things, with reference to his will. Then will our lives be a continuaU'self sacrifice, and an incessant prayer
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Two of his greatest performances came in 1979, with 5 for 38 in the World Cup final and 6 for 29 in the Gillette final for Somerset, although both times Richards pipped him for the match award. # For such a tall man Joel Garner had a beautiful follow-through with a great deal of athletic grace. In many ways Garner was the <head>model</head> professional, totally dedicated and loyal to his teams, an intelligent man who gave much thought to his game. If it is stretching the imagination to describe any West Indian fast bowler as a gentle giant he is nevertheless mild-mannered and easy-going, and it is significant that while the likes of Croft and Marshall were doing unpleasant things to batsmen's heads
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Brian Jacksons wrote eloquently about the still frequently thwarted aspirations of young fathers today to be different from the invisible or authoritarian men they remember their own fathers as having been. For some fathers, the motivation to be involved with their children has powerful psychological roots. Liddie Heath's husband, Richard, was the <head>model</head> of a helpful partner when their son was born. He had been with Liddie through the various pre-natal classes, lying on the floor with her and learning the breathing exercises. Back at home with their baby he was quick to be the one to change the nappies and administer the bottle feed once Liddie had given up breastfeeding.
</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
