<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Minister P.V. Narasimha Rao was beginning his US trip by meeting Sunday with the Indian community in New York. Rao, who arrived in the Big <head>Apple</head> on Saturday on the first US tour by an Indian premier since Rajiv Gandhi came here in 1987, was also to visit Houston and Boston 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="1"/>
<context>
Monday. The 19 tonnes of apples represented the first significant import of foreign apples since the Japanese government enacted a law in 1971 to liberalize <head>apple</head> imports, press reports said.  Despite the formal liberalization, Japan had continued its ban on apple imports from major exporters such as New Zealand and the 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="1"/>
<context>
the Japanese government enacted a law in 1971 to liberalize apple imports, press reports said. Despite the formal liberalization, Japan had continued its ban on <head>apple</head> imports from major exporters such as New Zealand and the United States, citing possible risks from insects and viruses arriving with foreign products.  A total 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="2"/>
<context>
yen (7.60 dollars), twice the price of local apples. Last month, when a sample consignment of New Zealand apples arrived at Tokyo's Narita airport, Japanese <head>apple</head> growers passed out free samples of their fruit to convince consumers that homegrown apples were better than imports.  Hot dogs, as American as apple pie 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Japanese apple growers passed out free samples of their fruit to convince consumers that homegrown apples were better than imports. Hot dogs, as American as <head>apple</head> pie and a staple diet for tens of thousands of kids, may be a cancer risk according to a report published in a cancer research 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="3"/>
<context>
their respective development costs, allowing them bigger budgets to fight off the competition by their toughest rival, the PowerPC chip chosen by IBM, Motorola and <head>Apple</head> Computer.  Though the industry seems split into two huge camps over the new- generation microprocessors, the HP-Intel initiative could weaken efforts by other US chip 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Boso peninsula, a picturesque sub-tropical area dotted with rice paddies, flower farms and fishing villages, Tateyama is a world away from the dairy pastures and <head>apple</head> orchards of western Normandy.  The beach is popular with windsurfers and on a clear day you can see Mount Fuji across the bay. The biggest 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="2"/>
<context>
most popular sport among young Americans, it faces an impenetrable barrier of prejudice erected by the nation's media. Hating soccer is more American then " <head>apple</head> pie," according to one top columnist, and the Globe's own star writer Bob Ryan recently said it was "sacrilege" and "preposterous" to give soccer elbow 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="0"/>
<context>
1896. The Republic of Ireland, preparing for Friday's clash with Mexico here, cannot wait to return to New York for another bite at the Big <head>Apple</head>  If they can make it anywhere, they will make it in New York, 1,000 miles up America's East coast, says goalkeeper Packie Bonner, who recalls 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="5"/>
<context>
warning off Jewish children trying to raid his fruit trees, recalling the days when the whole area was open countryside. "There only used to be <head>apple</head> and olive trees and rocks here," said the old man who left his birthplace in 1948 when Israel was founded. That village, Al Amour, by 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="0"/>
<context>
the waist, but left unbuttoned to show a tantalising glimpse of at least 10 centimetres of boxer shorts. Colours for the sunshine were mediterranean blues, <head>apple</head> green, sizzling orange and turquoise. Linen suits also came in straw and crushed raspberry, worn with simple T-shirts. For the beach there were jump suits 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="6"/>
<context>
or blocked efforts to check them out. The Mollen report found it was nearly impossible to estimate the number of bad apples in the "Big <head>Apple</head> but said that the city's poor, crime-ridden neighborhoods suffered most.  "Numerous residents and leaders of these communities told us that they often do not know 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="7"/>
<context>
demonstrate techniques in the creation of images and scenes used in the development of virtual reality attractions. Other exhibit sponsors include American Telephone and Telegraph, <head>Apple</head> Oracle, Sega and International Business Machines. Apple will focus on its multimedia products. Oracle will demonstrate the impact of the "information superhighway" on households and 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="7"/>
<context>
and scenes used in the development of virtual reality attractions. Other exhibit sponsors include American Telephone and Telegraph, Apple, Oracle, Sega and International Business Machines. <head>Apple</head> will focus on its multimedia products. Oracle will demonstrate the impact of the "information superhighway" on households and Sega will feature a virtual helmet in 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="7"/>
<context>
"information superhighway" on households and Sega will feature a virtual helmet in its new game, "Virtual Fighter." IBM plans to show speech-recognition technology. Some 250 <head>apple</head> growers in Japan expressed strong opposition Friday to importing US apples, saying that the product did not meet Japan's quarantine standards.  During a two-day hearing 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="8"/>
<context>
US apples to Japan in May in Washington. Officials of the ministry of agriculture, forestry and fisheries said that it would hold another hearing for <head>apple</head> growers in the near future.  In June last year, the ministry decided to lift the import ban on apples from New Zealand as it had 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="9"/>
<context>
used to control the cursor on computer screens. GlidePoint is a screen on which the computer user's finger can trace the direction of the cursor. <head>Apple</head> recently incorporated the concept in its new line of PowerBook 500.  Cirque says the independent screen has the advantage of being able to be placed 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="10"/>
<context>
or trackball. The screen works with Windows 3.1. A version for IBM-compatible portable computers is due on the market in several months and one for <head>Apple</head> Macintosh computers is under development.  Sally Little is on course to end a six-year victory drought at the 650,000 dollar Big Apple Classic after shooting 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="10"/>
<context>
and one for Apple's Macintosh computers is under development. Sally Little is on course to end a six-year victory drought at the 650,000 dollar Big <head>Apple</head> Classic after shooting a four-under par 67 in the opening round here.  Little, who has 15 tournament titles to her credit but has not won 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="10"/>
<context>
Maine company. our veteran JoAnne Carner was bidding for her first victory since 1985 after taking a two-stroke lead in the 650,000 dollar JAL Big <head>Apple</head> Classic second round on Friday.  The 55-year-old, who became the oldest tournament winner back in 1985 when she won the last of her 42 titles, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="11"/>
<context>
an eight-foot birdie putt on the 18th hole here Saturday, pulling to a three-stroke lead entering the final round of the 650,000-dollar LPGA JAL Big <head>Apple</head> Classic.  Daniel, who ranks second to England's Laura Davies on the money list, also dropped a 20-foot birdie putt on the 12th hole during a 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="11"/>
<context>
putt on the first sudden-death playoff hole here Sunday to defeat England's Laura Davies in a battle of LPGA money leaders for the JAL Big <head>Apple</head> Classic title.  Tour money leader Davies left her three-foot birdie effort short on the extra hole, giving second-place money winner Daniel the 97,500-dollar top prize.  

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="8"/>
<context>
40 million dollars a year from exports to China, providing a major boon to the state's 4,500 growers. Chinese officials and US diplomats said the <head>apple</head> agreement marked a further thaw in bilateral trade relations which, despite the renewal of China most-favoured-nation staus in May, are still mired in rows over 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="0"/>
<context>
came during US Agriculture Minister Mike Espy's official visit to Beijing in October. He arrived at a meeting with Chinese agriculture officials carrying a Washington <head>apple</head> he had brought from a street vendor.  "Look the trade is already occurring," he said. "Let's make it official."  In addition, the Washington Apple Commission 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Washington apple he had brought from a street vendor. "Look the trade is already occurring," he said. "Let's make it official." In addition, the Washington <head>Apple</head> Commission (WAC), a trade and lobbying commission representing growers, pressured President Bill Clinton to renew MFN through one of his close allies -- house speaker 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="12"/>
<context>
to such services, which provide everything from electronic bulletin boards to long-distance shopping, and the figure should double by 1998. APPLE ANNOUNCES NEW POWERBOOK <head>Apple</head> announced this week a new PowerBook portable model 150 to replace the PowerBook 145 as its low-end offering aimed mostly at budget-minded students and new 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="9"/>
<context>
1.8 kilograms (four pounds) it is about 500 grams (one pound) lighter, and has a 22.8 centimeter (nine-inch) high-resolution screen with four levels of gray. <head>Apple</head> has also boosted battery life and included a new software to better monitor remaining power.   TOURING ANCIENT CITIES VIA CD-ROM  The San Francisco software publisher 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="13"/>
<context>
years ago. But bookmakers clearly believe he has made the right choice with Ezzoud's latest odds cut to 10-1 from 12-1 behind 7-2 Erhaab, 9-2 <head>Apple</head> Tree, 11-2 White Muzzle, 13-2 Bob's Return, 8-1 Foyer.  Doubts still surround Hamdan Al-Maktoum's second string, the Alec Stewart trained Wagon Master, while Ionio and 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="0"/>
<context>
this Kashmir summer capital after being discharged from a New Delhi hospital where he was admitted Sunday in serious condition. Malik drank a glass of <head>apple</head> juice in front of supporters here, symbolically breaking the "fast unto death" he launched Friday. He denied that he had ended his hunger strike in 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="5"/>
<context>
only about 10,000 of its Personal Communicators. Analysts said technical problems and the 2,000 to 4,000-dollar price tag deterred buyers. Similar products such as the <head>Apple</head> Newton or Motorola's Envoy are also having difficulties and others have been taken off the market.   SEGA LAUNCHES VIDEO GAME CHANNEL  Sega, one of the 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="11"/>
<context>
inside the former Lido. The Champs Elysees Planet Hollywood will have a 500-seater restaurant, featuring a "Classic Californian" menu of vegetarian dishes, exotic salads and <head>apple</head> strudel -- made from a recipe of Schwarzenegger's mother.  Planet Hollywood will also have a 100-seat cinema, a private room and a shop.  Moslem guerrillas 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="14"/>
<context>
pledging to continue their separatist campaign until Kashmir secedes from India. Police said some 300 militants armed with AK-47 rifles held a parade in an <head>apple</head> orchard in north Kashmir on Sunday.  Smaller parades were reported elsewhere in the Kashmir valley.  Fighting erupted between Indian troops and militants in two places 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="15"/>
<context>
growth of local software industries," the BSA said. The BSA, formed in 1988, groups the world's major computer software and hardware producers, among them Aldus, <head>Apple</head> Computer, Autodesk, Lotus, Microsoft, Novell and WordPerfect.  It has so far prosecuted more than 30 companies in Singapore and about 300 companies worldwide for infringing 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="12"/>
<context>
to start any war", he added. Compaq ranked first in computer sales for the United States in two consecutive quarters, outpacing rival giants IBM and <head>Apple</head> Computer, according to Dataquest.  It had 14.3 percent of the US market share, Apple held 11.2 percent, Packard Bell Electronics 9.3 percent and IBM, 7.9 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="12"/>
<context>
United States in two consecutive quarters, outpacing rival giants IBM and Apple Computer, according to Dataquest. It had 14.3 percent of the US market share, <head>Apple</head> held 11.2 percent, Packard Bell Electronics 9.3 percent and IBM, 7.9 percent.  Compaq outranked IBM as the world's number one computer manufacturer last year.  Apple, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="12"/>
<context>
Apple held 11.2 percent, Packard Bell Electronics 9.3 percent and IBM, 7.9 percent. Compaq outranked IBM as the world's number one computer manufacturer last year. <head>Apple</head> which was number one in the US market up until this year, launched a new series of pocket computers, Power PC, in March in a 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="12"/>
<context>
US market up until this year, launched a new series of pocket computers, Power PC, in March in a bid to regain its market share. <head>Apple</head> officials refused to comment on the Compaq price cuts.  IBM was expected to be directly affected by the move as it is already tackling a 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="8"/>
<context>
products, according to Business Week. Japan said Friday it would lift a long-standing ban on imports of US apples August 22 despite opposition from local <head>apple</head> growers.  The ministry of agriculture, forestry and fisheries made the announcement after concluding talks with Japanese apple growers.  The Japanese government, bowing to US pressure, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="8"/>
<context>
US apples August 22 despite opposition from local apple growers. The ministry of agriculture, forestry and fisheries made the announcement after concluding talks with Japanese <head>apple</head> growers.  The Japanese government, bowing to US pressure, agreed in principle last year to lift the ban.  But domestic growers remain opposed to the imports, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="16"/>
<context>
after it complied with technical requirements. Shipments began in May.Japan's decision announced Friday to allow imports of American apples is a new setback for French <head>apple</head> producers, the world export leader, they said on Friday.  "For 20 years now, we've been trying to penetrate that market, multiplying our presentations and missions, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="16"/>
<context>
trying to penetrate that market, multiplying our presentations and missions, and we're still at square one", AFP was told by Nicolas Arnoux, who handles the <head>apple</head> sector at the French Association of Fruits and Vegetables Economic Committees (ASCOFEL).  He noted that the Japanese government applies very strict plant health regulations to 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="4"/>
<context>
the fruit be completely free of "Mediterranean flies" - an insect found in all European orchards that can be easily eliminated. Arnoux added that French <head>apple</head> producers, turning out two million tonnes a year for export markets, have for years been ogling profitable Asian markets. In addition to Japan, they are 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="17"/>
<context>
a year for export markets, have for years been ogling profitable Asian markets. In addition to Japan, they are going to tackle Taiwan, a promising <head>apple</head> market 95 percent dominated by the Americans. Japan's decision announced Friday to allow imports of American apples is a new setback for French apple producers, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="16"/>
<context>
promising apple market 95 percent dominated by the Americans. Japan's decision announced Friday to allow imports of American apples is a new setback for French <head>apple</head> producers, the world export leader, they said on Friday.  "For 20 years now, we've been trying to penetrate that market, multiplying our presentations and missions, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="4"/>
<context>
the fruit be completely free of "Mediterranean flies" - an insect found in all European orchards that can be easily eliminated. Arnoux added that French <head>apple</head> producers, turning out two million tonnes a year including 600,000 for export markets, have for years been ogling profitable Asian markets. In addition to Japan, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="17"/>
<context>
including 600,000 for export markets, have for years been ogling profitable Asian markets. In addition to Japan, they are going to tackle Taiwan, a promising <head>apple</head> market 95 percent dominated by the Americans. Washington state apple growers Friday hailed Japan's lifting of a longstanding import ban on US apples, hoping their 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="17"/>
<context>
profitable Asian markets. In addition to Japan, they are going to tackle Taiwan, a promising apple market 95 percent dominated by the Americans. Washington state <head>apple</head> growers Friday hailed Japan's lifting of a longstanding import ban on US apples, hoping their cheaper, "everyday" fruit will create a new niche in the 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="6"/>
<context>
hoping their cheaper, "everyday" fruit will create a new niche in the Japanese diet. "We're pleased about the announcement," Jim Thomas, spokesman for the Washington <head>apple</head> Commission, told AFP in a telephone interview from the Pacific northwest state.  Thomas said that apple growers in Washington state were planning to ship their 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="6"/>
<context>
about the announcement," Jim Thomas, spokesman for the Washington Apple Commission, told AFP in a telephone interview from the Pacific northwest state. Thomas said that <head>apple</head> growers in Washington state were planning to ship their apples to Japan "around December if everything goes as planned."  "We're not popping the champagne corks 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="18"/>
<context>
said, recalling a 23-year-long battle with the Japanese government to gain entry into the market. Japan is the last Pacific Rim country to admit US <head>apple</head> imports. Japan opened its apple market in 1971 but continued to ban imports from the United States on grounds that the fruit might carry in 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="18"/>
<context>
with the Japanese government to gain entry into the market. Japan is the last Pacific Rim country to admit US apple imports. Japan opened its <head>apple</head> market in 1971 but continued to ban imports from the United States on grounds that the fruit might carry in pests and disease.  US growers 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="8"/>
<context>
crossed the threshold and met the (domestic) political reaction." Japan's ministry of agriculture, forestry and fisheries made the announcement Friday after concluding talks with Japanese <head>apple</head> growers, who remain opposed to the imports.  Thomas said the action only allows entry of Golden and Red Delicious apples from Washington, which produces 96 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="8"/>
<context>
will review all shipping facilities. Then the entire process will be reviewed. Thomas said about 800 hectares (2,000 acres), or one percent of the state's <head>apple</head> acreage, has been cultivated this year to meet Japan's requirements.  That acreage is "down considerably" from previous years as growers grew disenchanted with the costly 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="19"/>
<context>
horse. The waiters' voices echo throughout the coffee shop, calling out the orders of "two reds" (a hibiscus drink), "three greens" (mint tea), "one honeyed <head>apple</head> an Arab water-pipe with apple or molasses flavoring.  The allure of the decor and the atmosphere redolent of history draws Egyptians and tourists who are 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="19"/>
<context>
throughout the coffee shop, calling out the orders of "two reds" (a hibiscus drink), "three greens" (mint tea), "one honeyed apple," an Arab water-pipe with <head>apple</head> or molasses flavoring.  The allure of the decor and the atmosphere redolent of history draws Egyptians and tourists who are crammed into the shop's tiny 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="12"/>
<context>
profitability, the best retailing network, the best marketing in the business," Corpuz said. Officials at the Texas-based Compaq, which has leapfrogged ahead of IBM and <head>Apple</head> as the top personal computer producer in the early months of 1994, declined to comment on IBM's move.  Corpuz said that Compaq is likely to 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="12"/>
<context>
by changing the architecture of its devices. The Redwood City, California-based firm has said it would switch to the Power PC put out by IBM, <head>Apple</head> and Motorola to double the power from 32 to 64 bits. It will also provide a new card to make a similar power boost in 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="1"/>
<context>
long run of Broadway flops and a wartime stint in the US Navy, Ewell had his first taste of commercial success in 1946 with " <head>Apple</head> of His Eye" and "John Loves Mary."  His film career began in 1949 with "Adam's Rib" with Katherine Hepburn and Spencer Tracy.  The Japanese electronics 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="20"/>
<context>
mail, faxes, on-line services and other functions as well as serving as a regular computer to organize and store information. Developed with AT and T, <head>Apple</head> Computers and other firms, the new marvel is sized like a fat paperback novel and weighs 1.2 pounds (half a kilogram). It sells for 995 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="5"/>
<context>
the Japanese company's US unit. Others have stumbled along the same path. AT and T's EO Personal Communicator was too expensive and difficult to use. <head>Apple</head> Newton Message Pad tried out a handwriting recognition software that was a dismal failure.  Sony said it was targeting a market of "mobile professionals" with 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="3"/>
<context>
will be in constant contact with users, looking for feedback to refine the device. The operating system software was developed by General Magic Inc., an <head>Apple</head> spinoff also partly owned by Sony, Motorola Inc., AT and T, the Japanese firm Matsushita and the Dutch company Philips.  Known as Magic Cap, it 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="3"/>
<context>
powerPC alliance as an important strategic step toward next-generation computer development," Kunika Mizushima, executive vice president of Toshiba, said. The PowerPC, developed jointly by IBM, <head>Apple</head> Computer and Motorola Inc., is designed to operate in a wide range of computers, from portable personal units to multi-processor parallel processing computers.  The company 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="12"/>
<context>
Mandela will be seeking to demonstrate to business leaders that South Africa is a good place to invest. While some big US firms such as <head>Apple</head> IBM and Pepsico have returned to South Africa, more investment is needed to help rebuild the ecoomy.  Mandela "wants to send a message to investors 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="0"/>
<context>
said.Carnegie, ridden by Thierry Jarnet, won the 73rd L'Arc de Triomphe horse race here on Sunday. Hernando, owned by Greece's Stavros Niarchos, came second and <head>Apple</head> Tree, ridden by Northern Ireland's John Reid, third in Europe's top flat race.  In an exciting event at the Longchamps race course on the edge 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="5"/>
<context>
The case was brought after the 51-year-old actress alleged that the officers "tortured" her, and claims to have had a bruise "as big as an <head>apple</head> She said she was off work for four days as a result of the incident.  Following the court ruling in this southern French city Tuesday, 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="2"/>
<context>
in accusing the policemen," he said. "It was for the court to decide."Would a God-fearing Frenchman ban the baguette? Non. Would a patriotic American outlaw <head>apple</head> pie? Nope. Would a German scrap sauerkraut? Nein.  Would an Indian risk vilification and the wrath of millions by calling for a ban on one 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="21"/>
<context>
marketing organisation which, operating in 100 countries with 80 fully owned subsidiaries, associate companies and agencies, is the largest dairy organisation in the world. The <head>Apple</head> and Pear Marketing Board is a grower co-operative that until recently controlled all pipfruit sales, although the domestic market is now being deregulated. Through its 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="21"/>
<context>
no useful information available." Board supporters were "still stuck in the Brezhnev era, not realising that the world is changing around them", Kerr said. The <head>Apple</head> and Pear Board is under assault by publicly-listed company Apple Fields, which claims growers would be much better off in a deregulated market.  A similar 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="21"/>
<context>
the Brezhnev era, not realising that the world is changing around them", Kerr said. The Apple and Pear Board is under assault by publicly-listed company <head>Apple</head> Fields, which claims growers would be much better off in a deregulated market.  A similar battle is underway against KMB with growers producing 40 percent 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="22"/>
<context>
percent are sold under the Samsung brand. It also produces seven million colour monitors, half of them for companies such as Hewlett Packard, IBM or <head>Apple</head>  Its vast industrial complex in Suwon covers 1,500 hectares (3,706 acres), employs 30,000 people --with residential accomodation for 6,000 of them -- as well as 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="13"/>
<context>
adopted two years ago by Lee Kun-Hee, Samsung Group president and son of the conglomerate's founder. The Group slogan: "Change to be the world's best." <head>Apple</head> Computer, the second largest US computer maker, said Tuesday that its quarterly results will be better than expected because of the popularity of its Power 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="13"/>
<context>
largest US computer maker, said Tuesday that its quarterly results will be better than expected because of the popularity of its Power Macintoshes and Powerbooks. <head>Apple</head> revenues for its fourth quarter, which ended September 30, are expected to total about 2.5 billion dollars with profits of more than 90 cents per 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="13"/>
<context>
for its fourth quarter, which ended September 30, are expected to total about 2.5 billion dollars with profits of more than 90 cents per share, <head>Apple</head> said based on preliminary figures.  Apple said that the upward revision was due to strong sales of the Power Macintosh and Powerbook notebook computers.  Apple's 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="13"/>
<context>
September 30, are expected to total about 2.5 billion dollars with profits of more than 90 cents per share, Apple said based on preliminary figures. <head>Apple</head> said that the upward revision was due to strong sales of the Power Macintosh and Powerbook notebook computers.  Apple's share prices rose sharply on Wall 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="13"/>
<context>
Apple said based on preliminary figures. Apple said that the upward revision was due to strong sales of the Power Macintosh and Powerbook notebook computers. <head>Apple</head> share prices rose sharply on Wall Street Tuesday on news that it and IBM were nearing an agreement on making the two lines of computers 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="23"/>
<context>
prices rose sharply on Wall Street Tuesday on news that it and IBM were nearing an agreement on making the two lines of computers compatible. <head>Apple</head> rose 2-3/8 dollars to 41-1/4 dollars Tuesday at midmorning on the NASDAQ exchange. Apple's share prices rose 1.87 dollars on Monday.IBM, the world's largest computer 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="23"/>
<context>
nearing an agreement on making the two lines of computers compatible. Apple rose 2-3/8 dollars to 41-1/4 dollars Tuesday at midmorning on the NASDAQ exchange. <head>Apple</head> share prices rose 1.87 dollars on Monday.IBM, the world's largest computer manufacturer, announced here Tuesday that it was bringing out a new version of its 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="24"/>
<context>
itself in the expanding micro-computer market. "IBM can't give up the market to Microsoft," said John Jones, an expert with Salomon Brothers. IBM has joined <head>Apple</head> to wage its battle against Microsoft and has also enlisted telecommunications player Motorola to develop a microchip for the latest generation of PowerPC computers.  Apple 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="24"/>
<context>
Apple to wage its battle against Microsoft and has also enlisted telecommunications player Motorola to develop a microchip for the latest generation of PowerPC computers. <head>Apple</head> and IBM have set up two joint ventures -- Kaleida Labs and Taligent -- to develop multimedia programs.  The two companies have reportedly moved towards 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="24"/>
<context>
-- Kaleida Labs and Taligent -- to develop multimedia programs. The two companies have reportedly moved towards greater compatibility and developed systems that will allow <head>Apple</head> and IBM programs to be used by both.  Rumors on Wall Street also claim that IBM is preparing to buy a stake in Apple.Samsung Electronics 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="24"/>
<context>
allow Apple and IBM programs to be used by both. Rumors on Wall Street also claim that IBM is preparing to buy a stake in <head>Apple</head> Electronics Co. (SEC), a subsidiary of South Korea's giant Samsung group, forecasts a mammoth 40 percent rise in turnover this year to 14 billion US 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="22"/>
<context>
percent are sold under the Samsung brand. It also produces seven million colour monitors, half of them for companies such as Hewlett Packard, IBM and <head>Apple</head>  Its vast industrial complex in Suwon covers 1,500 hectares (3,706 acres), employs 30,000 people -- with residential accomodation for 6,000 of them -- as well 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="0"/>
<context>
clothes bearing the Lagerfeld tag in the recent past. Demure little dresses with flippy skirts skimming the knee in pretty shades like lemon, lilac and <head>apple</head> green were given a hard edge with shiny plastic girdles worn outside. But these could be unzipped and discarded, as the models demonstrated.  Similarly, broad 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="14"/>
<context>
range of sharply tailored black and white coordinates, with waistcoats and little short-sleeved shirts, white ties on black and vice versa, which were warmly applauded. <head>Apple</head> Computer reported Monday that quarterly earnings soared to 114.6 million dollars, compared with 2.6 million dollars in the same period a year earlier.  Apple said 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="14"/>
<context>
applauded. Apple Computer reported Monday that quarterly earnings soared to 114.6 million dollars, compared with 2.6 million dollars in the same period a year earlier. <head>Apple</head> said profits for its fiscal year fourth quarter ending September 30 amounted to 95 cents per share from two cents a year ago.  The company 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="13"/>
<context>
million dollars, or 73 cents per share, in the previous 12 months. Total fiscal year sales rose to 9.18 billion dollars from 7.97 billion dollars. <head>Apple</head> said it had trouble meeting demand for its most popular computers, and was working to remedy the situation.An influential group of global software producers said 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="15"/>
<context>
based on a report by the International Intellectual Property Association (IIPA), which lobbied for Manila's inclusion on the list. BSA, active members of which include <head>Apple</head> Computer, Autodesk, Intergraph, Lotus Development, Microsoft and Novell/Wordperfect Applications Group, is also to submit its input to the IIPA.  Eckstrom said one proof of the 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="5"/>
<context>
atmosphere is perfectly captured. The menu is mouth-watering, featuring warm duck foie-gras with peppered black beans, Kobe beef grilled with shallots and poached marrowbone, and <head>apple</head> souffle.  Taillevent director Jean Claude Vrinat, whose team is responsible for service and the magnificent wine cellar, said Sapporo has not spared any expense. "There 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="25"/>
<context>
1961 Chateau Margaux. Five Japanese farmers filed a suit against the agricultural ministry on Wednesday, demanding cancellation of a decision to lift a ban on <head>apple</head> imports from the United States.  The farmers brought an action to the Tokyo District Court, claiming that US apples, which they say did not meet 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="25"/>
<context>
In August, the ministry, bowing to US pressure, announced it would lift a ban on imports of American apples a year after removing restrictions on <head>apple</head> shipments from New Zealand.  Tokyo technically opened its apple market in 1971 but continued to ban imports from big exporters such as the United States 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="25"/>
<context>
it would lift a ban on imports of American apples a year after removing restrictions on apple shipments from New Zealand. Tokyo technically opened its <head>apple</head> market in 1971 but continued to ban imports from big exporters such as the United States and New Zealand on grounds that the fruit might 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="3"/>
<context>
A first shipment of US apples is scheduled for December.Japan's Pioneer Electronic Corp. will enter the personal computer market next year in a tie-up with <head>Apple</head> Computer Inc., a daily said Saturday.  Pioneer, a major audio equipment maker, will sell personal computers loaded with Apple software and a microprocessor jointly developed 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="3"/>
<context>
next year in a tie-up with Apple Computer Inc., a daily said Saturday. Pioneer, a major audio equipment maker, will sell personal computers loaded with <head>Apple</head> software and a microprocessor jointly developed by US companies Apple, IBM Corp. and Motorola Inc., the Nihon Keizai Shimbun said.  Apple is asking Japanese and 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="3"/>
<context>
daily said Saturday. Pioneer, a major audio equipment maker, will sell personal computers loaded with Apple software and a microprocessor jointly developed by US companies <head>Apple</head> IBM Corp. and Motorola Inc., the Nihon Keizai Shimbun said.  Apple is asking Japanese and US companies to use its personal computer software to compete 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="3"/>
<context>
personal computers loaded with Apple software and a microprocessor jointly developed by US companies Apple, IBM Corp. and Motorola Inc., the Nihon Keizai Shimbun said. <head>Apple</head> is asking Japanese and US companies to use its personal computer software to compete with US computer giant Microsoft Corp., the newspaper said.  Japan's Fujitsu 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="26"/>
<context>
a built-in rewritable magneto-optical disc drive. Fujitsu, the biggest computer maker in Japan but ranked third in sales of perosnal computers behind NEC Corp. and <head>Apple</head> Computer Co. of the United States, targetted sales at 150,000 units in the first year.Computer giants IBM and Apple plan to announce Monday a common 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="26"/>
<context>
perosnal computers behind NEC Corp. and Apple Computer Co. of the United States, targetted sales at 150,000 units in the first year.Computer giants IBM and <head>Apple</head> plan to announce Monday a common standard for future personal computers, industry sources said Friday.  The agreement between the two largest US computer makers covers 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="27"/>
<context>
Toshiba and Canon are likely to offer clones of the machines based on the joint technology, the sources said. Other sources close to IBM and <head>Apple</head> said Italian concern Olivetti may do the same.  The agreement should encourage the development of special software, which would counterbalance the overwhelming domination of Microsoft 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="27"/>
<context>
of special software, which would counterbalance the overwhelming domination of Microsoft and Intel. But while ending the longstanding problem of the incompatibility of IBM and <head>Apple</head> systems for the future, the agreement will do nothing to make the two group's existing systems compatible.  The two groups have also not yet agreed 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="28"/>
<context>
two groups have also not yet agreed to share their operating software for the new machines. IBM, for example, would not be able to sell <head>Apple</head> MacIntosh software, which essentially means it would be marketing machines technically capable of operating with Apple software without being able to sell the program enabling 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="100">
<answer instance="100" senseid="28"/>
<context>
IBM, for example, would not be able to sell Apple's MacIntosh software, which essentially means it would be marketing machines technically capable of operating with <head>Apple</head> software without being able to sell the program enabling the buyer to use such software on his machine.  But an agreement in this area could 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="101">
<answer instance="101" senseid="20"/>
<context>
said. But it remained unclear whether the Fed would act again on rates before the end of the year. IBM fell 2 to 71-1/8 and <head>Apple</head> traded on the secondary market, lost 1-1/8 to 40-3/8 after the two computer firms announced they had developed a common standard for personal computers.  Union 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="102">
<answer instance="102" senseid="20"/>
<context>
computer firms announced they had developed a common standard for personal computers. Union Carbide rose 1/2 to 31 and Coca-Cola 1/4 to 50.High-tech giants IBM, <head>Apple</head> and Motorola announced Monday that they had agreed on a common standard for personal computers, with the first of the new machines to come on 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="103">
<answer instance="103" senseid="20"/>
<context>
new machines to come on the market in 1996. The agreement covers personal computers using the PowerPC microprocessor developed by the three companies.High-tech giants IBM, <head>Apple</head> and Motorola announced Monday that they had agreed a common standard for personal computers, with the first of the new machines to come on the 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="104">
<answer instance="104" senseid="29"/>
<context>
personal computers using the PowerPC microproessor developed by the three companies. The new computers would be able to use software designed for both IBM and <head>Apple</head> systems, which are currently incompatible.  PowerPC will enable the companies to offer personal computers which could use Apple's Mac OS operating software, IBM's OS/2 and 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="105">
<answer instance="105" senseid="29"/>
<context>
use software designed for both IBM and Apple systems, which are currently incompatible. PowerPC will enable the companies to offer personal computers which could use <head>Apple</head> Mac OS operating software, IBM's OS/2 and AIX and Microsoft's Windows.  Windows is by far the world's most popular personal computer software system, present in 

</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
