<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Mafia, historically associated with the rural backlands of Sicily, has turned into a modern crime "business" through its arrival on the international drug market. Experts <head>calculate</head> its turnover per year in increasingly varied criminal activities at 45 billion to 55 billion dollars, with a major portion reinvested in the international financial
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="2"/>
<context>
On the London import market, a tonne of white pepper going for about 2,700 dollars a year ago is now fetching 3,850 dollars. British importers <head>calculate</head> that prices ought to climb a further 10 to 15 percent this year and stay firm at those levels for several years.  The impact has
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="1"/>
<context>
your original query Inflation index exaggerates real price rises: Greenspan by Jean-Louis Santini Source: Agence France Presse Changing the method the United States uses to <head>calculate</head> its inflation rate could save the government 150 billion dollars over five years, Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan said Wednesday.  The current method of calculating
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="2"/>
<context>
construction point in the direction of an overstatement of increases in the cost of living," Greenspan said. Because the CPI index is the basis to <head>calculate</head> increases in a wide range of federal spending, including the basic retirement pension nationwide, any inbuilt error in calculating the index itself is incurring huge
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="2"/>
<context>
dollars in March, but the increase in real terms was only 3.0 percent because of the dollar's plunge. "The price has not increased if you <head>calculate</head> the depreciation of the dollar," Iran's Aghazadeh said as he arrived here Sunday, adding it was still "very far from our target price" of 21
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="2"/>
<context>
for each bank's problem loans is considerably higher," the report said. Another estimate excluding the effect of the subsidy and using other methods to <head>calculate</head> bad loans, the potential losses represent 184 billion dollars, the firm said. It used a dollar-yen rate of 101.46.  Concerns about Japan's banking system have
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="2"/>
<context>
institutions to their respective national central banks. "More than eight billion euro banknotes are already in circulation," the ECB estimated. The ECB has begun to <head>calculate</head> its own "euro progress ratio or EPR" to monitor the progress of the cash changeover.  The ratio calculated the value of euro banknotes in circulation
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the fourth quarter from the third quarter, after already contracting by 0.1 percent in the third quarter. Economists cautioned it was too early to accurately <head>calculate</head> the full extent of the decline, since the latest data were only provisional and did not yet take into account a number of important factors.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="2"/>
<context>
fourth quarter from the third quarter, after already contracting by 0.1 percent in the third quarter. Nevertheless, economists caution it is too early to accurately <head>calculate</head> the full extent of the fourth-quarter decline, since the latest official GDP data were only provisional and did not yet take into account a number
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="2"/>
<context>
billion euros, down from 1.921 billion euros. Bank governor Zsigmond Jarai said the discrepencies were the result of using figures from companies' financial reports to <head>calculate</head> current account figures.  European Union members and the International Monetary Fund use customs statistics to draw up their data.  "Hungary has begun to apply the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="2"/>
<context>
by 0.5 percentage points and for the whole year, GDP will be lowered by 0.2 percentage points," Cheong told AFP. It was too early to <head>calculate</head> the heavy losses suffered by industrial plant in southeastern industrial cities including Changwon, Masan and Ulsan, where production was halted by floods and power failures,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="2"/>
<context>
also revise GDP statistics for previous years, Li said, suggesting they will go as far back as 1952. He insisted statisticians have the ability to <head>calculate</head> the real economic growth even for chaotic periods in Chinese history such as the Great Leap Forward in the late 1950s when officials routinely reported
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="2"/>
<context>
to Albanians, Bulgarians and Hungarians living in Switzerland, the daily said. But the insurer had denied its decision was racist, Le Matin added. "When we <head>calculate</head> the risks, nationality is only one of some 12 criteria we use," Balois spokeswoman Martina Hilker told the paper.  "But it is true that we
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Martina Hilker, a spokeswoman for Baloise, rejected any accusation of unfair discrimination. "Nationality is only one of the criteria that is taken into account to <head>calculate</head> the insurance charge along with, for example, the type of vehicle, the age of the driver or the average number of kilometres they drive," she
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="2"/>
<context>
will feed through to job creation in the EU's hidebound labour markets. In particular, the Dutch want to promote a computer model they use to <head>calculate</head> the cost of new regulations on business. If the cost is too high, civil servants -- in this case the European Commission -- must re-think.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="2"/>
<context>
a quarter of a point to 2.75 percent. Russia-EU-bank-eurozone-euro-dollar-forex MOSCOW The Russian central bank said that it had doubled the weighting of euros used to <head>calculate</head> the nominal exchange rate of the ruble from 10 percent to 20 percent at the expense of the dollar.  Kenya-Britain-corruption  NAIROBI: Almost a billion dollars
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="2"/>
<context>
budget. Hammud said the League should review each member's conditions and possibilities, such as their individual revenues, gross domestic products and per capita income, and <head>calculate</head> their share accordingly.  "All these conditions should be taken into account," to ensure a fair distribution, Hammud said.  At their summit last year, the Arab
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the EU tax. EU clients can alternatively authorise the banks to hand over their details to tax authorities in their home country, which can then <head>calculate</head> the exact sum they should pay.  But even though the Swiss-EU accord is meant to cut tax evasion, it has several loopholes.  The withholding tax
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="2"/>
<context>
killed and another 16,000 wounded in attacks by armed groups in the 24 months to March 2005. But it said it was impossible to really <head>calculate</head> the true toll on the civilian population.  Amnesty appealed to religious leaders and other "influential figures" in Iraq to condemn atrocities and resist efforts to
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Up to two billion pounds (3 billion euros, 3.6 billion dollars) could be raised for charities this way, although the precise sum is hard to <head>calculate</head> and would vary according to the formula for defining a dormant account.  It would most likely take 10 or even 15 years of non-use for
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="2"/>
<context>
of the center. The center is named after Liu Hui, an ancient Chinese mathematician living in the 3rd century who was the first person to <head>calculate</head> pi.  The center is jointly sponsored by Nankai University and Tianjin University. The two schools vow to develop the applied mathematics institute into a world-class
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="2"/>
<context>
and notes approaches, the number of enquiries has been growing, he added. "People are even ringing to ask us to check their maths when they <head>calculate</head> deutschemark sums in euros," the spokesman said.    Sixteen years after producing evidence crediting the Chinese with the numeral system, debunking the popular view it was
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="2"/>
<context>
it involved rote learning and "because of this, step-by- step reasoning was lost, and when the rods fell into disuse mathematicians lost the ability to <head>calculate</head> advanced equations, and mathematics declined."   Ottawa gives a new chance to refugees threatened with deportation Source: Agence France Presse  Canada will give some 10,000 asylum
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="2"/>
<context>
asylum who have been rejected but not deported reach around 4,500. From now on, before each person reaches their final appeal, authorities will have to <head>calculate</head> the risk each refugee would face if deported to nations with a known history of torture, arbitrary arrests, and disappearances, said the spokesman.  Until now,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="2"/>
<context>
been diverted for military use. The IAEA wants to measure the fuel rods to determine how long they have been in the reactor and thereby <head>calculate</head> whether any plutonium could have been diverted for military purposes.  On Friday, US Defense Secretary William Perry said North Korea had not diverted any nuclear
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the so-called "unitary tax" formula means that states can treat multinationals as one entity and tax them accordingly. In so doing, it allows them to <head>calculate</head> the company's business operations in individual states as a percentage of worldwide operations to establish its overall tax liability.  The US Federal government and most
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Jane's said. The weekly said that if North Korea succeeded in deploying nuclear tipped missiles, "the status of Taepo Dong is crucial." "Intelligence specialists now <head>calculate</head> that the spent fuel rods removed last month from a North Korean reactor could be used to make as many as four to six devices
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="2"/>
<context>
an oath of office. At the UNESCO ceremony, Rabin warned that "the difficult, more dangerous part" of the peace process had come. "Both sides must <head>calculate</head> their steps slowly, with prudence and care. For a century of hatred does not dissolve suddenly, with a handshake in Washington," he said, referring to
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="2"/>
<context>
with me." Bortolami said: "I may have missed it by a second, but I never thought about the yellow jersey. When I pedal, I don't <head>calculate</head>  Motorola spokesman Alain Bondue was jubilant.  "Hats off to Sean Yates. He did a lot in England, but he still found the resources to win
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="2"/>
<context>
reduce the market risk involved in delays between the date of a transaction and the date on which settlement occurs. With rolling settlement, investors can <head>calculate</head> more easily when they will receive or hand over their money or shares, bringing a degree of predictability into the market and thus reducing volatility.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Eugene Shoemaker, the third co-discoverer of the comet. The Shoemakers and Levy discovered the string of comet fragments March 24, 1993. Scientists were able to <head>calculate</head> the impact time and prepare to observe the blows, but they had no idea what effect the crash would have.  Debate remains heated on what
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="0"/>
<context>
four percent to 3.5 percent. The prime rate is the interest rate banks such as Chase Manhattan charge their best customers. It is used to <head>calculate</head> other rates, including credit card rates and other consumer lending rates.  Chase Manhattan's decision puts the prime rate at its highest level since late 1991,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="0"/>
<context>
a half percentage point to 7.75 percent, the highest in nearly three years. The prime rate, which banks charge their best customers, is used to <head>calculate</head> other interest rates.  The central bank raised the federal funds, or interbank rate, to 4.75 percent, the fifth such rise since February.  The Fed also
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the biggest fall among all sites surveyed, to the level of 1988, it said. The agency surveyed roadside land prices of 370,000 locations nationwide to <head>calculate</head> inheritance and land taxes.  The survey also showed roadside land values fell an average 7.2 percent in residential areas, 18.2 percent in commercial zones and
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="2"/>
<context>
their destinations without entering Osaka. Matsui said: "A lot of people are expected to use the airport. But at the moment it is hard to <head>calculate</head> how many people will actually visit the city of Osaka. Nobody can tell that until the die is cast."  Another concern is a delay in
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="2"/>
<context>
has two other branches in China, in Shenzhen, on the border with Hong Kong, and Shanghai. In order to eliminate seasonal factors, Indosuez does not <head>calculate</head> its half-year comparisons based on figures on June 30, but on the basis of half of the previous year's figures.    The US shuttle Discovery was
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="2"/>
<context>
rate of 10 per second, reflecting off cloud tops, atmospheric particles and the Earth itself. An on-board telescope collected reflected light which allowed scientists to <head>calculate</head> the altitude and density of desert dust, urban smog and other particles in the atmosphere.  The six astronauts were awakened Sunday with a Billy Joel
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="2"/>
<context>
light pulses at clouds, atmospheric particles and the Earth's surface to study the global climate. An on-board telescope collected reflected light which allowed scientists to <head>calculate</head> the altitude and density of desert dust, urban smog and other particles in the atmosphere.  The crew also retrieved a sun-gazing satellite, called the SPARTAN-201,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="2"/>
<context>
"Three Khmer Rouge were killed and two wounded. Some of our soldiers were also wounded," he said. "Now we have to assess the situation and <head>calculate</head> whether we should launch military operations again."  The general said he thought the three foreigners were still alive.  "But my job is not to know
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="2"/>
<context>
universe's expansion, a NASA team said Wednesday. With the Hubble's help, the team led by Carnegie Observatories of Pasadena astronomer Wendy Freedman was able to <head>calculate</head> precisely the distance separating Earth from a far-flung galaxy, M100.  It was found to be 66 million light years from Earth, making it the most
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="2"/>
<context>
age ranged up to 20 billion years. With the Hubble's help, the team led by Carnegie Observatories of Pasadena astronomer Wendy Freedman was able to <head>calculate</head> the distance separating Earth from a far-flung galaxy, M100.  The team targeted M100 because it contains a particular type of star -- a Cepheid --
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="2"/>
<context>
visiting Cairo with a Russian trade delegation, told AFP. The debts are "around 500 million dollars" on each side but "it is very difficult to <head>calculate</head> because the debt was in rubles and dollars, and that was why" the two decided to cancel them, Davidov said.  According to the agreement, which
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="2"/>
<context>
businessmen and hundreds of counts of intimidation ranging from planting bombs to arson. Drug sales, including heroin, net some eight million dollars a year, police <head>calculate</head> Drug addicts in communist times were numbered at several hundred in Bulgaria, now there are more than 20,000.  The gangs prey on churches, monasteries and
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Dan newspaper said in a column on security issues. Foreigners were particularly eager to get hold of "information that helps them work out their investments, <head>calculate</head> prices and put pressure on their Vietnamese partners," the army newspaper warned.  Around 170 seminars had been held in the first 10 months of the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="2"/>
<context>
schism between the political leadership of the country and the armed forces." Within those forces, a crisis of which the fall-out is still impossible to <head>calculate</head> has already begun.  Defence Minister Pavel Grachev, who is at odds with his own military hierarchy, has tried to fire three deputy defence ministers --
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="2"/>
<context>
a rating of AA for the long-term debt in foreign currency and A-1plus for short-term debt in foreign currency. It said that it did not <head>calculate</head> a rating for the long-term and short-term debt in lire.  S and P said that its downgrading of the trend reflected a danger that this
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="2"/>
<context>
a source close to the GCC oil industry. "This, in turn will help stabilise their budgets as it will be less difficult for them to <head>calculate</head> their oil earnings."  Oil prices averaged around 15.90 dollars in 1994 compared with 16.33 dollars in 1993 and 18.44 dollars in 1992. In 1980, they
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="2"/>
<context>
government thinks in German marks, setting official electricity prices and making investment projections in the currency. In store windows goods are advertised in marks. Residents <head>calculate</head> their salaries in marks, which can usually be done in one's head in a country where average monthly pay varies between 15 and 20 marks.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="2"/>
<context>
"Prices are rising every second," said the headlines of the daily Salam. The crisis is also hitting industry and commerce because nobody knows how to <head>calculate</head> prices, officials say.  "Certain traders now prefer not to make sales rather than being landed with rials which may have lost half their value by
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="2"/>
<context>
result of last month's earthquake, the Osaka-based company did not revise its forecast for the year to March. "We have not finished collecting information to <head>calculate</head> damage from the earthquake," said a spokesman for Matsushita, whose headquarters are less than 100 kilometers (62 miles) east of the epicenter of the killer
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="2"/>
<context>
on the Tokyo foreign exchange market at 3 p.m. (0600 GMT) Friday, against the previous day's 91.93-98 yen. Liu acknowledged that it was impossible to <head>calculate</head> the cost of the exchange fluctuations to China -- which began its 30-year loan repayment period in 1989 -- because only a small proportion had
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="2"/>
<context>
construction point in the direction of an overstatement of increases in the cost of living," Greenspan said. Because the CPI index is the basis to <head>calculate</head> increases in a wide range of federal spending, including the basic retirement pension nationwide, any inbuilt inflation in calculating the index itself is incurring huge
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="1"/>
<context>
to consider setting up an independent national commission to review the method of calculating the price index. Changing the method the United States uses to <head>calculate</head> its inflation rate could save the government 150 billion dollars over five years, Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan said Wednesday.  The current method of calculating
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="1"/>
<context>
but many analysts said that risked halting economic growth entirely and sending the country back into recession. Changing the method the United States uses to <head>calculate</head> its inflation rate could save the government 150 billion dollars over five years, Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan said Wednesday.  The current method of calculating
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Kulikov said in an interview with The New York Times in the Chechen capital, Grozny. "The war has its own laws and stages, and we <head>calculate</head> that by the summer period (June 21-September 21), we can establish control of two- thirds of the territory," he said.  This, he added, would allow
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="2"/>
<context>
world is also regarded as a factor in increased CO2 levels, because like all green plants trees absorb carbon dioxide in their photo-synthetic life-process. Scientists <head>calculate</head> that a simple doubling of CO2 concentrations puts up world temperatures by 1.2 degrees, and they say that on present trends the average temperature will
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="2"/>
<context>
daily basis," he said. "That's why we strained to make this offer. "But after the season starts  Sunday night we can't any more <head>calculate</head> what's going to happen. So this offer has got to be accepted by this weekend."  The owners have been proceeding with plans to launch the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Few Russians actually receive the minimum wage, which would be insufficient for general living purposes, but it nonetheless serves as a base on which to <head>calculate</head> various salaries, including those of civil servants, indexed with it.  According to figures drawn up by Finance Minister Vladimir Panskov, lifting the mimimum wage will
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="2"/>
<context>
export profits. "All of which adds up to the need for refom in the tax refund system," it said, warning of "grievous consequences" if exporters <head>calculate</head> tax refunds into their export costs and the government cannot realise the refunds in time.  The country's total foreign trade volume jumped 38.7 percent in
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Sweden was a woman, compared to one out of five nowadays, Dreber said. The advertising campaign recommends an alcohol measuring stick sold at chemists to <head>calculate</head> alcohol intake.   The Iranian currency crashed below the barrier of 5,000 rials to the dollar on Wednesday and has now halved in value since the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the way for a drop in the value of the shekel without a formal devaluation. First the dollar's share in a currency basket used to <head>calculate</head> the value of the shekel, will be increased 3.2 percent to 57.9 percent from June 5.  The share of the German mark, sterling, yen and
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="2"/>
<context>
Cairo and in early August in Gaza. They also drew up an agenda and working procedures. The main problem would be to define "displaced" and <head>calculate</head> how many people qualify.  Israel's chief delegate Yosef Hadas told reporters: "We started today and our talks will go on a long time. Naturally there
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="2"/>
<context>
"nasty spiral of uplifting costs", which would put Britain's competitive position in Europe at risk. Unions at Ford maintain that workers' increased productivity --which they <head>calculate</head> has risen by an average 90 percent over the past 10 years -- has made Ford's British plants some of the most competitive among the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="2"/>
<context>
also offered significant improvements to pension payments. But union leaders unanimously rejected the offer. Unions at Ford maintain that workers' increased productivity -- which they <head>calculate</head> has risen by an average 90 percent over the past 10 years -- has made Ford's British plants some of the most competitive among the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="2"/>
<context>
word "goal" rather than being bound to balancing the budget within seven years. The hint at compromise came over whether economic growth figures used to <head>calculate</head> the budget would come from the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) -- which is under the White House -- or the Congressional Budget Office
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="2"/>
<context>
he added. Asked about the assassination of his predecessor, Yitzhak Rabin, by a Jew opposed to the peace process, Peres acknowledged that "we did not <head>calculate</head> the depth and intensity of this opposition."  "But we will pick up the pieces. A very large majority of the public wants to ensure that
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="2"/>
<context>
An out-of-control Chinese military satellite weighing two tonnes is set to crash land in the first half of next year, and it is impossible to <head>calculate</head> where, a report said Monday.  Aviation Week and Space Technology said the FSW-1 reconnaissance satellite could crash anywhere between latitutes 56.5 degrees north and south,
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="2"/>
<context>
for each bank's problem loans ... is considerably higher," the report said. Another estimate excluding the effect of the subsidy and using other methods to <head>calculate</head> bad loans, the potential losses represent 184 billion dollars, the firm said. It used a dollar-yen rate of 101.46.  Concerns about Japan's banking system have
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="2"/>
<context>
calling members out for a big "action day" on Thursday. The strikes should then affec t all civil service sectors. Economic experts are trying to <head>calculate</head> the damage resulting from the strikes to an economy already showing marked signs of a slowdown. On Wednesday, Economics and Finance Minister Jean Arthuis said
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="2"/>
<context>
remained uninfected for years. They are the subject of intense studies. - Zimbabwe: Three hundred people are dying of AIDS every week, leading businessmen to <head>calculate</head> that 10 percent of the workforce will disappear in the next two years.  - Zambia: Eleven thousand children have died of AIDS since 1985, a
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="2"/>
<context>
to return to work. Additional costs may be incurred in coming months due to contracts lost to competition during the strike. These are impossible to <head>calculate</head> the source said.  Striking workers agreed to end their action after Prime Minister Alain Juppe made a number of key concessions, notably freezing a five-year
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="2"/>
<context>
gathered on Capitol Hill after the session. Gingrich said the key products of the meeting included a presidential commitment to use congressional budget figures to <head>calculate</head> economic growth; Clinton's promise to take part personally in the sessions; and a pledge to get a balanced budget agreement by the end of the
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Banque Nationale de Paris, and Credit Commercial de France all announced the cut to 7.5 percent in the base rate, an indicator generally used to <head>calculate</head> enterprise loans to companies rather than individual borrowing.  The cut is to become effective on Tuesday.  French banks lowered their rates by 0.4 percent to
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Banque Nationale de Paris, and Credit Commercial de France all announced a cut to 7.5 percent in the base rate, an indicator generally used to <head>calculate</head> loans to companies rather than individual borrowing. The cut is to become effective on Tuesday.  Juppe, juggling his way out of another crisis, averted a
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="2"/>
<context>
likely be delayed until the second week of January, the business group said in a statement. The Conference Board said that it was unable to <head>calculate</head> the index, used to predict future US economic performance, because four of the 11 components come from the commerce and labor departments, which have been
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="2"/>
<context>
-- in Staffordshire South East and Hemsworth -- Major's majority could be reduced to just one. And actuaries, who predict mortality rates for pension purposes, <head>calculate</head> four possible Tory deaths in 1996, which would plunge the Conservatives into a voting minority.  Nicholson's defection Friday came a day after Conservative Party chairman
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the independent Sejahtera trade union, told AFP he believed most companies had the money to meet the new wage levels, but because they had to <head>calculate</head> the "invisible costs" into their overheads, workers often missed out.  "I have met many employers who say they want to pay the minimum wage but
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="2"/>
<context>
dues), a Saudi economic newspaper said Wednesday. According to the director of the Zakat agency, Mansur Abdel Ghaffar, quoted by Al-Iqtissadiya, Saudi authorities plan to <head>calculate</head> how much each company must pay based on their declared revenue, capital and employee salaries.  All Moslems must pay dues of 2.5 percent of their
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="2"/>
<context>
capital and employee salaries. All Moslems must pay dues of 2.5 percent of their assets. Companies in Saudi Arabia, which strictly applies Islamic law, now <head>calculate</head> themselves how much they owe the Zakat department.  Saudi officials also on Wedneday announced that the cost of license plates would rise from 200 riyals
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="2"/>
<context>
earthquake or Hurricane Andrew, which cost some 25 billion dollars in output. Diana Cronan of the Air Transport Association said the group has yet to <head>calculate</head> the cost of the storm for airlines but it would include overtime, snow removal, ferrying empty planes, dealing with stranded passengers and lost fares from
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="2"/>
<context>
up and down the eastern US seabord, which suffered a double whammy snow storm that began a week earlier. Other residents were just beginning to <head>calculate</head> the damage caused by a raging blizzard -- the worst in decades -- that prompted disaster declarations in three US states and the federal district
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="2"/>
<context>
as one of the first tests of the North American Free Trade Agreement. The Washington talks were due to focus on a US plan to <head>calculate</head> Mexico's winter tomato import quotas on a weekly rather than quarterly basis. Florida tomato farmers have claimed Mexican winter tomatoes are flooding the market.  On
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="2"/>
<context>
and notes approaches, the number of enquiries has been growing, he added. "People are even ringing to ask us to check their maths when they <head>calculate</head> deutschemark sums in euros," the spokesman said.  Return to your original query  Copyright © 1992-2015 Linguistic Data Consortium, University of Pennsylvania. All Rights Reserved. |
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the Tibetan plateau. Although the study does not address flood levels -- a question that also requires such things as deforestation and river defences to <head>calculate</head> effectively -- Palmer said it was clear that some countries would have to grapple with serious flooding problems.  Bangladesh faces "a double whammy" of more
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="2"/>
<context>
is to provide capability building for developing countries," co-chair and Japan's science and technology minister, Takeo Kawamura, told a closing news conference. "We need to <head>calculate</head> how much funding we need to have," he said.  According to the framework statement, developing countries that have the most to benefit from better forecasting
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="2"/>
<context>
results over a longer term and the expectations of each club. He used a computer to process an astonishing four billion virtual Premiership games to <head>calculate</head> the so-called "trap door level" for each club, below which managers can consider themselves likely to face the boot.  The bad news for Everton's David
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="2"/>
<context>
a terrorist attack are only limited by the imagination of the terrorists themselves. He also said that risk management models used by insurance brokerages to <head>calculate</head> premiums for coverage against natural disasters were no use in forecasting terrorism.  Natural disasters are recurring and follow patterns when observed over a number of
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="2"/>
<context>
is still not achievable." Given the huge task of achieving predictability, the study recommends that resources be devoted more to improving computer models to help <head>calculate</head> how big a future quake will be and what kind of ground motion it is likely to cause.  This would have immediate benefit for people
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="2"/>
<context>
and notes approaches, the number of enquiries has been growing, he added. "People are even ringing to ask us to check their maths when they <head>calculate</head> deutschemark sums in euros," the spokesman said.  Sixteen years after producing evidence crediting the Chinese with the numeral system, debunking the popular view it was
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="2"/>
<context>
it involved rote learning and "because of this, step-by- step reasoning was lost, and when the rods fell into disuse mathematicians lost the ability to <head>calculate</head> advanced equations, and mathematics declined."  China formed its first applied maths research center Saturday in the Tianjin Municipality.  Shiing-shen Chern, a renowned mathematician who is
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="2"/>
<context>
one's marriage plans these days," said Ahmad Awang, president of the Ulama (Religious Scholars') Association of Malaysia. Ahmad suggested that a "formula" be devised to <head>calculate</head> a more realistic sum based on the groom's income to avoid leaving the suitor at the mercy of the prospective bride's family.  The government has
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="2"/>
<context>
such losses included accumulating interest on their deposits of between five and six percent. "It is true that the loss becomes much bigger when you <head>calculate</head> interest on our money. When I started depositing with BCCI seven years ago, my target was to double the money," said BCCI depositor Ibrahim Atteyya.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="2"/>
<context>
the player to establish the exact state of his injuries, incapacity and pain. "The court will then produce a report. On that basis we will <head>calculate</head> the sum involved and press for compensation from Wasps. There is a price for the pain, a price for the scar on Aurelien's neck and
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="2"/>
<context>
be imposed retroactively from December 1991, when the Soviet Union collapsed and the Caucasian republic of Georgia became independent. The lawmakers demanded that the government <head>calculate</head> the amount of taxes due and collect them within three months. The total sum could amount to 700 million dollars (euros).  The Georgian foreign ministry
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="2"/>
<context>
fall to 1.2 percent in 2004, the same ratio as in 2002. The difference in the forecasts results mostly from the new government's decision to <head>calculate</head> 2004 VAT revenue, totalling around 1.0 percent of GDP, in the current year's budget, a senior finance ministry official told reporters on condition of anonymity.
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="2"/>
<context>
which hit the eastern states in September 2003, he said. AIR is a catastrophe modelling company, which uses sophisticated computer programs to help insurance companies <head>calculate</head> losses from disasters such as hurricanes.  Risk Management Solutions, another leading disaster modeller, cut its estimate of insured losses to about five billion dollars from
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="0"/>
<context>
hiked its discount rate from 3.5 to four percent. The prime rate is the interest rate banks charge their best customers. It is used to <head>c</head> other rates, including credit card rates and other consumer lending rates.  A cut in provisions enabled Banque Indosuez of France to increase net profits by
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="2"/>
<context>
schism between the political leadership of the country and the armed forces." Within those forces, a crisis of which the fall-out is still impossible to <head>c</head> has already begun.  Defence Minister Pavel Grachev, who is at odds with his own military hierarchy, has tried to fire three deputy defence ministers --
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="2"/>
<context>
On the London import market, a tonne of white pepper going for about 2,700 dollars a year ago is now fetching 3,850 dollars. British importers <head>c</head> that prices ought to climb a further 10 to 15 percent this year and stay firm at those levels for several years.  The impact has
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="2"/>
<context>
has two other branches in China, in Shenzhen, on the border with Hong Kong, and Shanghai. In order to eliminate seasonal factors, Indosuez does not <head>c</head> its half-year comparisons based on figures on June 30, but on the basis of half of the previous year's figures.
</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
