<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="0"/>
<context>
are a vegetarian it is certainly worthwhile making sure you include other good sources of iron in your diet. You'll need to get your daily iron from eggs (if you're eating them), beans such as baked beans, soya beans and lentils, leafy green veg, dried fruit, and fortified breakfast cereals (check the labels to see which have iron added). Iron from non meat sources is better absorbed by the body if it is eaten with a source of vitamin C, so try to have your cereal with a glass of fresh <head>orange</head> or your lentils with a tomato based sauce and so on. CAN you tell me which type of milk is suitable for my four-year-old daughter? A LITTLE ray of sunshine she isn't. Cute and sweet are not adjectives that readily spring to mind on surveying the stage wardrobe of Andi, the blonde frontwoman of local cover band Sunshine. But then Andi isn't really your average rock babe. Two years ago she traded her long, barbie doll locks for a

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="1"/>
<context>
one of the biggest exhibitions at the fair with 21 towns and holiday attractions taking part. It is not all work for children at Mount Pleasant primary school in Darlington, where children take a caring approach. Distressed by mindless vandalism that destroys trees and flowers they are keeping a watchful eye on plant life. The animal kingdom gets its fair share of attention as children learn how to care for pets. A runaway hamster called Sophie takes pride of place where the school rat once roamed. And they learn to care for themselves with a sociable cafe selling <head>orange</head> and biscuits before home-time every Friday. Lynne Humes has taken time off work as a staff nurse at Darlington Memorial Hospital to start a family, and her son Anthony was born in January. The NHS is one of the main election issues for Lynne, who says she has seen many changes in the service over the last ten years.' Some were for the better but a lot were for worse. Lack of funds has been a big problem, especially for research, but it always has

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="2"/>
<context>
recalls a vanished age of acting with her effortless sense of style and superb ability to turn a line to perfection, while Jean Marsh brings a moving sense of both hurt and hope to the role of Miss Madrigal. There's a superb comic performance from Robert Austin as the hilariously touchy yet deeply sympathetic manservant Maitland, and outstanding work, too, from the 15-year-old Kellie Bright as Laurel, an alarmingly forward yet painfully vulnerable child who announces that her mother' is so overloaded with sex that it sparkles'. Following the <head>orange</head> Tree's fine revival of Rodney Ackland's The Dark River, this production offers further persuasive evidence that there was far more vitality in the English theatre before the arrival of the angry young men and the Royal Court revolution than is generally acknowledged. 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="3"/>
<context>
and Cajun and Creole from New Orleans are some of the native cuisines worth sampling, while lobster can be gorged in New England for a fraction of the U.K. price. The day starts with the great American breakfast, which, if you haven't managed to get as part of your hotel deal, should be eaten in a local coffee shop or diner and will set you back $3-$4 for eggs, bacon, toast and unlimited coffee. Add two dollars for freshly squeezed <head>orange</head> juice. This is quite enough until lunchtime when you might hunt down some dim sum, steamed pork buns and the like for $1-$2 a basket in the local Chinatown, or hit the deli for another American institution, the sandwich. By' sandwich' we're not talking undernourished British Rail. A good Americansandwich will be a Dagwood Bumstead special -- at least six inches long, four multi-layered inches high and need two hands to control it. As for an evening meal, the golden rule is that

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="2"/>
<context>
John Steinbeck's saga of the Depression years was a political hot potato when Hollywood mogul Darryl F Zanuck sought to film it in 1940. He skirted the problem by turning it, via Nunnally Johnson's script, from a radical rallying cry into a depiction of the common man's ability to survive injustice by endurance. Aspects of the novel were changed. The screenplay drops Steinbeck's somewhat pretentious literary device of interspersing the story of the Joad family (poor farmers trekking from the Oklahoma dust bowl to the false promise of the California <head>orange</head> groves) with abstract chapters pontificating on the state of the world. Also abandoned was the grandiose ending, in which Rose of Sharon, whose baby has died, breast feeds a starving stranger. The film covers only the first two-thirds of the book but is dramatically more satisfying because it is the story of Tom Joad's political awakening. From a hot-head who has done time for killing a man, he develops into a union organiser who discovers the eloquence his new role demands. There is a Biblical

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="4"/>
<context>
in the Calypso bar at Chania carries a smiling blond baby on one hip, and my Cretan breakfast in one hand. For about 2 there are tomatoes, olives, bread, cheese, a sausage, a boiled egg, a nectarine, and a bowl of yoghurt, honey and sultanas, <head>orange</head> juice and mountain herb tea. All is fresh, local and utterly delicious. The tea is made of malotira and, I'm sure, peppermint. This herb has tiny leaves here, and is furiously strong: I made tea from some herbs I picked, put in a generous sprig of peppermint, and spat out the result in shock. At the north-western tip of the island I picked malotira, on the long empty golden beach of Phalasarna, thinking from its exotic perfume that I was gathering

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="6">
<answer instance="6" senseid="5"/>
<context>
pretty well. French influence was limited. They left alone the old town with its souks, square, palaces and its impressive Koutoubia minaret. Instead they built their handsome new town with its wide tree-lined boulevards, outside the city walls. One policy still enforced means that all but Moslems are banned from entering the mosques. The most noticeable French legacies are their language and their food. Breakfast at a pavement table in the new town is a leisurely Gallic affair. A croissant warm from the oven, a cup of good coffee and a tumbler of just-squeezed <head>orange</head> juice costs under 1. An a la carte three-course supper for two with a bottle of very drinkable Moroccan red at, say, Le Petit Poucet comes to 10 all in. It's the sort of shabby restaurant you can still find in France: radishes and butter and spiced olives for nibbles, enormous roses plonked on the table and football on the TV in a back room are the setting for the very best pommes frites and memorable dishes of brains a beurre blanc and kidneys in garlic.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="7">
<answer instance="7" senseid="5"/>
<context>
many thousands of Soviet Jews are emigrating to their spiritual home. Ian Black in Tel Aviv asks whether Israel, willing but hardly prepared for the influx, can cope. VALERY and Ina and their children were visibly tired as they traipsed into the Ministry of Immigrant Absorption reception hall at Ben Gurion Airport. It had been a long, slow journey from Odessa and although it was already 1am there were still many more official forms to fill out before their new life in Israel could begin. Victoria, aged 12, made a beeline for the reconstituted <head>orange</head> juice and sandwiches prepared by a pair of stout volunteer ladies who arrived from Russia themselves a few years back, and two-year-old Oleg was soon roaring about wildly on a plastic fire-engine in the playroom. There were about 100 of them on Sunday's evening flight from Bucharest to Tel Aviv, unmistakably Soviet with their fur hats, cheap wintry clothes and suitcases and quiet, mechanical submission to the first taste of Israeli bureaucracy. Fair-haired Jews from Moscow and Leningrad mingled with olive-skinned Georgians to read the Cyrillic slogans welcoming

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="8">
<answer instance="8" senseid="2"/>
<context>
range of malt whiskies sitting in the window.' Based on market research, we're locating the new Wine Racks to target the more affluent, urban areas.' We want to focus more on wine, less on the traditional off-licence with its wider range of fags and beers,' continues Waters, undeterred. On cue, customer number four walks off dangling a six-pack of Castlemaine XXXX. A fifth customer, a young man with baby in sling, wanders in. Yuppie profile, surely. He buys a can of cider. A sixth selects <head>orange</head> juice and Perrier. As we discuss the changing role of the traditional high-street off-licence, it is all too plain that none of the first six customers have browsed or bought wine or done what the market research says they should be doing. But then a man in a suit heads for the cool cabinet and picks out two bottles of champagne. At last. We're in business. On the morning I met Tim Waters to talk about Thresher's plans for the development of its off-licences, few customers

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="9">
<answer instance="9" senseid="6"/>
<context>
Our guests are looking for a comfortable, clean bedroom first of all,' says sales manager Joanna Honey MHCIMA. Regular Holiday Inn guests also get added extras.' We do try and do things a little differently for them like giving them complementary fruit and maybe upgrading them to an executive room.' Added value is created in executive rooms by offering a larger bed in a larger room, a mini bar, complimentary <head>orange</head> juice and mineral water, bathrobes, satellite TV and a high level of decor and soft furnishings. According to Honey it's these little touches that make a big difference.' People also want to feel more at home which is why facilities like tea and coffee, perhaps a minibar and, in some of our hotels, satellite TV, are widely expected.' While we can never offer a real home from home, guests come knowing that they can get some of the comforts of home 

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="10">
<answer instance="10" senseid="0"/>
<context>
I followed Portia Forbes's progress along it through Tom's eyes. They never left her.' She isn't happy with the selection,' he said.' I wonder if she's even been down here before. With a figure like that one would hardly take her for a chips and stodge consumer. She's arguing with the serving woman who's lifted all the lids from the hot dishes to show her the succulent variety. None of it will do. She's settled for some biscuits and cheese and a yoghurt and a glass of <head>orange</head> juice.' As his commentary stopped I realised that she must have completed her purchases and was very likely surveying the room for somewhere to sit. Tom's head sank into his shoulders, as if he were trying to make himself invisible, but his eyes remained restlessly curious. The next moment I heard the confident heel taps behind me. She was coming up the central passage between the rows of tables. Tom seemed to freeze. I wondered if she would join us.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="11">
<answer instance="11" senseid="0"/>
<context>
flavoured milks, fruit juices and biscuits. Mosat flavoured milks are made with skimmed milk but these banana, strawberry and chocolate milks are made with full fat milk, recommended for toddlers because it is a good source of calcium. The juices are sold in packs of three and come in a choice of apple and banana, grape and <head>orange</head>, and apple and blackcurrant flavours. These are made with concentrated fruit juices, and contain added vitamin C, with no added sugar. The teddy bear shaped biscuits, available in chocolate and honey and oats varieties, contain added iron for growing children.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="12">
<answer instance="12" senseid="7"/>
<context>
rely more on the author's experience and on the collective experience of his colleagues. This is not too unscientific or random an approach, as it is often found that one can do an experiment in a defined situation and reinforce one's findings by consulting one's colleagues about their own experience. The difference in the selection of vocabulary in different courses can be quite marked, as is also the case with grading and recycling. Word counts can show remarkable discrepancies in the vocabulary control that is typical; for instance they may contain strawberry but not <head>orange</head>. Choice of themes and situations is governed by religious, cultural and educational considerations of the country of countries for which the course is planned. Some things can be talked about, others can't. In language presentation and practice there should be a story of some kind or a series of anecdotes or incidents. A business course should, naturally, have a string of business situations and a science course should have plenty of scientific vocabulary. Another consideration is the use of humour, which should be at

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="13">
<answer instance="13" senseid="8"/>
<context>
Having your own original opinions was clearly a major flaw in a mirza and, just to be on the safe side, the Mirza Nama offers a few acceptable opinions for the young gentleman to learn by heart and adopt as his own. Among flowers and trees he should admire the narcissus, the violet and the <head>orange</head>. He should eat his fill of watermelon (' the best of all fruits') and' rice boiled with spices should be preferred by him to all other eatables.' A gentleman' should not make too much use of tobacco' but' should recognize the Fort in Agra as unequalled in the whole world and... must think of Isfahan as the best town in Persia'; if he insists on travelling he should visit' Egypt because it is worth seeing'. Finally, the Mirza

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="14">
<answer instance="14" senseid="2"/>
<context>
I am not sure which is the more enjoyable: to win an argument or to annihilate the opponent. Instead of building a case for ourselves we attack the opponent or his case. Attack is rather easy. We choose our frame of reference and attack something for not fitting it. We can attack an <head>orange</head> for not being an apple. No matter what is being done we attack it for not being enough. No matter how worthwhile a project seems we attack it for the hidden and sinister purposes behind it. If something is done that benefits a particular group then that group is being bribed or bought off. If something is couched in general terms then it is too vague and ill-defined. If something is popular then people are being conned. If something is unpopular then it is being forced on people.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="15">
<answer instance="15" senseid="6"/>
<context>
I pulled it free and found it to be sand-frosted and pear-shaped, like the one Nicky had shown me. A present for Joan. By then the worst of the day was over and things became easier, as I later recorded: Frenchman stopped. Black/grey beard, kind eyes. Told me I'd come 5 kilometres. Three miles in three hours. Sang' Hallelujah Chorus' and the Rolling Stones'' You can make it if you try'. Stopped at 1100 for dates and an <head>orange</head>. Nothing to drink all morning as yet. Approaching the crags we've seen for a couple of days. Undulating scenery, sandy patches. Occasionally would hear the cart rumble as the ground became firm. Thanked God I could see all my friends, relatives, all the old ladies, Joan and the kids in my daydreams. Felt v. contented but tired. 1230 lunch, carrots, dates, dry bread. Boys drove past 7 miles in 5 hours. I said make it 14.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="16">
<answer instance="16" senseid="4"/>
<context>
If you're watching calories as well as alcohol, use diet or low-calorie mixers and artificial sweetener. Pink Fizz Mix the juice of 1 lemon with 1 pints/1 litre tonic, about 2 tbsp of grenadine and sugar to taste. Fruit fizz Mix together the juice of 1 lemon, about pint/200ml each of <head>orange</head> juice, pineapple juice and grapefruit juice. Top up with pint/450ml of soda water. Melon sling Cut of a small green melon in pieces and soak in 1 to 2 tbsp ginger wine or syrup. Add bottle Sainsbury's alcohol-free wine and 1 pint/600ml soda water.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="17">
<answer instance="17" senseid="0"/>
<context>
trace elements so essential to optimum health. I do not wish to enter into the rights and wrongs of meat consumption versus vegetarianism or alcohol consumption versus abstention. That is a matter for personal belief and conscience alone. All I am trying to show is that it is possible to improve your general health and your sense of well-being by paying greater attention to what you put into your mouth and body. It isn't easy for any of us today to be sure that we are getting all the vitamins that we need. The writing on a carton of <head>orange</head> juice may tell you that it contains a certain amount of vitamin C -- but did you know that the vitamin C content starts to decrease from the moment the carton is opened? If you are drinking from it two or three days later, even if it has been refrigerated, the vitamin C has probably disappeared altogether. If you are unsure about the adequacy of your daily diet, look at the list of symptoms below. If any of them apply to you, it is possible that you are

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="18">
<answer instance="18" senseid="5"/>
<context>
You know you'll always receive a warm and friendly welcome. And whether you are dining in the restaurant or relaxing at the bar, our helpful staff want to make sure you really enjoy your visit. And you will, especially when you see what's new on the menu this summer. Beefeater menus change to match the season, so here's a preview of some of the special dishes and wines we'll be featuring from June 10th alongside traditional favourites. Start with our Fresh Melon -- a quarter of juicy honeydew melon, served with a twisted <head>orange</head> slice and strawberry garnish. Or Seafood Salad -- a delicious combination of prawns, smoked salmon and crab pieces on a bed of mixed salad. Served with a dipper pot of seafood sauce and brown bread and butter. To follow why not try our new Rump Steak with Seafood Kebab -- a delicious combination of a succulent 5oz rump steak cooked to your liking and a chargrill flavoured seafood kebab of swordfish, tuna, scallop, prawns, red and green peppers. Served with mushrooms.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="19">
<answer instance="19" senseid="6"/>
<context>
Follow the basic suggestions for perfuming rooms as outlined on page 105. Any of the perfume blends suggested earlier can also be used to subtly influence the mood of the occupants within a room. Here are a few more ideas: to jolly up a winter's party, try a mixture of cinnamon bark, cloves and <head>orange</head>. Lavender, clary-sage and chamomile will aid restful sleep. For meditation, yoga or for a philosophical discussion, try a blend of frankincense, myrrh and cedarwood. A children's party will go down well with a background fragrance of bergamot, lemon, and perhaps a touch of geranium. Finally, if you are trying to sell your house, but without much success, aromatherapy may be the answer. Next time a prospective buyer comes to view, make sure the kitchen is scented with

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="20">
<answer instance="20" senseid="5"/>
<context>
The theatre had two windows, between which was a table. In front of this table were four rows of benches, slightly raised one above the other. The lecturer stood between the table and the wall -- the worst possible position. The room was badly ventilated, and the floor was strewn with nut shells and <head>orange</head> peel. It is reported that the window blinds had been indecently defaced with coloured chalk. It sounds most depressing. Supplementing this account of the College shortly after the Coleman regime comes one written late in life by Principal Simonds, describing the College and its environs in 1828-1829, when he was a student there.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="21">
<answer instance="21" senseid="5"/>
<context>
finally he slumped over into sleep. I came to know the mother's breasts well. She left one out as both she and the baby dozed; or she placed the baby on the table and lifted a breast to its mouth. It was impressive how she coped with the two children for the twelve hours to Juliaca while her boorish husband slept, the baby's shawl across his face. Like most of the Peruvian children I had seen, the toddler appeared self-sufficient already. She made few demands on her parents but sat quietly, playing with an <head>orange</head> in a plastic mug. A quarter of Peruvian children die before their first birthday and those who survived, it seemed, learned early not to expect anything; there were never any toys. Though she had the liquid brown eyes, the shiny black hair of a child, already this toddler had the little rough hands of a campesina. The landscape changed from the lushness of the Urubamba valley into the sweeping emptiness of bare hills, the sky holding the rare fleck of a red-backed hawk or the huge

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="22">
<answer instance="22" senseid="3"/>
<context>
In fact, I needed to look no further than the ground below me. At three o'clock, when I had scanned every crack in the ridge, every curve of every dune, every patch of colour on the plain, I looked down and saw an ant, crawling into the wind. It was carried back on the blowing sand, but it moved unhurriedly forward. At home I might have fed it to the fish, but here I felt sorry for it and watched until it was time to move on. When I was putting the <head>orange</head> juice bottle back into the wheelbarrow, an empty plastic bag was blown out of the locker and soared towards Morocco, like a racing pigeon from a basket. I had visions of a nomad's only camel eating it and dying, so I gave chase, watching the dust from my feet overtake me. The bag was increasing its lead, almost out of view, when it arced and plummeted like a kite above the beach and was slammed against a rock. I reached it, peeled it off

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="23">
<answer instance="23" senseid="9"/>
<context>
though not of many years standing and keep pace with the other kinds of Pines and Firs in the same plantation'. When Kalm visited Miller, they discussed cultivation of trees, particularly conifers, and he was told that at Woburn larches had been planted' some in good soil, some in meagre' and the latter' looked very lively, while the former looked quite drooping, as though they were obliged reluctantly to force themselves to grow'. There was correspondence with Woburn over the construction of a shelter for <head>orange</head> trees, to be added to an existing wall, with a moveable roof erected every autumn. The glass for this could, Miller suggested, be of inferior quality for the top, but the front should be' glaz'd with new Castle Glass'. Miller was conscious of economy and recognised that from an aesthetic viewpoint the Duke must be gratified, but felt that good use could be made of cheaper material elsewhere. During the eighteenth century the second and third Dukes of Richmond planted many trees at

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="24">
<answer instance="24" senseid="9"/>
<context>
White called on Miller at Chelsea and took due note of the correct procedure. Not long afterwards his hotbeds produced' fine, large, beautiful fruit, just like Miller's' and so six years of patience were rewarded. In the seventeen-forties Philip Miller acted as adviser to the Fourth Duke of Bedford at his Woburn estate. There are five letters written by Miller within fifteen months in 1748-9 to Robert Butcher, Chief Agent at Bedford House in Bloomsbury Square. Apparently indisposition had, in March 1748 prevented him from working on a plan for winter shelter of <head>orange</head> trees. By July he hoped to be able to meet Butcher at Cheam, a property where the fourth Duke had spent his early married life; but only if the weather proved favourable,' for I have had the Rheumatism so bad of late, as to make me fearful of riding in the wet'. In the following May, Miller again reported illness, being just recovered from a fever and subsequent attack of rheumatism, so wished to postpone a visit to Woburn. However, this must

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="25">
<answer instance="25" senseid="10"/>
<context>
the mirror eastern corrie of the one gained by the Bridge of Orchy route. A route not to take unless you know no fear, is to walk straight up the sweeping southern flanks of the hill, which will leave you giddy and hanging on to craggy, near-vertical terrain with your teeth. The sweeping contours of the hill at that point have always reminded me of a huge wave about to break, and it's an uncomfortable thought trying to imagine where you might stop for lunch, and what would happen if you dropped your <head>orange</head>. But by walking up to the eastern corrie, Coire an Dothaidh, fear is not an issue; only leg muscle. It's a fast ascent on to the bealach, and then a right turn takes you on to a surprising flat little plateau sporting a tiny circular lochan. In accordance with my usual run of luck, I climbed up into thick mist, and being too lazy and smug to take a bearing I followed what seemed to be a well-worn path heading in the right direction for

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="26">
<answer instance="26" senseid="10"/>
<context>
in an uncompromising, almost perfect horseshoe. The other was the huge and spectacular sweep of Beinn Dorain's west slopes that towered above the railway line giving scale to its forbidding gradient. We rarely saw its summit, lost as it would be in thick mist, but its mystery made it all the more attractive and seductive. My brother and I would imagine all manner of things to be lurking at the top, from demons' castles to wizards and fairies. Touching to think that as we did so, the reality was probably a few bits of <head>orange</head> peel and a walker in a woollen hat eating a cheese sandwich. So it was naturally with great affection and nostalgia that as an adult I laced up my boots on a damp October morning at the starting point in the station car park at Bridge of Orchy, in preparation to find out what really lurked at the top of Beinn Dorain. I've always found the settlements on the A82 between Crianlarich and Glencoe most peculiar. Crianlarich, Tyndrum and Bridge of Orchy are melancholy, stranded little hamlets that

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="27">
<answer instance="27" senseid="3"/>
<context>
give a telephone number where you can be contacted. It is sometimes beneficial to compare our industry with other service industries. When you look at the way our railways are run, we can only be grateful that British Rail no longer owns hotels, particularly when you recall what a wonderful training ground the old British Transport Hotels used to be. Imagine a hotel where the service changed without warning and the staff had no idea what was happening. It is 8am. You are looking for coffee, <head>orange</head> juice, toast. And what do you get? An announcement. We apologise to customers for the cancellation of breakfast owing to: repair work in the kitchen, staff shortages, a fatality in the cold room, the non-arrival of deliveries. You approach the reception desk:' Where can I go for breakfast?' you ask.'' s closed.'' What do you mean by' s closed?'' I mean there's no breakfast.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="28">
<answer instance="28" senseid="1"/>
<context>
The resulting irritation causes scratching which allows transfer of eggs to the fingers and fingernails. Eggs can then be easily transferred to the mouth by finger sucking or nail biting, causing reinfection, and spread to other members of the family by direct contact or via food, towels and bedlinen etc. Threadworms only affect humans, they do not affect pets. Threadworms are very easy to treat. There is now a simple one tablet treatment available from your pharmacy called OVEX TM. The tablet is <head>orange</head> flavoured, sugar free and chewable so it is suitable for children, although it should not be used for infants under 2 years of age. A single tablet of OVEX TM will kill threadworms. However it may not destroy all the eggs, which can cause reinfection. It is therefore recommended that a second tablet of OVEX TM is taken after 2 weeks. OVEX TM must not be taken by women who are or think they may be pregnant

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="29">
<answer instance="29" senseid="6"/>
<context>
by prevention, which will involve you actively looking at your lifestyle and seeing what you can do to help yourself (pages 12-13). How You Can Help To Relieve An Attack. Even if an attack begins at night, don't turn over and try to ignore it. Start trying to help yourself as soon as you feel an attack coming on. Dealing with Cystitis early gives you a greater chance of clearing it up. Start drinking plenty of bland liquids such as water, milk, weak tea or <head>orange</head> squash, and aim to drink at least eight pints a day. Try one of the Cystitis treatments which are available from your pharmacy without prescription. One of these is Cystopurin, which takes the form of a course of six sachets which mix with water to make alkalising drinks. These drinks work to counteract the acidity of your urine, which will ease the burning sensation on passing water, and also help to stop any bacteria in the bladder

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="30">
<answer instance="30" senseid="7"/>
<context>
We were out for an airing with Air Hanson this week. As we bopped up and down over Hampshire in the world's quietest helicopter, the McDonnell-Douglas 520, we were told the story of a former Luftwaffe pilot, now aged 65, who still ferries little propeller craft across the pond from America to England. He is Dieter Schmidt and his secret recipe keeps him awake for the 20-hour flights. Apparently, he drinks two pints of milk and, as soon as he feels drowsy, he drinks two pints of <head>orange</head> juice. The two don't mix and the indigestion makes sure he is still alert enough to touch down at Blackbushe. M1 drivers, please take note. BELIEVE it or not, there's a take-out Chinese restaurant in Charlton, Massachusetts called, Khant Gho Wong. No knight at the opera THE determined but unpopular Jeremy Isaacs, yet to achieve a gong, has been upsetting the Establishment with his high-handed behaviour at the Royal Opera House to such an extent that there is now a new

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="31">
<answer instance="31" senseid="8"/>
<context>
the sunshine. All the bedrooms are served by a lift the have private facilities and a balcony. Rooms sleep 2 or 3. Some single rooms are also available. This wonderful' White coast' has one of the best sunshine records in Europe, with mid-summer temperatures pushing the high 90's and miles and miles of long golden sandy beaches fringed by the sparkling Mediterranean sea. This popular corner of Spain has something of everything for everyone. The rugged mountains and hills form an impressive backdrop, and inland peaceful villages look out across <head>orange</head> and lemon groves. Alicante is the provincial capital and is full of attractive and trendy shops (great for clothes) and also has a marvellous seafront promenade. Just six minutes away is the beautiful picturesque old village of Altea where a lovely old church stands on the top of a hill. The village square has interesting market stalls selling local handmade crafts, and nearby Albir offers a range of watersports and a fabulous stretch of coastline. The weather on this coast is delightful and there are bright lights and

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="32">
<answer instance="32" senseid="8"/>
<context>
view, most have balconies. Rooms sleep 2, 3 or 4. Meals: Bed and breakfast or self catering. The Paloma Blanca is a fabulous hotel for those wanting to combine relaxing, sun-soaked days with lively nights. It is only 500 metres from the centre of Dassia with its array of cocktail bars, pubs and discos. Stroll into town and you'll find a great choice of restaurants serving all types of food from traditional Greek and international food to typical English. The ideal location of the Paloma Blanca, set amidst <head>orange</head> trees and attractive gardens means you can enjoy the best of both worlds -- daytime relaxation and night-time life. Daytimes can also be spent on the beach at Dassia, soaking up the sunshine or taking advantage of the excellent watersports available. Or, you can simply relax at the hotel as it offers excellent amenities for a comfortable holiday. A focal point is the inviting, good-sized pool where you can cool off from the heat of the sun. The Paloma Blanca has its own tennis courts where friendly tournaments

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="33">
<answer instance="33" senseid="8"/>
<context>
facilities set amidst lawns and terraces. A good choice for a family holiday. Aptly named' The Sun Coast of Spain', the Costa del Sol has almost two hundred miles of golden beaches, interrupted here and there by cliffs plunging spectacularly into the deep blue Mediterranean. Along the road from Malaga to Gibraltar, there are some of Europe's most fashionable shops, lively nightlife, restaurants, bars and cafs galore -- a galaxy of fun and excitement in the coastal resorts. Further inland, the gentle hills, olive and <head>orange</head> groves give way to magnificent Sierra Nevada and the sleepy white-washed villages of old Andalucia -- land of the flamenco, strumming guitars and fiery fiestas. A wonderful combination of holiday activity and local tradition all within reach of the sun-soaked beaches. A sophisticated harbour just outside Marbella with a superb selection of fashionable bars, restaurants and nightclubs. An astonishing group of palaces and fortresses built in Spain by the Moors and now a legacy of their

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="34">
<answer instance="34" senseid="0"/>
<context>
shone through the dark sky, showing Santa the way to everybody's houses. The reindeers just would not have managed without him on this dark Christmas Eve, they would have got lost. When they had finished delivering all the presents, the reindeers returned to Greenland and Randolph went straight to bed, happily, because it was quite late for a reindeer. The next morning, on Christmas Day, Randolph woke up very early, and very excitedly walked over his stocking. He quickly tipped out the contents: an apple, a new scarf, an <head>orange</head>, reindeer money, a new game and... nothing else. Randolph's heart sank, after all, he thought that he deserved a red nose after all the hard work he did last night, helping the other reindeers to deliver presents. Just then he heard a knock at his door, Randolph wondered who it could be. He opened it and there stood Santa in his doorway.' Hello Randolph, how are you feeling after last night?' asked Santa.' Oh, not too

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="35">
<answer instance="35" senseid="7"/>
<context>
At the capitalization party a number of well-wishers had wandered in from the various Labour movement campaigns and organizations which shared the Caxton House office block with NoS. One of them had been Keith Sutton, taking a break from editing the anti-Murdoch strike paper, the Wapping Post, in the office below. Hayling had seemed unusually pleased to see him and offered him some champagne. Sutton, who had gone teetotal, refused.' You've done the easy bit, Alan,' he joked, sipping <head>orange</head> juice.' Now all you've got to do is produce the paper.' It was an obvious remark to make, but Sutton was surprised by the response.' Well,' Hayling whispered with a twinkle in his eye,' that's largely going to be up to you, mate!'

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="36">
<answer instance="36" senseid="2"/>
<context>
have come through verges on the criminal,' said children's health writer Dr Tim Lobstein. COW and Gate insist that there's no added sugar in their baby drinks.' You'll only find the sugar that's naturally in the fruit,' said spokesman Elon Newton. Colmans, who make Robinsons and Delrosa drinks, say their products are vital for many babies.' We don't accept that our products damage teeth as long as they're used properly,' said spokesman Nick Attenborough. SmithKline Beecham said' BabyRibena has less sugar than fresh <head>orange</head> juice.' A Milupa spokesman said: offer a refreshing drink when additional fluids are required.' And Boots spokeswoman Lorraine Gwinnutt said:' Our juice packs carry warnings never to use them with a dummy or soother. When baby's first teeth appear we advise parents to brush the child's teeth after a drink.' So what SHOULD you give a baby to drink? Up to four months: Even on a hot day breastfed babies won't need any other drinks. Bottle-fed babies might like

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="37">
<answer instance="37" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Apple pye with custard all on the top', and' clouted cream' was' the most acceptable entertainment that could be made me'. She also wrote that most parts of Herefordshire and Somerset were very' fruitful of orchards'. She watched cider pressing and said' they pound their apples then lay fresh straw on the press, and on that a good lay of pulp of the apples, then turneth the ends of the straw over it all round'. To be a little more adventurous with apple pies try mixing shortcrust pastry with grated <head>orange</head> or lemon rind and juice instead of water. Or top your pies with meringue for a change. Use a pint of stewed apple instead of water when making apricot jelly. Make an apple crumble crunchier with cornflakes or bran with crystallised ginger. Try apples in your curries and salads. Usually you will need a little more sugar if using cooking apples. My first impression of what is now my home was the apple-scented spare room. Here my grandmother used to store some of her apple crop. Each

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="38">
<answer instance="38" senseid="8"/>
<context>
Built as a Dominican monastery in the 14th century, this is now a majestic hotel of world renown in a setting of rare appeal. The original cloisters are now a charming, shady walkway around an inner courtyard, the monks' cells now luxurious bedrooms. The hotel is 650 feet above the sea, set in lush gardens of flowers, palms and <head>orange</head> trees. There is an elegant restaurant and a piano bar. The air-conditioned bedrooms have TV, mini-bar, and front sea view. Price includes dinner (or lunch), bed and breakfast. The hotel is unsuitable for children. Beach charges not included.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="39">
<answer instance="39" senseid="8"/>
<context>
Start inland with Pompeii and Herculaneum, the two ancient cities buried by the eruption of Mount Vesuvius in AD 79. Then there is lively, brash and colourful Naples Iaden with museums and priceless treasures, or a short steamer or hydrofoil ride away -- Capri and Ischia. Try the' Amalfi Drive' along the cliffside, among olive trees and citrus groves, to enchanting towns like Amalfi, Positano or Ravello. Stroll among streets lined with <head>orange</head> trees in Sorrento, take a horse-drawn' carrozza' ride or simply admire the fabulous views. Visit the Royal Palace and formal gardens of Caserta, designed to rival Versailles, or wonder at the crater of Mount Vesuvius and Solfatara. Further afield is the' Eternal City' -- Rome, crammed with historic landmarks, and alive with an energetic lust for life, all accessible for a day trip.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="40">
<answer instance="40" senseid="7"/>
<context>
the sake of argument that it is five different partners on the same night. Now if I were to suggest to you that in some gay bars the' lads' pop off to the toilets that number of times to indulge themselves, then you might think I was repeating lurid propaganda put about by the puritan league. Not so. The figure was mentioned to me by the manager of a gay bar who was justifying the role of the establishment, but added,' some of them are not angels you know. They come in here for one <head>orange</head> juice and they're up and down to the loos five times in one night with different blokes.' If that is not over the score I do not know what is. I am resisting the temptation to thunder about AIDS being a judgment upon them, etc. Brutality and callousness are never justified, even in response to disgusting conduct. Many homosexuals are gentle and loving people who have neither physical nor promiscuous relationships. There is also apparently no link between homosexuality and child abuse, although most normal

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="41">
<answer instance="41" senseid="11"/>
<context>
history, describing their arrival in' a low parlour' of this two-storeyed house, to be greeted with tea from a silver service. Supper was as lavish as they had yet had in Scotland:' A large dish of minced beef collops, a large dish of fricassee of fowl, I believe a dish called fried chicken or something like it, a dish of ham or tongue, some excellent haddocks, some herrings, a large bowl of rich milk, frothed, as good a bread-pudding as I ever tasted, full of raisin and lemon or <head>orange</head> peel, and sillabubs made with port wine and in sillabub glasses. There was a good table-cloth with napkins; china, silver spoons, porter if we chose it, and a large bowl of very good punch.' When Boswell awoke on Wednesday, 8 September, the wind had died, but the rain persisted. It eventually cleared and after breakfast they prepared to go to Raasay; they would see the Mackinnons again in two weeks or so. Boswell's account says they rode two miles to

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="42">
<answer instance="42" senseid="4"/>
<context>
various fruit farms dotted around. Disappointingly strawberries do not freeze so if you do not eat them at once you need to use them up in some other way.Home-made strawberry jam is particularly delicious but there are plenty of recipes around which centre on this scrummy fruit. ICED STRAWBERRY SOUFFLE (Serves 4 to 6) 3 level tsps powdered gelatine; 4 tbsp <head>orange</head> juice; 2 oz granulated sugar; 8 oz cleaned, hulled strawberries; pint double cream, lightly whipped; 3 egg whites, whipped until stiff but not dry. Put the gelatine and lemon juice in the top of a double saucepan over hot water, or in a cup standing in a pan of hot water. Set over a low heat and stir the gelatine constantly until it dissolves. Add the sugar and as soon as it has dissolved, set the liquid aside to cool a little. Meanwhile, press the strawberries into a large bowl through a nylon or aluminium sieve. Stir in the gelatine mixture and fold in the whipped cream. Cover the bowl and put it into the fridge

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="43">
<answer instance="43" senseid="11"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> juice that is pasteurized and then sold to consumers without having been concentrated is labeled as "not from concentrate". Just as "from concentrate" processing, most "not from concentrate" processing reduces the natural flavor from the juice. The largest producers of "not from concentrate" use a production process where the juice is placed in aseptic storage, with the oxygen stripped from it, for up to a year.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="44">
<answer instance="44" senseid="12"/>
<context>
McCollum became the unofficial nutritionist of the nation beginning in the early 1920&#8217;s when he heavily promoted the life-extending and healing capabilities of vitamins and warned against the deadly effects of a vitamin-deficient diet. This &#8220;Vitamania&#8221; gave producers the perfect marketing opportunity. The National Fruit Growers Exchange, under the Sunkist brand, created a national campaign promoting drinking daily doses of <head>orange</head> juice for its &#8220;health giving vitamins and rare salts and acids.&#8221; But McCollum soon cast aside vitamins in favor of acid. McCollum ignited a panic over a nebulous condition called acidosis: an excess of acid in the bloodstream which supposedly caused fatigue and lassitude. He claimed the ailment was brought on by consuming meat, eggs and bread, which were acid producers.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="45">
<answer instance="45" senseid="11"/>
<context>
During World War II the U.S. Department of Agriculture encouraged Florida citizens to do their wartime duty and increase production of food staples such as <head>orange</head>s. But the government soon recognized a larger problem: American soldiers were rejecting the vitamin C-packed lemon crystals included in their food rations&#8212;they simply didn&#8217;t taste very good. The government needed to fulfill the nutritional needs of soldiers and ward off scurvy with a tasty and transportable vitamin C product.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="46">
<answer instance="46" senseid="3"/>
<context>
The post-war American Dream was an image of domestic serenity in which the national talent for creating labor-saving technology was realized. Americans were eating better for less money and in less time. &#8220;Fresh-frozen&#8221; <head>orange</head> juice was concentrated health stuffed into a can and its only preparation requirements were thawing, adding water, and stirring. In Paradox of Plenty: A Social History of Eating in Modern America, Harvey Levenstein argues that such convenience foods became an essential part of the post-war housewife&#8217;s duty to build a healthy and happy American home.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="47">
<answer instance="47" senseid="12"/>
<context>
Meanwhile, growers plan to roll out a marketing campaign to address some of these health concerns by promoting drinking smaller glasses of juice. &#8220;The industry is trying to revive its healthy reputation against all odds,&#8221; says Hamilton. &#8220;Not only is <head>orange</head> juice heavily processed, but it&#8217;s straight sugar which today people recognize as contributing to obesity and diabetes.&#8221; Hamilton admits that the juice is low on the FDA&#8217;s list of priorities, but the British government is taking action by calling for a tax on fruit juice and warning consumers that it has as much sugar as Coke and should be consumed sparingly.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="48">
<answer instance="48" senseid="4"/>
<context>
Canned meals, powdered foods, frozen seasonal and exotic produce were now readily available year-round. Women&#8217;s magazines extolled these &#8220;new&#8221; foods and their miraculous time-saving attributes. But the idea that something processed could also be &#8220;fresh,&#8221; was provoking questions. By 1960 the FDA was becoming concerned with the misrepresentative &#8220;fresh&#8221; labeling of commercial <head>orange</head> juice. Not only was it far from fresh, but sugar and water were being added. Federal standards and regulation ensued.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="49">
<answer instance="49" senseid="2"/>
<context>
A tall glass of juice is the very image of refreshment, packed with vitamins and radiating with sunshine freshness. It&#8217;s part of a balanced breakfast, after all. But America&#8217;s classic morning drink is in trouble: sales of commercial <head>orange</head> juice are down to their lowest levels in the last 15 seasons, according to the WSJ and the Florida Department of Citrus. The industry is facing growing competition from exotic fruit and energy drinks while its &#8220;all-natural&#8221; claims are being called into serious question.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="50">
<answer instance="50" senseid="7"/>
<context>
But <head>orange</head> juice did not always have a place at the American breakfast table, mostly because for years it was either too expensive, or just didn&#8217;t taste very good. Here&#8217;s a taste experiment for the adventurous and historically inclined drinker: Boil some juice, place it in a can, and leave it on a shelf for several weeks. This is what most people knew as juice in the 1920&#8217;s. In lieu of pricey fresh-squeezed, average Americans enjoyed what the latest preservation technology offered: canned juice, which was essentially boiled to death. Unsurprisingly, its flavor was&#8230;somewhat lacking.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="51">
<answer instance="51" senseid="2"/>
<context>
"Fruit juice isn't the same as intact fruit and it has as much sugar as many classical sugar drinks," said Jebb, who has stopped drinking juice. "It is also absorbed very fast, so by the time it gets to your stomach your body doesn't know whether it's Coca-Cola or <head>orange</head> juice, frankly. I have to say it is a relatively easy thing to give up. Swap it and have a piece of real fruit. If you are going to drink it, you should dilute it." This comes on top of a year or so of stories about the high sugar content of fruit juice. The same US scientists who warned about the use of high-fructose corn syrup in fizzy drinks have now turned their attention to juice.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="52">
<answer instance="52" senseid="11"/>
<context>
It's embarrassing to admit they've made a mistake." Does she drink juice? "I don't, really &#8211; not in any great quantity," she says. At one point, she says, in the late 1980s and early 90s, she was "a very enthusiastic <head>orange</head> juicer. I remember coming back from the States, where everyone juices like mad, and I got a juicer. Then over the last couple of years there has been more and more evidence that sweet juices are basically just fructose, and have a similar effect on the body to fizzy and soft drinks in terms of sugar."

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="53">
<answer instance="53" senseid="11"/>
<context>
In the early 20th century, juice was mainly sold in cans. During the second world war, the US government commissioned scientists to develop a product that would supply vitamin C to soldiers overseas. "That's when research into developing a frozen concentrate that people would actually like started," says Hamilton. Until then, it had been fairly tasteless &#8211; the concentrating process removed the water, but also the natural chemicals that gave <head>orange</head> juice its taste. "They started adding fresh juice to the concentrate and that made it taste good. The discovery was too late for the war, but after the war that's when the juice started to become really popular."

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="54">
<answer instance="54" senseid="0"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> juice is the go-to drink of the morning. It's what we reach for to get a dose of vitamin C when we feel a cold coming on. It's an essential ingredient in mimosas. And it's a staple beverage that's loved by everyone.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="55">
<answer instance="55" senseid="4"/>
<context>
I wanted a variety of well-known national brands that readers would be familiar with, ones that could be found at most grocery stores throughout the country. I also included a generic store brand, as well as homemade fresh-squeezed <head>orange</head> juice as a control option. All varieties selected were 100% pure, and not from concentrate. I selected all pulp-free juice, and the fresh-squeezed variety was strained multiple times to remove all the pulp. The juices I chose also happened to vary in packaging &#8212; some were sold in cartons and some in plastic containers.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="56">
<answer instance="56" senseid="13"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> juice, as you can probably guess, is the juice squeezed from the popular and delicious citrus fruit. It is widely considered one of the healthiest beverages because of its wide range of health benefits, which include its ability to boost immune system function, reduce signs of aging, protect against cancer, boost cellular repair and metabolism, detoxify the body, improve circulation, improves blood pressure, reduces inflammation, and lowers cholesterol levels.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="57">
<answer instance="57" senseid="14"/>
<context>
As mentioned, vitamin C works as an antioxidant, and one of the most important functions of antioxidants is to prevent cancer. Antioxidants keep the DNA of healthy cells from mutating into cancerous cells, so antioxidants like vitamin C are the first line of defense for cancer and other serious diseases. Along with vitamin C, <head>orange</head> juice also contains the antioxidant hesperidin, which has been connected to reducing tumor growth and even stimulating apoptosis, or programmed cell death, in cancerous cells. Although research is ongoing, it has positively been linked to colon cancer prevention, but it is likely that hesperidin is effective in terms of many types of cancer.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="58">
<answer instance="58" senseid="15"/>
<context>
High sugar and high fat meals can lead to inflammation of various body parts, and this, in turn, can lead to the development of increased insulin resistance. This is one of the major underlying causes of type 2 diabetes and atherosclerosis. Studies have shown that <head>orange</head> juice can inhibit this insulin resistance by reducing inflammation, thereby protecting the heart and guaranteeing overall cardiovascular protection. Also, being able to reduce the chances of developing diabetes is a major bonus of this property of this juice.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="59">
<answer instance="59" senseid="13"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> juice is the amazing drink for the patients of high or low blood pressure. Are you interested in finding the reason? Well, this delicious drink contains a significant amount of magnesium which has a wonderful ability to bring back the disturbed blood pressure level to normal range.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="60">
<answer instance="60" senseid="15"/>
<context>
Eating meals with a lot of fat or glucose can lead to the development of inflammatory reactions. Inflammatory reactions lead to the resistance of insulin, which is a common cause of type II diabetes and atherosclerosis. Atherosclerosis is a very serious condition where the blood vessel walls harden due to fatty deposits. Drinking <head>orange</head> juice when ingesting a high-carbohydrate and high-fat meal will prevent the occurrence of this inflammation, making it a good preventative measure against insulin resistance and atherosclerosis.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="61">
<answer instance="61" senseid="14"/>
<context>
Folate deficiency is one of the main causes of low birth weight and neural tube defects, which are congenital problems in the brain and spinal cord. It also one of the most preventable causes of these birth defects. Drinking &#8531; cup of <head>orange</head> juice each day provides 40 mcg of folates to expectant mothers. Folates are important micronutrients that are known to prevent a wide variety of birth defects. The &#8531; cup serving mentioned provides 10% of the recommended daily value of folates.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="62">
<answer instance="62" senseid="0"/>
<context>
If you said yes to the two above questions, then you&#8217;ve been conned by very clever marketers and businessmen. Let me explain. At some point during the Vitamin C era, when it became very popular as a supplement, some smart marketer learned that <head>orange</head>s had vitamin C.  People in the alternative health space at this time were buying Vitamin C by the boatloads because they believed that it protected them against the common cold and flu.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="63">
<answer instance="63" senseid="2"/>
<context>
But now because of the massive use of High Fructose Corn Syrup &#8212; which basically tastes like sugar but is cheaper to make &#8212; Fructose makes up a much higher percentage of our diet.  Fructose is in everything. Soft drinks. Candies. Crackers. Fructose, when you consume it in normal proportions, is fine.  But because people now are drinking 2 glasses of <head>orange</head> juice, then a soda with High Fructose Cornsyrup, and some crackers and chips (also with High Fructose Corn Syrup), and even bread that has it, fructose consumption is at an all-time high. In studies, high fructose consumption has been linked to alterations in fat levels, cholesterol changes, as well as other obvious changes that occur with a high energy intake like weight gain, metabolic disorder, and cardiovascular issues.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="64">
<answer instance="64" senseid="0"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> juice is the excellent source of vitamin C and fulfills the entire day requirement of vitamin C in just one serving. It is tasty and delicious with full of medicinal as well as health benefits. It is known for many minerals such as magnesium, potassium, Vitamin B6, beta carotene, calcium, folic acid, and having low fats and no cholesterol.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="65">
<answer instance="65" senseid="15"/>
<context>
he modern day faulty lifestyle along with paradox in dietary pattern leads to inflammatory reactions in the body, which causes lifestyle related disorders such as diabetes, heart diseases, arthritis, asthma, depression, etc. Drinking of <head>orange</head> juice helps to minimize the impact of type II diabetes and atherosclerosis. The flavonoids like hesperidin, and naringenin are acting as anti-inflammatory products and good for arthritis, rheumatoid arthritis, and asthma.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="66">
<answer instance="66" senseid="15"/>
<context>
The intake of glucose and high-fat meals induces the development of inflammatory reactions within the body. Inflammatory reactions lead to the development of increased insulin resistance, a common cause of Type 2 diabetes and atherosclerosis, the hardening of blood vessel walls due to fat deposition. As mentioned in a study published in the April 2010 &#8220;The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition,&#8221; the intake of <head>orange</head> juice, together with a high-carbohydrate, high-fat meal, prevents the occurrence of inflammation within the body, making it a good preventive measure against the development of insulin resistance and atherosclerosis.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="67">
<answer instance="67" senseid="13"/>
<context>
A 500 milliliter glass of the juice naturally contains 292 milligrams of hesperidin. Over the course of the study, every man drank every beverage for one month straight. The researchers found that when the men drank the daily <head>orange</head> juice or the hesperidin-fortified drink, they had better endothelial function and lower diastolic blood pressure (the bottom number of a blood pressure reading) than when they drank the non-hesperidin beverage. In addition, gene expression profiles (as related to cardiovascular disease development) were improved.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="68">
<answer instance="68" senseid="0"/>
<context>
While another study, which looked at much larger quantities of vitamin C, did show a protective effect from the vitamin alone, this research indicates that not only is the protection afforded by fruit more complex, but smaller amounts of nutrients like vitamin C are all that are needed for benefit. Said lead researcher, Serena Guarnieri, "It appears that vitamin C is not the only chemical responsible for antioxidant protection." In <head>orange</head>s, vitamin C is part of a matrix involving many beneficial phytochemicals (for example, cyanidin-3-glucoside, flavanones and carotenoids)."But how they are interacting is still anyone's guess," she added.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="69">
<answer instance="69" senseid="15"/>
<context>
Finally, the CSIRO Report notes that as low fat, nutrient-rich foods with a low glycemic index, citrus fruits are protective against overweight and obesity, conditions which increase the risk of heart disease, certain cancers, diabetes, high blood pressure and stroke, and add to symptoms of other conditions like arthritis. An <head>orange</head> has over 170 different phytonutrients and more than 60 flavonoids, many of which have been shown to have anti-inflammatory, anti-tumour and blood clot inhibiting properties, as well as strong antioxidant effects.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="70">
<answer instance="70" senseid="16"/>
<context>
In citrus fruits, limonin is present in the form of limonin glucoside, in which limonin is attached to a sugar (glucose) molecule. Our bodies easily digest this compound, cleaving off the sugar and releasing limonin. In the ARS study, 16 volunteers were given a dose of limonin glucoside in amounts ranging from those that would be found in from 1 to 7 glasses of <head>orange</head> juice. Blood tests showed that limonin was present in the plasma of all except one of the subjects, with concentrations highest within 6 hours after consumption. Traces of limonin were still present in 5 of the volunteers 24 hours after consumption!

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="71">
<answer instance="71" senseid="16"/>
<context>
Treatment with PMFs did not appear to have any effect on levels of beneficial HDL cholesterol, and no negative side effects were seen in the animals fed the PMF-containing diets. Although a variety of citrus fruits contain PMFs, the most common PMFs, tangeretin and nobiletin, are found in the peels of tangerines and <head>orange</head>s. Juices of these fruits also contain PMFs, but in much smaller amounts. In fact, you'd have to drink about 20 glasses of juice each day to receive an amount of PMFs comparable in humans to that given to the animals.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="72">
<answer instance="72" senseid="13"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head>s' health benefits continue with their fiber, which has been shown to reduce high cholesterol levels thus helping to prevent atherosclerosis. Fiber can also help out by keeping blood sugar levels under control, which may help explain why they can be a very healthy snack for people with diabetes.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="73">
<answer instance="73" senseid="15"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> a day may help keep ulcers away, according to a study published in the Journal of the American College of Nutrition. In this study, researchers evaluated data from over 6,000 adults enrolled in the Third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Study participants with the highest blood levels of vitamin C had a 25% lower incidence of infection with Helicobacter pylori (H. pylori), the bacterium responsible for causing peptic ulcers and in turn, an increased risk for stomach cancer.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="74">
<answer instance="74" senseid="3"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head>s are one of the most popular fruits around the world. While they are delightful as a snack or as a recipe ingredient, for many Americans, it is their juice that is most associated with good health, having a reputation for being an integral part of a healthy breakfast.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="75">
<answer instance="75" senseid="0"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head>s can either be stored at room temperature or in the refrigerator, depending upon your preference. They will generally last the same amount of time, two weeks with either method, and will retain nearly the same level of their vitamin content.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="76">
<answer instance="76" senseid="0"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> juice is recommended for Type II Diabetes patients because it has little sugar and has diuretic properties, which can help regulate excess sugar in your body. Also, the content of vitamin C helps those patients minimize the consequences that can bring this disease, which can be infections, the difficult to form scars, or visual problems.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="77">
<answer instance="77" senseid="13"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> juice helps improve blood circulation, avoiding the formation of clots, and therefore can prevent arteriosclerosis.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="78">
<answer instance="78" senseid="0"/>
<context>
Vitamin C is essential in the production of collagen, along with super nutrient Lutein. Its yellow pigment is linked to reducing sun-induced skin damage and is believed to improve elasticity of the skin. A 200ml glass of <head>orange</head> typically contains 60mg vitamin C and equates to 100 per cent of an adult&#8217;s recommended daily amount. Nutritionist Amanda Ursell said: &#8220;The adage of &#8216;you are what you eat&#8217; is not a new one but science has lagged behind in determining the effect nutrition has on our skin, hair and nails.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="79">
<answer instance="79" senseid="14"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head>s contain a wide variety of bioflavonoids such as hesperidin, quercetin and tangeritin. In general, bioflavonoids help prevent oxidation damage from free radicals, combat degenerative diseases and tissue aging, support cell growth and cardiovascular health and display some anti-cancer properties. More specifically, quercetin also exhibits anti-allergy, anti-inflammatory and antiviral properties. However, bioflavonoids in juice degrade fairly quickly with time, so drinking fresh-squeezed varieties ensures that you get the most nutrients from your fruit.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="80">
<answer instance="80" senseid="0"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> juice contains beneficial antioxidant polyphenols as well as key digestive enzymes&#8212;all of which are completely destroyed when the juice is pasteurized. Scorching the juice in the name of food &#8220;safety&#8221; also cuts way down on vitamins, especially vitamin C. These are all nutrients which are very sensitive to heat and oxidation, and will break down when exposed to the high temperatures of the pasteurization process in commercial juice production. So sometimes, manufacturers will add back in vitamin C to compensate for the loss.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="81">
<answer instance="81" senseid="13"/>
<context>
Worried about all that sugar you&#8217;d be drinking, though? Well, the magnesium that comes in your OJ is actually essential for blood sugar regulation, too, and keeps blood glucose levels normalized. As well as potassium, another key nutrient found plentifully in <head>orange</head> juice. Potassium is involved in regulating both blood sugar and insulin levels. Potassium works by getting sugar into the cell, which regulates cellular metabolism and makes use of that sugar by using it as fuel. Potassium has other benefits, too. It determines cellular hydration, by keeping sodium in circulation, which regulates water retention and blood volume.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="82">
<answer instance="82" senseid="0"/>
<context>
When the adrenal glands are overworked due to chronic stress and lack of nutritional stores, they may not be able to supply your body with hormones such as cortisol, in the amounts needed to maintain homeostasis in your everyday life. For example, cortisol is supposed to rise in the morning, get you up and ready and hungry to eat a nice big breakfast, and then taper off once your belly is full. But your adrenals can&#8217;t produce cortisol or function normally without adequate potassium, magnesium, vitamin C, B vitamins, and other nutrients. You&#8217;ll get a nice big dose of those of them in a glass of fresh <head>orange</head> juice, though! If you really want to boost your OJ&#8217;s thyroid-and-adrenal-supporting superpowers, you&#8217;ll want to add a few shakes of sea salt to your cup. Salt down-regulates stress hormones and supports both of these glands immensely. But overall, OJ itself contains an impressive array of nutrients which work together synergistically to support hormone health.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="83">
<answer instance="83" senseid="14"/>
<context>
Speaking of antioxidants, ever wonder why vitamin C is supposed to be so supportive to your immune system? It&#8217;s because it actually increases your white blood cell count&#8212;as long as it&#8217;s coming from a whole food source, with the entire C complex intact. Vitamin C is one of the most major and important antioxidants your body needs for optimal health. And as we all know, <head>orange</head> juice is a great source for it&#8212;especially when it&#8217;s raw. Fresh, raw OJ also is rich in bioflavanoids, which are plant pigments that enhance the bioavailability of nutrients such as vitamin C. Even when added to synthetic vitamin C, bioflavanoids significantly increase how much C is absorbed into your system.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="84">
<answer instance="84" senseid="7"/>
<context>
does not believe that it is necessary to like or even respect your movie co-star.' It makes it better for you if you do, but it probably doesn't matter to the film,' he says.' Although if there are two people at odds you may lose a bit because they are not going to get their ideas together.' In Housesitter we stuck mostly to the script. But there is one scene where I fall over a sofa, which we added on the day of the shoot.' As a boy growing up in <head>orange</head> County, California, Steve Martin's life of showbusiness began with Disneyland.' That's when I started to learn my craft,' he says.' I went along as a 10-year-old and watched the shows four times a day.' I used to dream that one day they would call out for a 10-year-old from the audience to give them a hand. It never happened.' At 14 he took an evening and weekend job in a magic shop. There he learned his second craft,

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="85">
<answer instance="85" senseid="3"/>
<context>
own fair share of muggers, murderers, and drug addicts. Police say there have been at least 50 armed robberies of tourists in the Orlando area so far this year. Few of these crimes got much publicity. One in four local people works in tourism -- which earns the area nearly 3 billion a year. And they do not need it spelt out how important it is to promote Orlando's image as a safe and healthy resort. So the city's worried public relations arm went into overdrive yesterday in the wake of Mr Thompson's death. <head>orange</head> County chairman Linda Chapin said the Orlando was' appalled and saddened'. She assured visitors everything was being done to catch the killers. But she admitted:' Such a senseless tragedy reminds us that, unfortunately, even the safest of places is not crime-proof.' Dangerous Orlando's crime rate is not excessive when compared to cities like New York, Washington and New Orleans where British tourist Julie Stott from Manchester was shot dead last April while strolling through the' safe' streets of the French Quarter

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="86">
<answer instance="86" senseid="2"/>
<context>
During this time he became acquainted with John Ray, the great English naturalist, and Robert Boyle, the philosopher, both of whom gave help and encouragement to the young man. He continued his studies in France at the Royal Garden of Plants in Paris under Joseph Pitton de Tournefort, a French botanist who had already made expeditions to Spain, Greece and Asia Minor, and later produced a new classification of plants, accompanied by descriptions of the genera. After Sloane had quickly gained his degree as Doctor of Medicine from the University of <head>orange</head> (southern France) in 1683, he continued his medical studies at Montpellier under another botanist, Pierre Magnol. Together they travelled in search of plants, sometimes joined by William Courten, who became Sloane's lifelong friend. At the end of 1684 he returned to England, fully qualified, and was taken on by Dr Thomas Sydenham as an assistant in a busy London practice. About this time a detailed correspondence, lasting for twenty years, started between Sloane and Ray. The aged naturalist was thus

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="87">
<answer instance="87" senseid="7"/>
<context>
new T-6 main landing gears and P-40 tail wheel assemblies were located and utilised in the mock-ups. Also, new Curtiss-Electric propellers were attached and, in at least two mock-ups, running Allison engines were installed. Much of the actual mock-up assembly work was completed in Hawaii before the filming, but the preliminary moulding and construction was completed at Long Beach and then shipped to Pearl Harbor. A fibreglass O2SU Kingfisher replica was also constructed for inclusion on the full-scale battleship Arizona replica being constructed. Also procured were five PBY Catalinas. Four derelict PBYs were located at <head>orange</head> County Airport in Southern California where they had been abandoned after a Navy surplus sale. They were purchased, cleaned up, and barged to Hawaii for use as targets. An airworthy Catalina, PBY-5A N6108, was leased for use in the film and apparently flown to Hawaii. A rare, even by 1967 standards, SBD Dauntless was also obtained for use in the film. Believed to actually be A-24A 42-60817, (N9142H) the old Douglas was trucked in from Seattle to Long Beach for some much-needed

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="88">
<answer instance="88" senseid="5"/>
<context>
The decoration is restrained and, apart from the Corinthian Order, is seen in the medallions in the spandrels. The arch was built to commemorate Augustus' restoration of the chief highways of Italy (162). FIRST CENTURY B.C. TO FOURTH CENTURY A.D. Outside Italy, one of the finest examples is the Arch of Tiberius at <head>orange</head> in France (c. 30-20 B.C.). It straddles the main road into the town, but a large roundabout has been constructed for the arch to stand serenely in a wide circular grass plot in the centre of the pounding traffic. This is a very early example of a three-arched design, in the Corinthian Order.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="89">
<answer instance="89" senseid="7"/>
<context>
At the same time Nelson invented a freezer for ready-made products, now known to the frozen food industry as the' Nelson Box'. This device froze mini-slabs of ice cream at -40 degrees Farenheit, which made them hard enough to be sealed with warm chocolate. Nelson sold the Eskimo Pie Corporation to the US Foil Company (now the Reynolds Metal Company) in 1924, but retained his affiliation: he stayed as vice-president, moving with the company to New York and to Richmond, Virginia, in the 1940s. Even after his retirement to <head>orange</head> County, California, in 1961, Nelson continued to travel across America, promoting Eskimo Pies and inventing new ways to store and deliver frozen novelties. Today the frozen sweets industry is worth $1.3 billion per annum. Among 400 different brand names Eskimo Pie has held its own, selling half a billion bars each year. Even in an era of' Political Correctness' and hyper-sensitivity over racial slights, Eskimo Pie has retained its name and its logo. Its television advertisements still portray a genuine Eskimo fisherman,

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="90">
<answer instance="90" senseid="7"/>
<context>
Sunday, a venue arranged before the start of the season. Widnes and Fulham are the season's first winners of the Stones Bitter Team of the Month awards. Widnes are unbeaten in their first six matches and have amassed 238 points. Fulham have registered four victories and are second behind Ryedale York in the Second Division. Biggs cut out to advance Mason's career: Ken Jones on the fragility a Briton aims to exploit tonight. The two things to remember about Tyrell Biggs, the 28-year-old Olympic gold medallist from <head>orange</head> County, California, who stands between Gary Mason and the rest of his career. One is that he has been in the ring with Michael Gerard Tyson. Two is that it would be extremely unwise for Biggs to engage in serious pugilistic activity without first retaining the services of an attendant unlikely to panic at the sight of a badly lacerated brow. It is safe to assume that these were prominent factors when Biggs was considered as a possible opponent for Mason who will go to his corner at the Royal

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="91">
<answer instance="91" senseid="17"/>
<context>
The period of April through November is warm to hot and dry with average high temperatures of 74 &#8211; 84 &#176;F (29 &#176;C) and lows of 52 &#8211; 64 &#176;F (18 &#176;C). Due to the moderating effect of the ocean, temperatures are cooler than more inland areas of <head>orange</head> County, where temperatures frequently exceed 90 &#176;F (32 &#176;C) and occasionally reach 100 &#176;F (38 &#176;C). The period of November through March is somewhat rainy, as shown in the table to right.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="92">
<answer instance="92" senseid="17"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> County area is also subject to the phenomena typical of a microclimate. As such, the temperatures can vary as much as 18 &#176;F (10 &#176;C) between inland areas and the coast, with a temperature gradient of over one degree per mile (1.6 km) from the coast inland. California also has a weather phenomenon called "June Gloom" or "May Gray," which sometimes brings overcast or foggy skies in the morning on the coast, but usually gives way to sunny skies by noon, during late spring and early summer.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="93">
<answer instance="93" senseid="17"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> County area averages 15 inches (385 mm) of precipitation annually, which mainly occurs during the winter and spring (November thru April) with generally light rain showers, but sometimes as heavy rainfall and thunderstorms. Coastal Torrance receives slightly less rainfall, while the mountains receive slightly more. Snowfall is extremely rare in the city basin, but the mountains within city limits typically receive snowfall every winter.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="94">
<answer instance="94" senseid="18"/>
<context>
The Historic District was listed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1997, and is the largest National Register District in California. The Old Towne Preservation Association is a non-profit organization dedicated to maintaining the district. <head>orange</head> is unique among the region and the state in that it has the second largest concentration of historic buildings.[12] A list of all of the buildings and sites appears in the National Register of Historic Places.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="95">
<answer instance="95" senseid="7"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> has a large Middle-Eastern community in proportion to its population, notably Armenians, Iranians and Arab peoples including Arab-Americans, who have bought homes and own some businesses in the city, and their business strips can be found along Tustin Avenue between Lincoln and Katella avenues.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="96">
<answer instance="96" senseid="19"/>
<context>
Historically, the plaza has been primarily home to a wide variety of antique shops&#8212;and has become a well known destination amongst antique collectors. A more recent trend has brought clothing boutiques, and several casual and upscale restaurants. It also features two Starbucks locations, mirroring each other on opposite ends of the plaza, Wells Fargo bank, a Masonic lodge, and is within walking distance of Chapman University and the newly reconstructed public library. Films such as That Thing You Do starring Tom Hanks, Accepted starring Justin Long, and Big Momma's House, Ghost Whisperer, Black Sheep were all filmed in the historical Old Town <head>orange</head>.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="97">
<answer instance="97" senseid="20"/>
<context>
Judge Thomas Goethals booted the entire County District Attorney&#8217;s office from Dekraai&#8217;s case after holding hearings on Dekraai&#8217;s motion. The Times is calling for a Justice Department investigation of the informant issue. The <head>orange</head> County Register profile says Sanders is &#8220;engaging and likable&#8221; outside the courtroom, and &#8220;energetic, excitable&#8221; and &#8220;tightly wound&#8221; inside the courtroom. &#8220;He displays an encyclopedic knowledge of cases past and present, and wields facts with cutting precision,&#8221; the story says. &#8220;He slices quickly through discrepancies, growing indignant when he is attacked.&#8221;

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="98">
<answer instance="98" senseid="18"/>
<context>
Not everyone is a fan. Mark Geller, a senior deputy district attorney who is among those facing accusations by Sanders, told the Register he found 30 inaccuracies in the Dekraai motion. Sanders engaged in &#8220;character assassination&#8221; and made &#8220;glaring errors,&#8221; Geller said. &#8220;Scott Sanders shouldn&#8217;t even be a lawyer based on the tactics he&#8217;s engaged.&#8221; Sanders gave a written response to the <head>orange</head> County Register. A &#8220;focus on self-vindication instead of justice is the one consistent theme in the prosecution&#8217;s response&#8221; to his work, Sanders said. &#8220;As long as that remains the situation the criminal justice system in this county will remain unfair.&#8221;

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="99">
<answer instance="99" senseid="21"/>
<context>
The City's planning area is 38 square miles, with a "Sphere of Influence" area of 55 square miles. Included in the City's Sphere of Influence is 18,500 acres of undeveloped land owned by The Irvine Company. The City was incorporated on April 6, 1888 under the general laws of the State of California. However, <head>orange</head> dates back to 1869 when Alfred Chapman and Andrew Glassell, both lawyers, accepted 1,385 acres of land from the Rancho Santiago de Santa Ana as legal fees. Soon thereafter, the men laid out a one square mile town with ten-acre farm lots surrounding a forty-acre central town site.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="100">
<answer instance="100" senseid="21"/>
<context>
Two Los Angeles lawyers involved in the lawsuit were Alfred Beck Chapman and Andrew Glassell, who took some of their fees in land. They had already started buying other sections of the rancho as early as 1864. By 1870, they owned about 5,400 acres in what is now downtown <head>orange</head>. It seemed like a good location for a town; the nearby Santa Ana River provided water, the soil was rich and a stage road ran nearby. Chapman hired a surveyor to divide the land into tracts of 40-, 80- and 120-acres. He called the area Richland and began selling the lots.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="101">
<answer instance="101" senseid="8"/>
<context>
The captain also supervised the construction of the A.B. Chapman Canal from the river to provide irrigation for the farm sites. (Part of the canal&#8217;s path may be traced along Canal Street, behind the Mall of <head>orange</head>.) He was a good salesman, and by the end of 1871, there were a dozen houses in and around Richland. The first school was opened on March 26, 1872, meeting at first in a private home. By August a one-room schoolhouse was opened at the corner of Sycamore and Lemon. The year 1873 saw the opening of the first local store (Fisher Brothers, on the north side of the Plaza), the first civic organization, and the first church congregation (the Methodist Episcopal).

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="102">
<answer instance="102" senseid="7"/>
<context>
In 1873, Richland&#8217;s application for a post office was refused because there was already a Richland in Sacramento County. In order to have their town map-recorded and to open a post office, they had to change their name. The story goes that Mr. Chapman, Mr. Glassell and two other men played a game of poker and whoever won the game would get to re-name the town. It was not recorded who actually won the game, but in January of 1875 Richland was renamed <head>orange</head>.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="103">
<answer instance="103" senseid="19"/>
<context>
The city continued to annex new areas and as of the 90s covered almost 25 square miles with a population of more than 120,000. The city is home to thousands of businesses, ranging from major Fortune 500 companies to family-owned stores. Chapman University, the oldest university in <head>orange</head> County, is located here, along with the rapidly growing Santiago Canyon College. The charming downtown area, with its antique stores, art galleries and restaurants, draws visitors from many miles around.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="104">
<answer instance="104" senseid="21"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> will continue to expand to the east, where it has a 60-square mile sphere of influence extending to the county line. Preliminary plans call for a variety of developments in the area around Irvine Lake, with much of the area to the north of the lake remaining as open space.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="105">
<answer instance="105" senseid="8"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> Community Historical Society is a non-profit community organization, with a volunteer board of directors which coordinates our ongoing activities. Besides presenting bimonthly programs on local history, the Society has hosted historic home tours and participated in various community anniversary celebrations.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="106">
<answer instance="106" senseid="8"/>
<context>
Each year the Society presents the Captain William T. Glassell Award to an individual or group which has contributed to preserving our local heritage. Over the years, the Society has published historic post cards, posters, booklets and two collections of pioneer recollections. In 1996 a beautiful historic afghan was introduced, and an annual holiday ornament project was begun. In 1997, we celebrated the completion of the first full-length history of <head>orange</head>.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="107">
<answer instance="107" senseid="19"/>
<context>
In his will dated two weeks before his death in 1858, Bernardo Yorba deeded to the Bishop of the Catholic Church a plot of land to the west of his home containing an adobe chapel already under construction, and 100 feet square of land for the establishment of a cemetery.  This later land, called the La Mesita, was a gently sloping hill with some corrals located on it.  The corrals would be removed and transformed in to the Yorba Cemetery, one of the oldest cemeteries in <head>orange</head> County predated only by the Mission Cemetery in Capistrano. The cemetery closed in 1939, and would fall victim of vandals who defaced and stole many of the rustic markers and marble headstones.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="108">
<answer instance="108" senseid="7"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> County Parks adopted a Master Planning Program that established the prime historic period from 1876 to 1947 as a guide for future restoration and interpretation of the historic property. The Katie Wheeler Branch Library has recreated the exterior of the Irvine family home on its original site and adapted the structure to provide library services.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="109">
<answer instance="109" senseid="19"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> has an estimated local government area population of 40,869 and an estimated city population of 39,226 making the city a major provincial centre. According to the 2011 Census, the key industries include health care and social assistance, retail and the education and training sector.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="110">
<answer instance="110" senseid="2"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> has several water sources used for domestic consumption, both currently in use and formerly used. Currently Suma Park Dam and Spring Creek Reservoir are used for domestic water consumption. Two other dams, Lake Canobolas and Gosling Creek Reservoir, were previously used for domestic water consumption however are now used for recreational purposes. The city is currently on Level 2 water restrictions.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="111">
<answer instance="111" senseid="10"/>
<context>
The main station, on the Main Western Line to Bourke, was opened in 1877 and is served by the daily NSW TrainLink Central West XPT service between Sydney and Dubbo and the weekly Outback Xplorer service between Sydney and Broken Hill. A smaller station, opened in 1970, known as <head>orange</head> East Fork, lies on the branch line to Broken Hill and is served by the weekly Indian Pacific service to Perth. It is a city in the Central West region of New South Wales, Australia.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="112">
<answer instance="112" senseid="11"/>
<context>
The Great Depression, not surprisingly, affected the city negatively, and it was not until World War II that the local economy was boosted again. A U.S. Naval Station was installed and additional housing was provided for thousands of defense workers and servicemen and their families. The population increased to just over 60,000 residents. After the war, the peace-time population decreased to about 25,000. At this time, the Navy Department announced it selected <head>orange</head> as one of eight locations where it would store reserve vessels. The area of the shipyards provided a favorable location, as the Sabine River furnished an abundant supply of fresh water to prevent saltwater corrosion. Also during this period the local chemical plants expanded which boosted the economy. The chemical industry continues today as a leading source of revenue to the area. The U.S. Naval Station was changed to a Reserve base in December 1975, and decommissioned completely in September, 2008.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="113">
<answer instance="113" senseid="2"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> sustained a direct hit from Hurricane Rita in 2005, causing damage to the ship. The city decreed that the ship be moved because, as it claimed, the city needed the dock space. The Orleck was not allowed to return to the port due to politics (as the city council was wanting the ship cut up and sold for scrap and had a long running feud with the Restoration Association) so a new location was sought, including one in Arkansas and Lake Charles, Louisiana, for a new home. On May 6, 2009, the Lake Charles city council voted in favor of an ordinance authorizing the city to enter into a "Cooperative Endeavor Agreement" with the "USS ORLECK". On May 20, 2010 the ship was moved to Lake Charles. The Grand Opening was on April 10, 2011.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="114">
<answer instance="114" senseid="3"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head>, Texas was heavily damaged by Hurricane Ike on September 13, 2008. Damage was widespread and severe across the County. The 22-foot (6.7 m) storm surge breached the city's levees, caused catastrophic flooding and obliterated everything in its path. The storm surge travelled up the Neches River to also flood Rose City.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="115">
<answer instance="115" senseid="3"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> received winds at hurricane force. Nearly the entire city of 19,000 people was flooded, anywhere from 6 inches (15 cm) to 15 feet (4.5 m). The mayor of the city said about 375 people, of those who stayed behind during the storm, began to emerge, some needing food, water and medical care.[11] Many dead fish littered streets and properties. Neighbor Bridge City Mayor Kirk Roccaforte estimated that only 14 homes in the city were unaffected by the surge, five of which were in the Oakview addition on Louise Street in Bridge City. The piles of debris and waterlogged furniture placed outside homes by residents beginning to clean up led the mayor to say "The whole city looks like a flea market. During the post-storm cleanup, Bridge City residents found swimming pools had been occupied by jellyfish brought inland with the water.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="116">
<answer instance="116" senseid="17"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> has a humid subtropical climate. Winters are warm and rainy while summers are hot, humid and wet. The climate is similar to nearby Vinton, Louisiana and Beaumont, Texas. The record high in here is 105 &#176;F recorded August 10, 1962. The record low is 11 &#176;F recorded December 26, 1983.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="117">
<answer instance="117" senseid="19"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> hosts several cultural and historical attractions. The Stark Museum of Art, houses one of the finest collections of 19th and 20th century Western American art and artifacts in the country. The collection focuses on the stunning land, dramatic people, and diverse wildlife of the American West. The Museum also holds a significant collection of American Indian art as well as collections of glass and porcelain, and rare books and manuscripts. The museum features the work of artists such as artist/naturalist John James Audubon, Paul Kane, Albert Bierstadt, Thomas Moran, and John Mix Stanley.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="118">
<answer instance="118" senseid="8"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> Community Players is a non-profit community theater located across the street from the historic courthouse and walking distance to the new riverfront park. Enjoy Southeast Texas' brightest stars, powerful stage performances, and unforgettable evenings of entertainment.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="119">
<answer instance="119" senseid="17"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> is served by Interstate 10, as well as a deep-water seaport. Commercial aviation service is located at nearby Southeast Texas Regional Airport, and general aviation service is provided by the County Airport. It has the distinction of having Exit 880 on Interstate 10 within its city limits, which is the highest numbered exit and mile marker on an interstate highway or freeway in North America. The area code is 409.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="120">
<answer instance="120" senseid="22"/>
<context>
"Ultimately, it was determined that euthanasia is necessary to ensure public safety," OC Animal Care Director Dr. Jennifer Hawkins said in a statement. More than 340,000 people signed an online petition to protest Karma's killing. At last week's board meeting, <head>orange</head> County Board Chairman Todd Spitzer argued that the dog was "neglected and not fed," prompting it to hunt down cats. Under Wednesday's ruling, the Ogles will never see Karma again, but they say that's OK. "This whole thing that I've gone through has been traumatic, and I'm just happy to see Karma surviving at this point," Joshua Ogle said.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="121">
<answer instance="121" senseid="22"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> County Animal Care officials then declared Karma vicious for allegedly killing at least one cat in 2012. DNA tests also showed Karma is part wolf and could not be properly vaccinated against rabies. "Ultimately, it was determined that euthanasia is necessary to ensure public safety," OC Animal Care Director Dr. Jennifer Hawkins said in a statement. More than 340,000 people signed an online petition to protest Karma's killing.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="122">
<answer instance="122" senseid="18"/>
<context>
He noted that other Irvine Republicans like Christina Shea and Steven Choi have won endorsements from a local police union in past campaigns. (Fleischman's PAC also made 2014 expenditures for Republican candidates Matt Harper in Huntington Beach ($5,179) and Scott Peotter in Newport Beach ($3,000), according to campaign finance records.) Republicans can't accuse Democrats or unions for creating the controversy. In 2010, the <head>orange</head> County Republican Party attacked public employee unions for creating a pension funding nightmare in California and, as a way to cripple their influence over government treasuries, banned party backed candidates from benefiting from any financial support from labor organizations.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="123">
<answer instance="123" senseid="18"/>
<context>
Hunt is a Republican--a very conservative one, in fact--but he is also fiercely independent, a trait party bosses abhor. The Baugh Manifesto went into effect while Hunt, a veteran sheriff's deputy and former chief of police in San Clemente, was favored by the Association of <head>orange</head> County Deputy Sheriffs, whose coffers have influenced elections for decades in the county. Sandra Hutchens, a Los Angeles Democrat turned OC Republican, won that election and remains in office.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="124">
<answer instance="124" senseid="18"/>
<context>
The Manifesto quickly became a paper tiger in other races. Janet Nguyen took $4,000 from the firefighter's union in her winning 2014 Republican state senate campaign against Democrat Jose Solorio. Baugh ordered the money return before the election. Nguyen and her campaign manager, Dave Gilliard, refused. Though Democrats get blamed for coziness with union bosses, it was an all Republican- <head>orange</head> County Board of Supervisors that voted in 2001 to hand the deputies' union one of the most lucrative government contracts in California. It allows officers to retire at the age of 50 and collect 90 percent of their annual salaries--or more, after pension inflation schemes--for the remainder of their lives. Though a 60-year-old convicted felon, Carona, for example, receives a taxpayer funded $220,000 pension each year.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="125">
<answer instance="125" senseid="1"/>
<context>
<head>orange</head> County currently has around 452 homeless people--this equates to 15,291 persons that become homeless over a 12 month period," said Roper. "Families with children represent 31% of the homeless population." She explained that this joint shelter/multi-service center--one-stop shops for homeless support services--would serve up to 200 homeless individuals who can only enter after passing a screening and securing a bed reservation.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="126">
<answer instance="126" senseid="7"/>
<context>
From its inception to today, it has been a publication the county has never stopped reading, waiting every week (and, in this Internet age, every minute) to see what politician we ruined, what saint we helped, what trend we discovered, what douchebag to despise--in short, to learn more about this crazy, horrible, beautiful land of ours. Simply put: The Weekly is one of OC's crowning achievements, simultaneously documenting and creating social and cultural movements that changed the county forever and for the better. Almost all of the stories of consequence in <head>orange</head> County over the past two decades--No Doubt, Kelly Thomas, immigration, hate groups, the Haidl Three, Mike Carona, Arrested Development, Burger Records, all of them--appeared in our pages first or had their definitive coverage here. We've been the best sledgehammer against the old OC, the nasty OC of retrograde Republicans, neo-Nazis, Don Bren and Mission Viejo. We've been the biggest cheerleader for this area's pariahs: the undocumented, the wrongfully jailed, the holes-in-the-wall, the unappreciated artists and the hidden treasures.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="127">
<answer instance="127" senseid="18"/>
<context>
Sophisticated financial crimes are, of course, an everyday occurrence in Southern California, but Toy's mess is unique. From 2006 to 2007, he counted among his pals then-LA Sheriff Lee Baca and Undersheriff Larry Waldie, who made him a reserve lieutenant sheriff after taking his regular campaign contributions. <head>orange</head> County experienced a similar unseemly pay-to-play scenario in which, before his FBI arrest and six-year prison trip, Sheriff Mike Carona routinely gave guns and official badges to wealthy businessmen seeking law-enforcement influence. Toy used his own connections in hopes of buying a hospital that would nab lucrative government contracts for indigent patients, an idea he pitched to Arlene Shih, a senior vice president at Chinatrust Bank.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="128">
<answer instance="128" senseid="20"/>
<context>
Initially, Judge Goethals had ruled that the DA&#8217;s office was negligent in failing to turn exculpatory information over, finding that &#8220;the district attorney&#8217;s well-documented failures in this case, although disappointing, even disheartening to any interested member of this community, were negligent rather than malicious.&#8221; But that seems to have changed following further revelations of refusal to turn over evidence. In an explosive moment following a hearing last year, Sanders revealed that the <head>orange</head> County Sheriff&#8217;s Department has maintained a massive, secret, 25-year-old computerized record-keeping system called TRED. These TRED documents were full of potentially exculpatory data, but the agency officials had systematically refused to turn any of them over, or even acknowledge their very existence, to defense counsel.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="129">
<answer instance="129" senseid="20"/>
<context>
In his March order, Goethals wrote: &#8220;It is now apparent that the discovery situation in this case is far worse than the court previously realized. In fact, a wealth of potentially relevant discovery material&#8212;an entire computerized data base built and maintained by the <head>orange</head> County Sheriff over the course of many years which is a repository for information related directly to the very issues that this court was examining as a result of the defendant&#8217;s motion&#8212;remained secret, despite numerous specific discovery orders issued by this court, until long after the initial evidentiary hearing in this case was concluded and rulings were made.&#8221;

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="130">
<answer instance="130" senseid="7"/>
<context>
Laura Fernandez of Yale Law School, who studies prosecutorial misconduct, says it&#8217;s amazing that both the sheriff&#8217;s office and the DA&#8217;s office worked together to cover up the misconduct: &#8220;From my perspective,&#8221; she says, &#8220;what really sets the County apart is the massive cover-up by both law enforcement and prosecutors&#8212;a cover-up that appears to have risen to the level of perjury and obstruction of justice. Law enforcement officers and prosecutors in <head>orange</head> County have gone to such lengths to conceal their wide-ranging misconduct that they have effectively turned the criminal justice system on its head: dismissing charges and reducing sentences in extraordinarily serious cases, utterly failing to investigate unsolved crimes and many murders (by informants&#8212;in order to prevent that evidence from ever getting to defense lawyers), while simultaneously pushing forward where it would seem to make no sense (except that it conceals more bad acts by the state), as in the case of an innocent 14-year old boy who was wrongfully detained for two years.&#8221;

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="131">
<answer instance="131" senseid="7"/>
<context>
And even though snitching happens everywhere, and inmates are well aware that there are benefits to be gained for eliciting information, there are few mechanisms that exist to correct the perverse incentive to trade false information for rewards. As Moxley notes, the Los Angeles Times&#8217; 1989 investigation, Jailhouse Snitches: Trading Lies for Freedom, exposed many of these problems. The article quoted Steve Vulpis, then an L.A. County Jail inmate, who admitted he and other informants told prosecutors anything they wanted to hear in order &#8220;to go home.&#8221; The story also quoted one informant from <head>orange</head> County: &#8220;He was blunt in his assessment of courtroom shams conducted by other snitches and sponsored by the government, saying, &#8216;A way you can get around maybe not being able to get a confession right away [from a targeted inmate] is create one.&#8217; &#8221; The problem persists after all these years. In a report this week for America Tonight, Al Jazeera obtained damning tapes of likely negotiating for testimony.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="132">
<answer instance="132" senseid="20"/>
<context>
He found that two deputies, Ben Garcia and Seth Tunstall, who belonged to the &#8220;special handling&#8221; unit dealing with informants, testified falsely to the court, denying the very existence of the TRED records at a crucial hearing last year. He also found that a prosecutor, Eric Petersen, had testified falsely. Natapoff observes that another stunning aspect of the <head>orange</head> County scandal is that a defense team was able to break through the prosecutors&#8217; and sheriff&#8217;s office wall of silence. &#8220;Here you have longstanding collusion between the sheriff&#8217;s department and the DA&#8217;s office, and then the willingness to lie about the practice, even to the extent of committing perjury, under oath, in court to cover up those practices.&#8221; Noting that most everything about jailhouse informants happens in what she calls a &#8220;culture of secrecy,&#8221; Natapoff recalls that at the start of this case nobody would believe Sanders&#8217; claims. He sounded like a conspiracy nut. This despite the fact that everyone knew this, or something like this, could be happening.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="133">
<answer instance="133" senseid="7"/>
<context>
When Kushner took over the Register in summer 2012, it had, by most tallies, about 198 newsroom staffers. At its peak, it has had either 380 or 400 in total; the company has issued different numbers on that at different times. The Register says it will have 370 newsroom people, after the layoffs. Seventy-five of them will be dedicated to the L.A. Register; about 20 are dedicated to the new Long Beach paper. That would leave 275 to cover <head>orange</head> County, 45 of whom are &#8220;trainees.&#8221; These are full-time staff, making about $10 an hour plus housing stipends &#8212; young journalists essentially being given one-year make-or-break jobs. Though many make significant contributions, let&#8217;s take them out of the count for a moment, which would leave 230 full-time professional journalists in O.C. That&#8217;s still 32 more than what the Register had 18 months ago. But the number puts the major expansion in perspective.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="134">
<answer instance="134" senseid="7"/>
<context>
It already sold off one local building for $2.7 million and now plans to move the rest of its real estate in the first quarter. The estimated return: $81 million for three parcels, one of which would become an apartment complex. Freedom&#8217;s waiting until now to sell those properties helped it meet collateral obligations and wait out an improving commercial real estate market. Sources put the market improvement at 10 to 15 percent in a year&#8217;s time in rebounding <head>orange</head> County. It has also sold two of the other newspaper group properties it got in Freedom&#8217;s out-of-bankruptcy fire sale for $34 million in cash. Its final disposition move is selling the last Freedom papers, in farther-flung San Bernadino County. Look for GateHouse to buy at a price of about $10 million.

</context>
</instance>
<instance id="135">
<answer instance="135" senseid="7"/>
<context>
It&#8217;s far too late for that now. This isn&#8217;t a case of a few bad actors. This is systematic corruption involving dozens of police officers and prosecutors that went on for well over two decades. At a minimum, there should be mass firings of cops and disbarments of prosecutors, past and present. A system that still retained some integrity would also have the worst offenders in handcuffs. But don&#8217;t believe for a second that this is a uniquely <head>orange</head> County problem. I pointed out in a post in May a couple stories I&#8217;ve personally reported in which prosecutors willingly put on informant testimony that they should have known wasn&#8217;t true. The problem is that there&#8217;s so little accountability for prosecutors. It&#8217;s just far too easy to skirt ethical rules, even to break the law, in procuring damning testimony from an informant. (And let&#8217;s be honest here, these are people whom those same prosecutors wouldn&#8217;t trust for a moment in just about any other context.) Prosecutors have very little to fear for going too far. Professional sanctions are rare. Save for a very few high-profile cases, criminal charges are unheard of. And they&#8217;re shielded from civil liability by absolute immunity.

</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
