<corpus lang="english">
<lexelt item="LEXELT">
<instance id="0">
<answer instance="0" senseid="fruit_tree"/>
<context>
are a vegetarian it is certainly worthwhile making sure you include other good sources of iron in your diet. You'll need to get your daily iron from eggs (if you're eating them), beans such as baked beans, soya beans and lentils, leafy green veg, dried fruit, and fortified breakfast cereals (check the labels to see which have iron added). Iron from non meat sources is better absorbed by the body if it is eaten with a source of vitamin C, so try to have your cereal with a glass of fresh <head>orange</head> or your lentils with a tomato based sauce and so on. CAN you tell me which type of milk is suitable for my four-year-old daughter? A LITTLE ray of sunshine she isn't. Cute and sweet are not adjectives that readily spring to mind on surveying the stage wardrobe of Andi, the blonde frontwoman of local cover band Sunshine. But then Andi isn't really your average rock babe. Two years ago she traded her long, barbie doll locks for a
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="1">
<answer instance="1" senseid="fruit_tree"/>
<context>
one of the biggest exhibitions at the fair with 21 towns and holiday attractions taking part. It is not all work for children at Mount Pleasant primary school in Darlington, where children take a caring approach. Distressed by mindless vandalism that destroys trees and flowers they are keeping a watchful eye on plant life. The animal kingdom gets its fair share of attention as children learn how to care for pets. A runaway hamster called Sophie takes pride of place where the school rat once roamed. And they learn to care for themselves with a sociable cafe selling <head>orange</head> and biscuits before home-time every Friday. Lynne Humes has taken time off work as a staff nurse at Darlington Memorial Hospital to start a family, and her son Anthony was born in January. The NHS is one of the main election issues for Lynne, who says she has seen many changes in the service over the last ten years.' Some were for the better but a lot were for worse. Lack of funds has been a big problem, especially for research, but it always has
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="2">
<answer instance="2" senseid="fruit_tree"/>
<context>
recalls a vanished age of acting with her effortless sense of style and superb ability to turn a line to perfection, while Jean Marsh brings a moving sense of both hurt and hope to the role of Miss Madrigal. There's a superb comic performance from Robert Austin as the hilariously touchy yet deeply sympathetic manservant Maitland, and outstanding work, too, from the 15-year-old Kellie Bright as Laurel, an alarmingly forward yet painfully vulnerable child who announces that her mother' is so overloaded with sex that it sparkles'. Following the <head>orange</head> Tree's fine revival of Rodney Ackland's The Dark River, this production offers further persuasive evidence that there was far more vitality in the English theatre before the arrival of the angry young men and the Royal Court revolution than is generally acknowledged. 
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="3">
<answer instance="3" senseid="fruit_tree"/>
<context>
and Cajun and Creole from New Orleans are some of the native cuisines worth sampling, while lobster can be gorged in New England for a fraction of the U.K. price. The day starts with the great American breakfast, which, if you haven't managed to get as part of your hotel deal, should be eaten in a local coffee shop or diner and will set you back $3-$4 for eggs, bacon, toast and unlimited coffee. Add two dollars for freshly squeezed <head>orange</head> juice. This is quite enough until lunchtime when you might hunt down some dim sum, steamed pork buns and the like for $1-$2 a basket in the local Chinatown, or hit the deli for another American institution, the sandwich. By' sandwich' we're not talking undernourished British Rail. A good Americansandwich will be a Dagwood Bumstead special -- at least six inches long, four multi-layered inches high and need two hands to control it. As for an evening meal, the golden rule is that
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="4">
<answer instance="4" senseid="fruit_tree"/>
<context>
John Steinbeck's saga of the Depression years was a political hot potato when Hollywood mogul Darryl F Zanuck sought to film it in 1940. He skirted the problem by turning it, via Nunnally Johnson's script, from a radical rallying cry into a depiction of the common man's ability to survive injustice by endurance. Aspects of the novel were changed. The screenplay drops Steinbeck's somewhat pretentious literary device of interspersing the story of the Joad family (poor farmers trekking from the Oklahoma dust bowl to the false promise of the California <head>orange</head> groves) with abstract chapters pontificating on the state of the world. Also abandoned was the grandiose ending, in which Rose of Sharon, whose baby has died, breast feeds a starving stranger. The film covers only the first two-thirds of the book but is dramatically more satisfying because it is the story of Tom Joad's political awakening. From a hot-head who has done time for killing a man, he develops into a union organiser who discovers the eloquence his new role demands. There is a Biblical
</context>
</instance>
<instance id="5">
<answer instance="5" senseid="fruit_tree"/>
<context>
in the Calypso bar at Chania carries a smiling blond baby on one hip, and my Cretan breakfast in one hand. For about 2 there are tomatoes, olives, bread, cheese, a sausage, a boiled egg, a nectarine, and a bowl of yoghurt, honey and sultanas, <head>orange</head> juice and mountain herb tea. All is fresh, local and utterly delicious. The tea is made of malotira and, I'm sure, peppermint. This herb has tiny leaves here, and is furiously strong: I made tea from some herbs I picked, put in a generous sprig of peppermint, and spat out the result in shock. At the north-western tip of the island I picked malotira, on the long empty golden beach of Phalasarna, thinking from its exotic perfume that I was gathering
</context>
</instance>
</lexelt>
</corpus>
